Mayank: Hey everyone, a very good morning. I hope all of you are doing great.
Mayank: Cool, cool, cool. I hope I'm audible as well. Let me just quickly share my… Come on, Elizabeth Yeah.
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Transcript file of last class is not there, let me ask and check it once. Sorry, I was traveling this week.
Mayank: So, that should be helpful.
Mayank: Oh, you all good, all good? Great. So, I think we should be good to begin. How are you now? Thanks a lot, I'm all good now. Yeah, Hintra is also redefined. So, just give me…
Mayank: Quickly just set a few things up.
Mayank: Hope all of you are doing great as well.
Mayank: Oh, good night, Silva, thanks a lot. I'm not able to see the old recordings. I think all the recordings are available.
Mayank: Anju, can you please check the same?
Mayank: Great. All is good, everyone. Let me quickly share the screen and set everything up.
Mayank: So, pretty awesome class for today.
Mayank: Awesome.
Mayank: No.
Mayank: Certainly.
Mayank: Just give me a minute, okay?
Mayank: Shettying a few things for all of us.
Mayank: Sweet.
Mayank: Okay, let me check. Yes, I'm clearing the agenda and everything, don't worry, okay?
Mayank: Asha, two people got the interview call, and I think they both were interviewed. Feedback which I got?
Mayank: Kind of both of them, just sharing that with the class. So, I will be forwarding more profiles on Monday, okay? So, many of you might be getting the call next week. So, feedback was that they were good in concept, but they were not very good in coding. So, yeah, just to have a look. I will be talking with the person so as to understand.
Mayank: He has actually went through with an agency who is taking the interview, so yeah, that should be helpful. Chalo, let's begin, everyone, just give me a minute, once…
Mayank: Just… second…
Mayank: Just a second, everyone can just…
Mayank: Great, so now I think I'm almost better settled in, great.
Mayank: Just a minute, I'm just setting one thing up, so that it should be good to begin.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Shut up, it's… Have everything started, everyone.
Mayank: I hope all of you are able to see my screen.
Mayank: Each and every one of you are able to see my screen.
Mayank: You have your chart here, great. Cool.
Mayank: Let me quickly see the questions. How to improve coding skill when that available when we will start, I think, just now.
Mayank: So, at what point can we say that we can give interview based on Agent Smart? Maybe just after the first project, you should be able to understand those things up, okay? Let me quickly explain what we will be doing. So, today, everyone, we have to just cover the… if you will remember from this.
Mayank: I hope all of you have played a lot with this particular thing, everyone. So today, we plan to make sure that we can quickly understand around
Mayank: The shutdown, transport layer, and other overall concepts.
Mayank: I'm pretty hopeful that you have revised the same. In the last class, we did a project as well. How many of you remember that we did a project?
Mayank: How many of you remember that we did the project?
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So, for people who have forgotten, this was the project everyone.
Mayank: Again, did it with no coding part, but I think still lots of things would be clear with the same around the AI updates and stocks and everything, okay? So that means it should be very, very helpful.
Mayank: Now, let's quickly understand the agenda of today and tomorrow. So, today and tomorrow, we have to do two things up.
Mayank: First, we will be completing, most probably.
Mayank: the MCP part, most probably we will be completing. Langchain with MCP, maybe we will see tomorrow only, or the class after. But what is the agenda, everyone? MCP…
Mayank: I'm not on mute, right?
Mayank: Raman, I'm not on mute, can you please check out your end? Great.
Mayank: So, MCP lifecycle, we will be completing everyone, complete. Then we will learn to create MCP servers.
Mayank: Okay? Plus clients.
Mayank: plus overall MCP… practical, basically, okay? Now, again.
Mayank: Since I just told you, right? So…
Mayank: I think… okay, I think I have the name of the person as well, if I can take it up.
Mayank: So, there was… A person, person, person, person, Rush of, right?
Mayank: So if I go on the POC name…
Mayank: Yeah, Dhush, are you in the class, Desha, by any chance?
Mayank: our USHA shub.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Great. So actually, I just wanted that, if he was in the class, he could have shared his,
Mayank: like, experience firsthand, but it should not be a problem. So, yes, we need to make sure that we do the practical and coding part as well, everyone. Again, both of these are very, very, very, very, very important things. We are going to see each and everything set up.
Mayank: And then, towards the end, I just want to make sure that we are doing a project with MCP as well. Project with MCP as well.
Mayank: And in the practical part, everyone, more or less what all we have done, I will be showcasing you. And towards the end, before the projects, I will just quickly talk about MCP Legacy.
Mayank: Versus modern architecture, so that it should be helpful, okay? Great. So, I think that was the case. Can you share the link of the HTML file? I think I've already shared that, so it should be pretty helpful, everyone.
Mayank: Let me, meanwhile, just quickly get started. So, for people who have forgotten what we are doing, where we are, we are covering MCP in complete depth, so that you can actually sit in an interview with confidence and answer the questions.
Mayank: And, yes, that's the whole idea, everyone. In the same role, we have been seeing the MCP lifecycle and the MCP architecture.
Mayank: We last stopped at the overall
Mayank: operation phase, everyone. I'm pretty sure that all of you would remember that. And then we have to make sure that
Mayank: We now start with the shutdown phase. So, with that, let's start with that, everyone, okay?
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Great, now let's begin. Do we learn fine-tuning in this course? No. Fine-tuning is not be taught, okay?
Mayank: Cool, let's move forward, everyone. I think that should be all the things.
Mayank: Sure.
Mayank: Evaluation, yes. Okay, not a problem.
Mayank: Coding interviewing as an end-to-end project coding, yes. Can we have a quick recap on last session on MCP?
Mayank: In the last session, everyone, we discussed around… so, quickly, I will just help you recap.
Mayank: We discussed… we first started with MCP, like, why MCP has to exist. I think I was not able to take the classes in between, so there was a good gap.
Mayank: one weekend you get for free to just enjoy. But anyways, we first understood about MCP in depth, like, why MCP is required and everything. Then we went on to understand about the MCP architecture properly, that what exactly are the different, different
Mayank: components in an MCP architecture, right? So we understood about The host, Client and server.
Mayank: In the same, I think I have shown you very much in depth, like, what role each and every one of them plays. Then we went on to…
Mayank: Separately, what is host, server, and what is your client.
Mayank: I have made sure to provide you completely in-depth notes and everything for the same, so I hope all of you are using the same. Please use that, okay?
Mayank: Then we went on to understand about the MCP architecture, MCP primitives, everyone, so as to understand that what are the different, different offerings and stuff.
Mayank: And yes, along with that, I discussed that what each and every one of… or what is the role they play, what are the functions which they are having, and we saw the same as well.
Mayank: If you remember, tools list, tools call, resource list, get, and template. So, of course, that was also there.
Mayank: Then we…
Mayank: understood about the lifecycle and the architecture. So, in that, we divided the same into three phases. Initialized, operation, and shutdown.
Mayank: And yes, that is what we are right now, we are.
Mayank: And we understood about the initialization phase, where there is a handshake happening, then we understood about the different, different parts in that.
Mayank: Version negotiation and capability negotiation.
Mayank: Then we discussed about how this operation phase works, where we have the tool slash list and tool slash call.
Mayank: And now we are starting with the overall shutdown phase, okay?
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: I think that should be more than… the interview.
Mayank: Will this course be enough to get a job in AI field? Yes, it should be enough, not a problem. Any other resource, like fine-tuning and Gen AI things? I think, that was mentioned as a prerequisite, so you can be able to read it, okay?
Mayank: Bugsleep, I'm not able to find the…
Mayank: 5th and 6th September classes, that is because I specifically mentioned in the class Radhao?
Mayank: Each and every of the things will be present in complete MCP in the new page. So, yes, this is where all the things are present.
Mayank: after the class, where MCP starts, all the things, each and every of the things is present in here, okay?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: So, everything is updated. I will parallelie make sure that I make the same right as well. So, let's start, everyone.
Mayank: Each and everything is provided, everything is there on the GitHub, so that should be more than enough. Let's now start.
Mayank: So, now everyone, let's move forward and try to understand about the Shutdown phase.
Mayank: That is where we actually will be understanding that how are MCPs, right? So, how exactly is when to
Mayank: Or let's say when a client and a server are connected in MCP, how do they make sure that they are gracefully shutting down?
Mayank: But before we jump onto understanding about the shutdown, there is one very, very important thing which we need to understand. So, for the same everyone, it will actually depend on how they are connected. So, quickly, I will just write it down.
Mayank: Don't V.
Mayank: A client and a server.
Mayank: is… going to… shirt.
Mayank: down.
Mayank: their connection, Depends on how exactly Are they?
Mayank: Connected… In the first… case.
Mayank: Now, to understand it, in law we have actually understood what MCP is, what is the language in which they communicate, what are the rules of that language, so JSON RPC 2.0, we have understood.
Mayank: We have also seen that what are the different, different steps, etc, how they do start with their initialization and overall the operation, etc. phase.
Mayank: But till we have not understood that how are they connected in the first place. So, we have seen that, yes, they are able to communicate, sorry, how they are able to talk, okay? But how they are connected, how this connection comes into picture.
Mayank: That is something which we have to now understand, and I guess that…
Mayank: How they stops, that is going to be more, like, very much helpful in the same. So, if you will see everyone, shutdown, transport closing is the goodbye.
Mayank: Now, your MCP, okay, the client and the architecture, they can be connected
Mayank: in two ways. So, they can be everyone connected in two ways. As we are able to see right in front of us, the first one being STDIO,
Mayank: The second one being streamable HTTP.
Mayank: Now, this is something which is known as transport layer.
Mayank: How exactly the client?
Mayank: and the server. So, how exactly this client, everyone?
Mayank: and this server.
Mayank: are going to transport information between each other, so this thing is very, very important to understand, because…
Mayank: Though we know how they will be talking, the language and etc. of talking, how they are connected, that is something defined by the transport layer.
Mayank: And as we are seeing right in front of us, there are two types of transport layer, everyone. First is your STDIO,
Mayank: Second is your… Overall, Streamable HTTP. Streamable… HTTP.
Mayank: So, everything up till now, the handshake, the discovery, every tool call has been the conversation itself.
Mayank: What gets said?
Mayank: this particular case kind of is discussing that, okay, what is the road? What is kind of connecting that? So, with that, first, before we jump onto
Mayank: shut down, let's quickly try to understand the same as well. So, quickly, I will just write down the first one here, everyone, which is your STD app.
Mayank: Now, the full form of STDIO is Standard.
Mayank: Input.
Mayank: And… output. So, STDIO.
Mayank: How many of you have heard about STDIO, ever?
Mayank: How many of you have ever heard about STDIU?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: this.
Mayank: In C language, yeah. If you have ever coded in C language, you must have done that, right?
Mayank: Great. Cool.
Mayank: So, many of us would have heard about this STDIO, and the initial thing which, the way I remember, is whenever we used to code in C++, or majorly any language, actually.
Mayank: We used to write something like this, include…
Mayank: stdio.h, okay? So, let's try to understand STDIO, the standard input and output, in a very quick manner, okay?
Mayank: In that, everyone, if you will notice, first, let's try to understand how this particularly works. So, this actually is a three-step process. So, this complete thing, everyone, is a three-step process.
Mayank: Let's try to see the same. If I go on transport layer, in this, which we have shared.
Mayank: The same will be very much clear. Client launches the server as a sub-process, so, again.
Mayank: Still, we have to connect client and server, everyone, right? So, still… still, we have to connect client and the…
Mayank: Son of what?
Mayank: Let's try to understand, and we will quickly see the quick practical, because this is actually something which we have been doing since ages. So, if you will notice, everyone, first thing which happened is that this server is started as a
Mayank: Overall, sub-process.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: this particular server, everyone, client or host, they start the same as a sub-process, not as a separate program running elsewhere, a direct child of this particular client. So, again, there is a parent-child relationship, where the server is started as a sub-process.
Mayank: Then, because now they are connected, because they are having a parent-child relationship, or because it is a sub-process.
Mayank: They can share.
Mayank: They can easily share their input and output.
Mayank: So, whatever input the client is getting.
Mayank: it can share it with the server via std in.
Mayank: And whatever the server is giving out, it can be read by the client via STD out. So, quickly, let's see the same, everyone. Client launches the server as a subprocess.
Mayank: Server reads std in.
Mayank: write std out, new line emitted, so everything is in a new line. std error is free for logging, so we can log and do everything as well.
Mayank: No separate authorization layer credentials from the environment, so if we try to focus here, everyone.
Mayank: We have the client.
Mayank: Inside the client, a subprocess gets started, which is your server, and they both are connected to each other. Now, to explain you and show you the very, very easy example, let's try to quickly open the terminal.
Mayank: So, what I will do, everyone, is that I will quickly open one terminal.
Mayank: And in… via that, I will show you, like, how this thing's done in the coding part.
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear, everyone, first.
Mayank: how STDIO kind of works?
Mayank: Because, again, that can be used multiple places, so I don't want to…
Mayank: have that case where you are not able to explain that, okay?
Mayank: One minute, I'm just getting the…
Mayank: Yes, it's one minute, everyone. I'm just getting the terminal, actually. So, something's running on my terminal.
Mayank: Great. Are you able to see my terminal, everyone?
Mayank: Able to see the terminal?
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Let me see quickly what is the doubt. I'm not on mute, everyone. Please check your mic, speaker and everything, okay?
Mayank: Do we use WebSockets to connect? No, we don't use WebSockets or anything, okay? I think now it is zoomed in.
Mayank: Pretty nicely zoomed in, everyone. Great.
Mayank: So, here I have opened a terminal, everyone, and quickly what we will do is, we will try to understand that how this kind of
Mayank: gets done, okay, how this STDIO process is used in every of the programming language, and then, of course, we will learn about what are the advantages and everything as well. So, let's first try to create a Python file.
Mayank: I will just simply try to create a Python file.
Mayank: In this Python file, I will just write the code print, Hello, Mayank.
Mayank: Franck.
Mayank: Python.
Mayank: Fighting.
Mayank: And… what else I can do is…
Mayank: I could quickly just have name.
Mayank: Which is input.
Mayank: Please?
Mayank: Tell. Mehdo.
Mayank: Meme?
Mayank: And I could just… Print.
Mayank: the name as well. So here, what I have done, everyone, I have just created a very, very simple kind of a file in which all I am doing is just taking in an input.
Mayank: printing the name, and then printing hello Mayank from Python file. So, just share this particular file.
Mayank: And… in the same, Once this gets shared every one… sorry, once this gets saved.
Mayank: I can just run this file as well. So, python.
Mayank: It is asking, please tell me the name. I can just quickly say… S2DIO is being explained.
Mayank: And now, this STD I.O. is being explained is printed.
Mayank: And hello Mayank from Python file is printed.
Mayank: Now, again, this is where, actually, in the backend, all the steps has been properly executed, everyone. So now, let me show you that what exactly happened behind the scenes.
Mayank: We have already this terminal.
Mayank: Terminal, which is nothing but your client.
Mayank: This terminal client, everyone, starts this Python file as a sub-process. So, again, understand and
Mayank: Pay a lot of attention on all the steps.
Mayank: this… Python file, Get started as a sub-process.
Mayank: And is a server.
Mayank: Now, these two, everyone, are connected by STDIO. So, these two are connected by standard input and output.
Mayank: Once this first step gets done.
Mayank: Anything which the terminal is getting in as input, so if I wanted to send everyone
Mayank: This STD I.O. is being explained.
Mayank: as an input.
Mayank: I was able to send it to my file, so whatever I wrote here, this particular thing was being sent here, everyone, so pay attention on the blue
Mayank: Color, no.
Mayank: And whatever this particular Python file want to
Mayank: Out, or give out the complete output.
Mayank: it was able to give out, which I was able to showcase. So this, everyone.
Mayank: It gave out the output, stdio is being explained, that is the exact same thing, and hello, mine, from the Python file.
Mayank: which might… Terminal was able to showcase.
Mayank: So, again, I will repeat the step.
Mayank: In this small thing, we are able to actually see all the steps.
Mayank: The very first one, everyone, is this terminal.
Mayank: Terminal is nothing but your client. So, terminal, everyone, is nothing but your client.
Mayank: So, quickly, I will draw the steps and everything again. So, we have the terminal, which is nothing but your
Mayank: Client?
Mayank: Then, everyone… and you can take it as client or host, okay, in the MCP admin logic.
Mayank: Then, next, everyone, we have the Python file.
Mayank: Then we have the Python file.
Mayank: When we do execute this Python file via my terminal, actually, they get connected via the STDIO protocol.
Mayank: STDIO protocol.
Mayank: Weird.
Mayank: This Python file is started as a sub-process inside my terminal, so it is a sub-process, everyone.
Mayank: This Python file, it starts off as a server.
Mayank: My client and server, they can now exchange the information via this STDIO protocol. Whatever input I'm getting in my terminal, okay, whatever input I'm getting in my terminal, that can be shared with my Python file. I hope all of you were able to understand that how
Mayank: So if I run python, Python, STDIO is being explained.
Mayank: So I hope all of you are able to understand that how this particular input I'm giving in terminal, everyone, yes or no? This particular input?
Mayank: I'm giving him 10 minutes.
Mayank: Is it able to reach to my file?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: Then, once I do enter, So, for example, when I'm running the file, everyone, and I am giving this
Mayank: So I asked it for the name. STDIO is being explained.
Mayank: I am giving in my input via terminal. So, once I press enter, this input which I am entering.
Mayank: in terminal, so… per minute?
Mayank: This will be able to pass to my Python file here.
Mayank: So, let me press the enter button now.
Mayank: And once the same is done, everyone, whatever output my Python file is shi…
Mayank: throwing out whatever output my Python file is throwing out.
Mayank: That I am able to showcase in my terminal as well, because
Mayank: As they are connected, they are able to transport the data between them.
Mayank: So, whatever needs to be transported, everyone, they are easily able to do that. They, of course, understand each other, and that is exactly how, unknowingly, we have been doing all these steps throughout Vola life. But yes, this is exactly how STDIO kind of works.
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: That how these two are able to connect. So they are… whatever Python file is outputting. Am I able to showcase that in Terminal?
Mayank: Is the terminal able to read that?
Mayank: Whatever is being shown, or thrown in that, right?
Mayank: So, I hope that does make the same clear.
Mayank: We have been actually doing this STDIO since our complete life, right?
Mayank: So… They are able to connect, that means they're able to share the data as well.
Mayank: If they're able to connect everyone, if the connection is created, they will be able to share the data, right?
Mayank: How Python is server, it has to be done on the server now. No, no, no, kapil it's a sub-process, started as a server. So inside that terminal, only the file ran?
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So, are you able to see that they are able to send the data to each other? Send and read the data from each other?
Mayank: Is that part clear?
Mayank: Okay, they are able to send the data, and they are able to read the data from each other.
Mayank: So now, does it matter if I make them communicate in whatever language.
Mayank: If you and your friend is connected, everyone, right? If you and your friend is connected.
Mayank: It doesn't matter which language you are talking, right?
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, again, it's a little tricky, but you have been doing this for your whole life without realizing.
Mayank: So, whenever we were writing any line of code, whenever we were implementing or executing anything, in the backend, this is what was happening. Clear? Let's move forward.
Mayank: If this thing is KRVEN,
Mayank: So, the compiler is part of?
Mayank: Sub process of terminal, yes, exactly. Okay?
Mayank: Great. So, yes. Acha, now I hope you were able to understand that why in your C++ file you used to write STDIO.
Mayank: So that your C++ terminal can showcase the output of your, code.
Mayank: And similarly, whatever you are giving in in your terminal, that can be read by your C++.
Mayank: file or C++ compiler or process. So they are connected via the STD IO, right?
Mayank: clear, I hope, in any interview now, if it does comes up, STDIO should not be a problem.
Mayank: Where is JSON RPC protocol here? Again, JSON RPC…
Mayank: Dictates how they will be communicating with each other.
Mayank: So, once they are connected, in which language they will be communicating.
Mayank: So JSON RPC is that language. Tomorrow, that can be HTTP, that can be FTP, that can be any language. But first is how they are connected.
Mayank: This part is transport, that how they are connected.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So again, the reason you were writing that stdio in the starting of your C++ file, for people who have coded in C++,
Mayank: That used to form a connection between the trans… between the terminal and your file. Okay? So this is forming the connection.
Mayank: After that connection is formed, that is where we can have any talk or any… any way we can just, chain the data.
Mayank: Okay, how can we decide when to use STDO transport layer? That will come in between, so it should not be a problem.
Mayank: Kia?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: In this example, sir, where is the host? So, terminal, Purna, you can think of Client and a host, okay?
Mayank: how can Python be a server? It has to be running on some server. Nani. It has started as a sub-process of my terminal only, okay?
Mayank: Are you able to see that both of them are able to exchange the data?
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: I hope you do also understand that Python terminal or Python must have been ran.
Mayank: Python terminal must have been ran every month when the terminal… when I wrote this command.
Mayank: So, that is exactly how they are connected, and via STDIO, they are able to, just communicate with each other, okay?
Mayank: Yes, sir, but at STDO related to shutdown signal, yes. The way shutdown, it depends on the…
Mayank: on how they are connected. Okay? All the programming languages work this way, yes. Mostly all the programming languages, when they are taking an input from the system on which they are running, they are using SDI.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Chauhan.
Mayank: Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: Let's move forward.
Mayank: Yes, every machine. So yes, again, everyone, just… you can have a read on this. I don't want to go in depth, because I know that now, since this is a very basic concept.
Mayank: This kind of question will come. Please explain, we have same… some machine for terminal and Python. They both are on the same machine. You mean they communicate through SDDI on the same machine? Yes, exactly.
Mayank: How else will they communicate?
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So again, just go back, read about the same. What I'm telling you is the way they connect. I'm not going in deep into STDIO, but this is how the whole system works.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Let's move forward.
Mayank: So, in production, which scenario we use? So, again, it will come. First, is STDIO? I have explained STDIO. Now you are asking when will we be using MCP? That is the next step. Is the STDIO clear, everyone?
Mayank: Is the SDDIO clear?
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: That is how things actually connect in local, like, whenever you are running these things up, that is how they are connecting.
Mayank: So, now, everyone, with this complete STDIO thing clear, and again.
Mayank: We can make sure to read more about the same, because it is something which has been kind of taken
Mayank: Like, very much for granted, because we have been doing and running this.
Mayank: But, this is exactly, everyone, how the STDIO sub-process… Sorry, STD I.O. transport layer works.
Mayank: Now, again, if you want, we can have a code like this as well, where we start this as a subprocess and see more things as well.
Mayank: But, again, I honestly feel that the way I have explained, that is much more easier to understand, and we can see that how terminal and the Python files are getting connected. Now, quickly, let's try to understand that what are the benefits of STDIO. So, if we think about the same.
Mayank: There are a few benefits of the same. The very first one, everyone, is how
Mayank: This connection will be very, very fast.
Mayank: Whenever… If you think about, if two things are connected via the STDIO protocol.
Mayank: The connection will be very, very fast, because they have to just…
Mayank: connect with each other on the same system. So, present.
Mayank: on the same system. So that's why the connection is pretty fast, everyone.
Mayank: Then, along with being fast, It will be very secure as well.
Mayank: Secure because?
Mayank: Again, both are Running.
Mayank: On same system.
Mayank: Both are running on the same system. That is why we can always make sure that this will be very, very secure. There are very less chances of any attack or any data leakage, because both of them don't have any fireball or anything in between.
Mayank: And if we kind of think about the same, I would make it third point.
Mayank: If we try to think about this, this is a very simple kind of a connection.
Mayank: Simple.
Mayank: connection
Mayank: So, again, this is how the STDIO connection, which is one type of transport layer, works. Now, if you go on the official documentation, everyone, and go to documentation.
Mayank: And in here, if I just show you the Save Quickly servers.
Mayank: So, this is all the thing.
Mayank: MCP, let me search for SBDIO.
Mayank: So, we'll see.
Mayank: Base protocol specification in STDIO transport, the client launches the MCP server as a sub-process. The two end communicate over sub-process tandem streams, okay? So, again, they have just made it a little bit…
Mayank: more technical. So that's why, everyone, this is the first way of making sure that
Mayank: Our client and server, they can, or how they will be connecting.
Mayank: Now, with that clear, let's move on to the next one, which is going to be your… streamable.
Mayank: HTTP.
Mayank: Fast compared to what? Any connection which you will make otherwise. Any connection, let's say via HTTP, the one which we are going to now move forward, or
Mayank: Anyways, how two things will be connected? Because they are on the same system, because they are connecting as a process, they will be very, very fast.
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: Okay? One question, can we call STD iOS local? Yes, that is local only.
Mayank: Is the server as in same where Client is running exactly?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, when working with local LLM, STDIO would be used if our tool don't want to connect to internet.
Mayank: Again.
Mayank: most probably local LLM and your terminal or any command that is connected via STTIO.
Mayank: Okay? So they are communicating things via STDIO.
Mayank: Ul?
Mayank: No authorization is required as an advantage. Ideally, yes, Muralhab authorization we can add, but still, they are pretty secure. Okay?
Mayank: Great. Any cons of STDIO? It cannot be used everywhere. That's the con, because, of course, everything cannot be running on your local, right?
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: So, these are all the advantages overall. Simple. No server address, no network setup, nothing to configure beyond the command itself. Private by construction, nothing is exposed to anything outside the room, so there is no network attack surface to defend. Fast, no network round trip at all, just a direct handoff between two programs on the same machine.
Mayank: And yes, we actually are using it everywhere, if we think about the same.
Mayank: At any two processes.
Mayank: Majorly, when they're communicating on your machine, they use the STDI protocol. Disadvantage, of course, it cannot be used everywhere, because
Mayank: your… both the things should be running on your local. So, with that thing clear, everyone, now let's move on to the streamable HTTP.
Mayank: Now, streamable HTTP, and before everyone, it was something known as HTTP plus SSE, which is your server-side events.
Mayank: Now that has been kind of depreciated, so it is known as streamable HTTP now, so let's see the same as well.
Mayank: Quickly.
Mayank: If we see streamable HTTP, as the name suggests, it is actually based on the HTTP protocol.
Mayank: So, HTTP protocol of Exchanging the… data.
Mayank: Now, where this is helpful, everyone, if we think about, the same, HTTP protocol is the most
Mayank: Use protocol over the web.
Mayank: via HTTP, my client, so the client which I'm having, everyone.
Mayank: We have to make sure to… Connect.
Mayank: this client.
Mayank: with the server, right? So that is why we are understanding it.
Mayank: Via HTTP, my client can actually connect on any server over the internet, so we already are knowing about the result, rules and everything of HTTP, right, everyone? So how… I think all of you must have heard about HTTP, right?
Mayank: For Sean, sorry.
Mayank: Oh, yeah, for sure.
Mayank: Http, HTTPS, both, like, that should not be a problem.
Mayank: So, via HTTP, we are able to connect with everything? Yes or no, everyone?
Mayank: Why HTTP? Are we able to correct with each and everything?
Mayank: Make sense?
Mayank: So, that means that, actually, by using the same.
Mayank: We will be able to have, okay, we will be able to connect to any server.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: So, since we are known about HTTP, HTTP
Mayank: Allows my server, or sorry, my host, to reach out to server.
Mayank: running anywhere on the internet. So that's the whole idea, that now, because we are aware about the HTTP protocol, it will be able to run anywhere.
Mayank: And now, everyone, if you think about the same, how this works, this…
Mayank: host or client, so I'm going to take it as… in here, I'm going to take it as host.
Mayank: slash client.
Mayank: It sends a… Post call.
Mayank: It actually sends a… Post call, everyone.
Mayank: to my server.
Mayank: So… Again, post call is sent.
Mayank: And in this post call only, we can send our JSON RPC as well. So, along with all the headers and everything, we can send the JSON RPC as well. And authentication can follow the standard HTTP authorization process, via
Mayank: API via key or anything. So, in HTTP, everyone, we have multiple ways of actually
Mayank: Making sure that we are able to authorize the same. So, in that case, it is the VOL case. So, quickly, if we see one endpoint, commonly slash MCP,
Mayank: And I can showcase this to you all as well.
Mayank: Unknowingly, when we were connecting to the LAN chain.
Mayank: If I copy this MCP server, right?
Mayank: See?
Mayank: In the end, it is having slash MCP. So… Again?
Mayank: There is slash MCP in the end of this particular Langchain MCP server. How many of you are able to see the slash MCP in the end?
Mayank: slash MCP.
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: And again, I will show you the same, like, for both of them, I will show you. Pay attention.
Mayank: So… As we can see in the Langchain server as well, everyone, there is slash MCP in the end.
Mayank: One endpoint commonly slash MCP, which can do the post plus get, or which can easily just have the post plus get, connection. Plain JSON or upgrades to SAC for long calls. So, again.
Mayank: SSE… Server-side events on streamable, what does that mean, everyone, is that?
Mayank: Again, I will not go a lot deep into this free mobile and SSE everything.
Mayank: The whole idea becomes that how?
Mayank: Exactly.
Mayank: If there are long calls, right, if there is a call which is going to take a lot of time, then they can, be connected, so streamable or server-side events can also be sent.
Mayank: Mcp session ID can be sent in header, okay? It replaces the older depreciated HTTP plus SSE transport, so I think, again, just to summarize, everyone, what exactly happened is that.
Mayank: We are able to make sure that using the standard HTTP protocol, we can connect to our servers, so our client or host can connect to the server.
Mayank: They can send the post call, and in that, they can send the information and everything as required. And then, in a normal way, we are able to work. So that is how exactly the two protocols are defined. Quickly, I will just help us to revise it.
Mayank: The first one, and why we are learning it, because the shutdown depends when we are closing the connection between
Mayank: Oh.
Mayank: Client and the server in MCP. It depends on how they are connected.
Mayank: So, just to give you a very good analogy, everyone, if I'm closing the connection between you and your friend whom you are talking, it will depend on how you two are connected. For example.
Mayank: If you are connected via chatting, if you are chatting on WhatsApp, then I might have to close the internet. That makes sense, everyone?
Mayank: That if you are chatting.
Mayank: to your friend on WhatsApp, or on Facebook, or anywhere. You are connected via internet, I will have to close the internet.
Mayank: But if you are talking on phone.
Mayank: Do you think that closing internet will help?
Mayank: If you're talking on phone, everyone?
Mayank: No, right? And vice versa as well.
Mayank: And vice versa as well. If you are talking on
Mayank: internet, and I close your network, okay? If you are connected via the Wi-Fi, and I close the network, then of course, your chat will still continue.
Mayank: So, again, now we have seen that how they two get connected as well.
Mayank: And in that, HTT IONT, remember, HTTP are the two ways which we normally have to understand.
Mayank: STDIO, we kind of understood and saw the same. Next, everyone is streamable HTTP. That is also how we can understand
Mayank: how they're working. So now, let's try to understand the… and see the same practically, because I do understand that all of you would be, at this point, like Mayank, okay, you are saying that, okay, this is how they are connected, and this is how we can close the connection and everything. So let me first showcase to you that how this kind of works, because
Mayank: Closing the connection, once we understand the transport layer is very, very easy. So in the next part, let's try to see the practically
Mayank: Two servers, one of them will be local, one of them will be… or STDIO server, and one will be HTTP-based server, and how, basically, all these connections and everything happens.
Mayank: What is post-call? Mehwari, please revise, okay? Just go to Mayank GPT or any chat GPT or anything. Just ask, ask this what is a POST call, okay?
Mayank: Cool, before I move forward, anyone has any doubt?
Mayank: Before I move forward, anyone has any doubt quickly?
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Suppose MCP server is connected with 10 clients, so 10 different session ID will be created, and how server will detect the connection? So, the server will be able to handle that, right? You are getting my messages? Yes, Krishnakumar, I'm getting your messages, but can you still ask it again? Can you show an example for STDIO? Ha, mother, we are jumping on the same, no?
Mayank: I have shown you the example via terminal, but now I'm showing you the MCP example as well. Okay?
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: Acha, first, Acha, let me make it a little bit easier to understand. Everyone just, with that example again, which I gave you, of friend and the you.
Mayank: Abhit, what we have done, everyone, is that…
Mayank: We understood the language and the rules.
Mayank: in which you and your friend will be communicating, which is Hindi, English, what are the language and everything. I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Till now, we know that how they will be connecting in JSON RPC, what fields they are setting and everything, right?
Mayank: We know the language and everything.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: But… but…
Mayank: We were still not clear that how they are connected to each other, by how they are actually connected.
Mayank: So, I kind of give you two ways. First is, let's say,
Mayank: Example, I'm just taking an example, via internet, which is Wi-Fi.
Mayank: Second is via network.
Mayank: Images Squad.
Mayank: Now, once you are connected in either of the way, everyone, we know that, okay, you will be
Mayank: exchanging the data, like, you will be talking in Hindi or English, so we know the language and everything, okay?
Mayank: But now, it will depend on how you are connected to understand how you will be shut down as well. Thinka? So that is why we are going under and understand about this transport layer. Thinka? So I hope this thing is now very much clear. To close your connection, I should understand how you are connected.
Mayank: And to connect a host
Mayank: Oh, sorry, to connect a client and a server in MCP, there are two ways. STDIO and Jon?
Mayank: streamable HTTP, which I've shown you. Teja?
Mayank: So, once you are connected, then, so you can easily change the information via this same thing, but yes. Overall, that is how we change the information and everything. Yeah?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: The JSON RPC is the language. JSON RPC is the language. It is not the transport thing.
Mayank: Tyga? JSON RPC is the language and the grammar and the rules around it. How they are connected, that is the transport layer, ki how that data… ki, by your… you are saying, ki, I want to send hi to my friend.
Mayank: So this high is GS1RPC.
Mayank: How this will be sent to your friend is the transport protocol, or transport layer.
Mayank: Clear, everyone?
Mayank: I hope the same is clear now.
Mayank: Let's move forward.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: JSON RPC is the language, or how you will be… what you want to send. So you are saying that, hey, I want to send this JSON RPC message, blah blah blah, whatever you want to send here.
Mayank: Okay? But how this will be sent depends on how you are connected.
Mayank: Clear, everyone? Shall we wait to move forward?
Mayank: How many of you have downloaded MCP Jam, which I asked you in the last class? MCP Jam application?
Mayank: MCP Jam application, which I told you in the last class. I hope all of you have done that. For people who don't know what it is, MCP Jam. It's, like, one of the best wins which I got for the SIM, okay?
Mayank: Any update on Udaymic course coupon? Let me tell you in the end, okay? Let me give you in the end.
Mayank: So, again, let's try to use this only, okay? It's website, you said to try it out, huh, Muralh, start testing, you can download it as well for macOS or Windows.
Mayank: Or run it directly via the npm command, enough?
Mayank: Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: With that?
Mayank: So, now, everyone, let's try to see the same practically, and for the same, what I will be doing is, I will be using this awesome application, which is JSON
Mayank: sorry, MCP Jam.
Mayank: Now, if you will go and search for MCP Jam, It is…
Mayank: testing or understanding how this connection actually works, okay, so how the connection is actually going to work. Each and everything we can see via… and inside this application. And the best part?
Mayank: Though all these things happen in the backend, in your Claude and all the other connection, which we will also be seeing in future, this just makes it a lot easier, right? So, now if we go back, everyone, what I have done in here is that
Mayank: I have multiple servers, as you can see.
Mayank: So?
Mayank: If you see on screen, everyone.
Mayank: I am having multiple servers. Extalydraw slash MCP server, which kind of tells that, okay, this is going to be your HTTP kind of a server.
Mayank: And this MV1 MCP server time, this is actually a local or STDIO kind of a server. Same for this LanChain server, this is your slash MCP, HTTPS or HTTP kind of a server.
Mayank: Similarly, file system, everyone, is my local kind of a server, which can help me to read file and everything.
Mayank: Just to show you, like.
Mayank: First, let's try to understand with your STD IO connection, everyone. So, let me just make this open.
Mayank: And I want that all of you focus on this right side. How does the logs and everything fills up here?
Mayank: So, let me make this thing open, and pay attention.
Mayank: This, actually, everyone, triggered multiple calls Between…
Mayank: my client or host, which you can take up, in this case, MCP Jam, and this MCP server.
Mayank: Pay a lot of attention.
Mayank: Request initialized, so they are actually connected to one another.
Mayank: via STDIO connection type. So, this server, everyone, it is running on my local. This server is running on my local.
Mayank: And it makes a lot of sense. Like, this file system server helped me to read the local files, okay? So, of course, it has to run on local for that matter, but still.
Mayank: If you will notice In this, what has happened, everyone, is that when I…
Mayank: made this file system MCP server active.
Mayank: they started the complete process, which we have learned, actually. So, they sent an initialized request.
Mayank: Now they are connected via the STDIO protocol.
Mayank: I can send the request.
Mayank: And whatever the file system protocol will be outputting, I can read the same as well. So, see? I'm able to now easily send my JSON RPC messages.
Mayank: And I am easily able to then get the output and the response as well.
Mayank: And all of that is actually happening.
Mayank: Via my… Simple local thing.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Easily via my simple local connection, the same is happening. And we can see the same in Claude as well. So just, if I ask my Claude, so this everyone is Claude, which I have downloaded Claude desktop application.
Mayank: In this, I have connected everyone, if I go on connectors.
Mayank: I have connected the file system server, See? File system server, okay?
Mayank: And if I ask it, Can you tell me what all files I have in my… complete MCP folder.
Mayank: Now, of course, Claude will have no idea what all files that Sepaha I'm having in my folder, but
Mayank: Since this file system MCP server is running locally.
Mayank: Claude will be able to connect to that via STDIO, like, the whole transport way in which they will be transforming information is STDIO, and the second I press enter.
Mayank: It will actually try to hit that
Mayank: file system MCP, and then get me the answer. So, let's see the same, everyone.
Mayank: See how it is locating a reference folder. Checking connected drives and projects for matching folder.
Mayank: I'm… hopefully it will try to call the MCP, else we will have to tell the same.
Mayank: So, what I can do is I can stop it. Okay, I think it asked for the same, let me say try again.
Mayank: Now, since Claude knows what all MCPs are connected, it will be able to understand it, so let's try to understand everyone.
Mayank: Locating files related to a specific project folder.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, pay a lot of attention in a bit. And again, that is why I'm showing you each and everything right in front of you, practically, so that you are actually able to understand that what happens in the backend, right? See? Claude want to list allowed directories from file system.
Mayank: So, Claude is actually asking that, hey, Mayank, I want to list all the directories and everything from this file system. I can allow the same ones.
Mayank: And we know, actually, that once you do the same.
Mayank: we get the allowed directories, so I've given the access to my complete MCP code.
Mayank: Then, it can see the list directly from file system, I can allow it once again.
Mayank: And this is how, again, it is able to get the response and everything.
Mayank: So, see?
Mayank: This server is running, everyone, and I'm able to get the response.
Mayank: Easily via just… Having my PHYSTM MCP server.
Mayank: Exactly same thing I can show you here as well.
Mayank: Now, just to quickly notice, server name file system connected via STDIO.
Mayank: This is the complete overview, like, which protocol they are using, what is the capabilities and everything.
Mayank: What are the different, different tools as well? So, of course, my server will be having different, different tools, everyone. So, it is having the read file, read text file.
Mayank: Read media file.
Mayank: history and everything, when it was changed and all these things, and what all Client support. So, just, again, MCP server is, kind of showcased here. If I go on playground, everyone, and I could just easily, right.
Mayank: So… I could just easily… See?
Mayank: List allowed directories, so pay attention a lot here as well.
Mayank: Let me delete all the logs for the time being.
Mayank: I can run this, and there will be a tool called.
Mayank: tool slash call, list allow directories. I sent this particular request, everyone.
Mayank: And see? I received the… Response as well.
Mayank: Huh?
Mayank: In the same.
Mayank: I will be getting the allowed directory. So, as of now, via the MCP server, it is showing the same as empty.
Mayank: But I could get… in a similar manner, I could just…
Mayank: have list directory, I could just enter a path here. So, for example.
Mayank: If my path is this one.
Mayank: Since this server is ending locally, right?
Mayank: I could just enter it, run it.
Mayank: And see? It gave me all the files which are inside it.
Mayank: So… I will just run it again.
Mayank: And? See?
Mayank: So it is doing tool slash call.
Mayank: Argument, it is sending this path.
Mayank: And… In the same.
Mayank: I can now get.
Mayank: all my… answer. So, what all is present, right? Properly, I'm able to get the
Mayank: content, so my MCP, which is running locally, via SDDIO, I am able to connect to that, and then I'm able to showcase that what all is exactly
Mayank: what information or whatever I want.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: Believe me, this is very much in-depth. I have tried to explain.
Mayank: I hope the same is clear.
Mayank: How to set a file system MCP in MCP Jam? I showed that in the last class as well, but what you can do, everyone, is that.
Mayank: Just go on this form and ask it.
Mayank: Add file system MCP.
Mayank: Okay? Just, generally, it's that easy. Add file system MCP, nothing else.
Mayank: Mia?
Mayank: Any doubt, anyone?
Mayank: Any doubt?
Mayank: Did you create in the file system MCP? No, I have not created it. It is already present.
Mayank: File system MCP is already present.
Mayank: Pika?
Mayank: To shut down the connection, we will come in a bit, but I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: Let's move forward to see the HTTP one as well. Streamable HTTP.
Mayank: Please show how to download the MCP. I've done that already, everyone. Everyone in the last class, I asked you to download and showed the same as well, right? MCP Jam application.
Mayank: Is it secure giving the access to Cloud AI tools like our personal folders? It depends. If you are having any personal information, don't do that, okay?
Mayank: Everyone, if you will go on MCP Jam website, I'm not sure that why you are not listen. Why don't you listen?
Mayank: If you go on this website, If you download the same.
Mayank: Then, it is on macOS or Windows, or simple NPX.
Mayank: And you can run the same.
Mayank: There is generally no complex setup or anything.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: Let's move forward.
Mayank: Let us move forward.
Mayank: Can I get a smiley face if this is clear?
Mayank: Can you show running a fast MCP server in VS Code and integrate? Sathish, yeah, that is the second part of today's class, don't worry. Explain with some use cases. This is generally a use case, Vivek.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: This is generally a use case.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Again, I'm explaining you these things because creating an MCP server, which we will be doing today, which we will be actually doing today, that would be very easy with the things. This is the level of depth which you should know about. Now, can you tell me what are the two transport protocols, how they work and everything?
Mayank: MCP Jat is not built for macOS Intel. It's an Uncle. Run via this thing, then.
Mayank: NPX command, you got?
Mayank: It can be done on the local as well, you can see all the different, different ways. It supports everything, to be honest.
Mayank: Streaming STDI are not yet clear, because there is nothing like streaming STDI.
Mayank: I don't think, like, you are… there is TML HTTP, but there is nothing like… Steamable STDIO.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Let's move forward.
Mayank: Hi, Meng Gaurav from Curiosity, I'm asking when we'll be going to do a major project. After this, we will be… MCP, once it gets clear, then I will be teaching you about MCP in Langchain, then multi-agent system in Langchain, and then we will be doing our project.
Mayank: Abhi, you are asking, Mayank when the project will start. Once I will do the project, then you will be like, Mayank, why is it getting so complex? So, understand things properly, okay?
Mayank: Where till when the Phase 1… where will Phase 1 end till October end?
Mayank: Puerto, huh?
Mayank: Celo.
Mayank: This is where we can connect to different servers. Everyone, I remember doing this in the last class.
Mayank: I specifically remember opening the same, adding the servers in the last class, showcasing you the MCP server time.
Mayank: Again, this device.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: It is not heavier, I've just discussed about two things, nothing else.
Mayank: So, let's move forward, everyone. Again, I think, yes, someone is saying the right thing.
Mayank: Ki…
Mayank: Thanks for the in-depth explanation, but for Bonda last time Anhira, we are doing STD streamable, which we could understand. Arunjit, I totally also agree, but if you will notice, I've just taught for 15-20 minutes. I'm just trying to clear the doubts. Not sure why people have not downloaded this, and everyone, again, I discussed this in the last class.
Mayank: I'm not sure that why you have not downloaded it the same, because generally, Ranjith is right. These things should not take us more than 30 to 35 minutes. You should revise, because else you will say that, Mayank, I want to make sure that I get the highest job, but you are not revising these things up.
Mayank: And I have actually told you, given no one is going to hire you for saying, here, Eva, you can define an MCP server, please come and work for us.
Mayank: As said though I don't guess anyone is going to hire you.
Mayank: These are all the things which will be needed.
Mayank: Hanna touch, I'm moving forward, everyone, extremely sorry, but you will have to revise. And again, for people who are thinking here, why is May I going in-depth? MCP server bus bhata do, how to telescreate an MCP server?
Mayank: If you think that this thing will get you hired.
Mayank: Genuinely, I will forward your CVs. Tyga. Let… tell me, like, why you are getting, not getting in the interview. Tyga? Chalo. Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: Now, let's try to understand about the streamable HTTP in a very similar sense. So, now what I will do, I will just quickly close this connection, everyone.
Mayank: And I think before I move on to stream-able HTTP, this is very, very much simpler how we can…
Mayank: Understand around the… closing part as well here, although I remember I showed you the same in the…
Mayank: VS Code as well, last time, that how exactly it happens in the VS Code. So, again, let's now try to first
Mayank: Go on to shutdown and understand how it happens in the
Mayank: STDIO case. So, let us try to understand this, everyone.
Mayank: Now, we have… actually, this whole discussion started with the shutdown only, and that is how we understood that how there is your HTTIO, and there is streamable HTTP, okay?
Mayank: Let's first try to see that in STDIO protocol, when two
Mayank: sorry, when an MCP is connected via STD I.O. to your
Mayank: server, okay? The client or host is connected to STDIO via your server. How does the shutdown happen? The very first thing.
Mayank: No JSON RPC messages exchanged during shutdown at all. The entire responsibility shifts to the transport layer. So, this actually is the reason, everyone, this complete line is the reason that why we have to first understand the transport layer. The way you are connected
Mayank: is going to depend on how we will be closing the connection. So, in SQDIO, everyone, Majorly, okay, majorly.
Mayank: The… wall… Overall duty of closing the connection lies on the client side.
Mayank: So, I will repeat this statement.
Mayank: In STDIO,
Mayank: when we have to close the connection. So, if this client and MCP are connected, if we have to close their connection.
Mayank: this… Depends on the client side.
Mayank: Most of the time, this duty. So let's see how it will happen, everyone.
Mayank: Transport, if this is STDIO.
Mayank: Client initiated, which is very, very common.
Mayank: close the STD
Mayank: In… so one is, of course, we can close that we are not sending any input, so that is where it can be closed, everyone.
Mayank: Or wait.
Mayank: Even if it doesn't happen, then we send signal termination command. So there is a command which we can send where we say that, hey.
Mayank: we are… Or we would want to
Mayank: terminate our signal. So, as an example, in here, if I want to, or when I'm closing this thing, everyone.
Mayank: My MCP jam will be sending a overall request to a file system that, hey.
Mayank: I want to close the system. Signal, terminate. Sictum.
Mayank: Even after that, if it doesn't happen, even after that, if it doesn't happen.
Mayank: Then it says kill, which is like the last resort, where we say that, hey, now I just want to kill the connection, I want to kill the signal between us, I don't care about anything.
Mayank: Please, just, let's get out, and don't have anything connected.
Mayank: Server-initiated, which is very rare. So, one is your Client Initiitiated, which is the most common in this kind of connection. Another is server-initiated. So, for example, your file system can also say that, hey, I don't want to connect with you.
Mayank: File system can also close the connection from its end.
Mayank: Server closes its output stream and exit. Server 5 system can say that, hey, I'm closing the output stream.
Mayank: I'm not going to exchange any data with you.
Mayank: I'm exiting. So this is how the shutdown happens between your
Mayank: between the client and the server when they are connected in STDIO.
Mayank: Majority of the time, or rather 99% of the time, it is initiated by the client.
Mayank: As an example, if I will close my
Mayank: Claude here, everyone, if I will close my Claude.
Mayank: it will actually terminate the connection. It will actually send a command, no JSON, RPC, nothing there, but it will terminate the complete connection, so that, my…
Mayank: Overall thing will know that, hey, now the connection is closed.
Mayank: So, that is the first, that is how it happens. But, if required, file system MCP server, it can also
Mayank: just close the connection attendance. So, that is how the shutdown happens in your overall STDIO protocol. Now, in the next part, everyone, let's try to understand and see the practical of streamable HTTP.
Mayank: And how the shutdown happened in that as well.
Mayank: So I hope this is clear, everyone.
Mayank: Yeah, so we are just disabling. See, they are just connected via the STDI of everyone. Either I am saying that I will close the input, so I will not be sending you anything, or I will say that s term command in Windows or in Mac, right? That, hey, I'm closing, I want to terminate the signal between us.
Mayank: Or last is sick, kill. That, hey, kill the signal, no matter what happens, that is the last resort.
Mayank: And the server, it can say that, hey, I'm closing my output stream.
Mayank: And just exiting.
Mayank: So I hope that makes sense, everyone.
Mayank: So, when token limit is reaches or hit, the cloud server will terminate. No, it will not depend on token limit.
Mayank: Sonu.
Mayank: Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: So, now, everyone, let's try to understand about the streamable HTTP, that is the other kind of a connection. So, again, I will just showcase the same via MCP Jam.
Mayank: Let me close this connection, so let me see… if I…
Mayank: close the connection, I think there is nothing, yeah. So it is not logging the same in.
Mayank: But I will be showcasing you that via Claude, so it should not be a problem.
Mayank: So, I've cleared all the logs, everyone. To add any, any MCP, you can just ask it here. Like, backend, it connects with your ChatGPT or Claude or anything, so you can just ask the same here.
Mayank: If you go on Connect, As an example, I'm just opening the Extcalid Raw MCP server.
Mayank: See now, pay attention.
Mayank: So, for the timing, just forget this first call. It is based on the modern MCP connection, which we will learn about as well, but as you can see, many connections are still on the previous one, so pay attention.
Mayank: This time, when I'm doing the initialization, everyone, I am actually making a post calling.
Mayank: So, this is what I mentioned, that I am actually making a HTTP post call.
Mayank: to initialize, and rather to communicate in any ways. So this, everyone, is the request to initialize my…
Mayank: complete connection. We can see the capabilities.
Mayank: what all its supports and everything, right? The version and all these things.
Mayank: Then, a post call gets made.
Mayank: In the post call, it is like any other post call, where we have the request headers, okay, response headers.
Mayank: And this JSON RPC can also be sent, and then I get the response in a very similar sense.
Mayank: So I'm just getting the request result.
Mayank: So it is saying that, hey, I have the protocol version.
Mayank: I have these capabilities, I have the tools.
Mayank: And I have the server info.
Mayank: Similarly, everyone, then we have the…
Mayank: notification call that, hey, now we are initialized, we are connected to each other. So this is exactly the whole process which we have learned in depth as well. Right now, you are just able to see the same in front of you.
Mayank: And then we can have post MCP for the tools list as well, if you will notice.
Mayank: Any request or anything which we learned about, that is being sent
Mayank: pour slash MCP to my server, which is there on the overall,
Mayank: on the HTTP. So, this post call, everyone.
Mayank: Just like a simple HTT server, it is being sent here. So, post slash MCP, the request got sent.
Mayank: for telling that, hey, we have initialized the complete thing. Next, when you want to understand what are the different, different tools which my Excalibur provides, so, again, if you will notice, connection type, HTTP,
Mayank: And if you make it HTTI over here, it will not work, because it's not a local one. No authentication, we can have any authentication, everyone. All the HTTP-based authentication, VR…
Mayank: auto, OAuth, all these are there.
Mayank: Overview, which tells us about the MCP. Tools, there is README, CreateView.
Mayank: Export to Excalibur, save checkpoint, read checkpoint, So this is…
Mayank: When I now want to make a to slash list call.
Mayank: Earlier, there was no HTTP. The connection was direct. Now, since this is all over the internet, I have to make a HTTP call.
Mayank: So, I am everyone now sending a call to get the tools list.
Mayank: And I'm getting the result.
Mayank: in which it is telling that, hey, I have 5 items. I think we just saw
Mayank: That how we are having these 5 items, right, everyone? And then again, of course, this is how this will move forward. For anything, now it is doing the resources slash read, it is trying to read the resource as well.
Mayank: And, again, a post-MCP call.
Mayank: And I'm getting that, hey, I have one resource. So, I hope all of you remember that MCP is more than just tools. It is resource and everything as well. So, right in front of you, I'm showcasing you that how
Mayank: for every call, you will notice that every step which we understood, everyone.
Mayank: It is initialized, it is followed by a… Overall, MCP call, post call.
Mayank: Notification, followed by a post call.
Mayank: Tools list, followed by a post call.
Mayank: Resources slash list, followed by a post call. And then we are getting the result. Again, two slash list, followed by a post call. And I think all of you would be able to understand, if I actually
Mayank: Go onto the playground.
Mayank: And… Just try to hit this, so let me get the logs every month.
Mayank: Delete everything?
Mayank: Then?
Mayank: See?
Mayank: I'm trying to call a tool.
Mayank: Followed by a post call. So, in the post call, because this is a simple HTTP connection now, I could just send the thing and get every result and everything.
Mayank: And, of course, because it is on HTTP, if the internet is not working, it will not work, because HTTP call is being sent.
Mayank: And properly, I'm sending all these information and everything, the headers and all these things.
Mayank: And yes, this is how the HTTP… streamable HTTP kind of works.
Mayank: And I guess this is much more in-depth than required, but…
Mayank: You should be aware that, yes, this is how they work, and if we now go back, everyone, let's try to understand it.
Mayank: In Steamable HTTP, it is very, very simple, if you think about the same.
Mayank: Again, if you have to just not connect to any particular, let's say.
Mayank: HTTP thing, just close the HTTP connection.
Mayank: It's that simple.
Mayank: If you want to disconnect or shut down the streamable HTTP,
Mayank: It is close the HTTP connection, so the client can just close the connection. I hope this makes a lot of sense, everyone.
Mayank: key, when you want to close any HTTP connection, you just close the client, right?
Mayank: For example, if you are connecting to a website via HTTPS, you can just close the website, or sorry, close your Google Chrome.
Mayank: And the connection will be halted.
Mayank: Ajay, when you open a website which is not safe or anything, you quickly close your browser, or you close your…
Mayank: Disconnect your internet, or close that tab.
Mayank: Right, everyone?
Mayank: Unknowingly, we have been doing this.
Mayank: If we are opening a website here.
Mayank: dark web, Lilo, you can take any example. But we used to close our internet, or we used to close our, close our browser, or anything, or your machine. So there, weren't we closing the connection, everyone, to HTTP?
Mayank: This is what we used to do.
Mayank: So, unknowingly, you see that how we were doing all these things? Just that you needed a mentor to tell you that this is what it is, nothing else, okay?
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear. Let's move forward.
Mayank: If it is connected to the MCP server, will it not be listed in the log? Here it is not showing. I will show you in the cloud. Here, it is not showing, okay?
Mayank: Mayanka, things we are showing things, it should be better if we can also do the hands-on on the class, we can take half class for it.
Mayank: OccupetelNet, this is the reason I asked you to download this MCP Jam, because if you have downloaded, then you would have done the same with me.
Mayank: Rather than looking at the screen. If you have not downloaded this, you cannot see the same practically.
Mayank: Well, genuinely.
Mayank: I, in the last class, asked you to download this, so that you can see the practical rather than seeing a screen.
Mayank: So, it is genuinely not that you are looking at the screen and not getting anything. I'm showcasing you the exact logs. It is as practical as it gets.
Mayank: Because these things are actually hidden in the VS Code, or whenever you try to do this. This is all the architecture level of things, which MCP has taken care of you.
Mayank: But I am going in deep of these things so that you can talk in an interview and you can understand that.
Mayank: Because when you will be defining, nowhere will you be seeing any trace of these things. Nowhere.
Mayank: Because MCP handles that.
Mayank: It's the same as if you want to use internet, you just type Google.com, but behind the scene, I'm showcasing you behind these tools, clear?
Mayank: Ha, that is the reason, huh? Great.
Mayank: And next, everyone, is…
Mayank: when the server closes unexpectedly, so I hope all of you do understand that this is also how
Mayank: the HTTP connection can Stop.
Mayank: But, again, if you think about the same, again, if you think about the same.
Mayank: Then, this is a kind of a problem. If your server closes unexpectedly during your HTTP connection, Dave?
Mayank: Ideally, that points to something being wrong in your connection. Because normally, we terminate the connection, not the server, and server can also go down with plethora of reasons, like, there can be multiple reasons, because of which your server can go down, and once your server goes down, everyone.
Mayank: then I think it makes a lot of sense that we should
Mayank: reconnect to the same gracefully, so that we should try, the client should try to connect to the server again. So, if for any reason Ecalibrate RaW server is facing any problem, and it gets shut down.
Mayank: My client should try to reconnect and see that, hey, what happened wrong? So… but that is also how the shutdown can happen.
Mayank: So, if you want to disconnect your server, you can just
Mayank: Like, kill your server. And everything will be done. It will be lost.
Mayank: If the internet or anything gets, done, that is actually… we are closing the connection from our end. Server is still running. That is not at the server end. So this is exactly how everyone the shutdown part happens. And yes, actually with that, we have covered all the phases in our
Mayank: MCP lifecycle, so initialization, operation, and shutdown. And yes, I think the same will be very, very helpful in understanding that how MCP runs behind the system, because this is something which is the most important part.
Mayank: with respect to interview, and also to designing your MCP server for the highest of the companies, because they would expect that you know the architecture and the lifecycle completely in-depth. And yes, I think that is all what is there.
Mayank: Now I can confidently say that in any interview, be it for any company, if you have revised these things and understood it properly, in depth, which I have told you, even if you showcase by telling all these parts and parcel and also this complete
Mayank: Maybe you can just show them that, hey, there is a tool, or this is how this happens. I don't think any company would be there who can reject you.
Mayank: But that said, now we have understood how and everything this happens. Next part, everyone, we will be understanding about how to now finally create our own MCP servers, and what exactly happens, what is the complete thing around that as well.
Mayank: Though, in that, lots of things are hidden from us, so that is something which we will have to make sure that, via this complete thing, we are able to understand.
Mayank: And there are few more concepts which we will learn, although they are pretty easy to understand what are the spings.
Mayank: and error handling, all these things, but let's first now, in the next part, try to understand practically what exactly, or how can you create your own MCP servers and everything.
Mayank: by using the normal MCP library, which is given by Anthropic, as well as by using the fast MCP, which is now the major way in which we can use our own, or create our own MCP servers.
Mayank: I hope this is clear, everyone.
Mayank: Clear. MCP lifecycle, MCP architecture, the language, everything.
Mayank: We have taken a very, very step-by-step manner. Where the things came in, I tried to explain that. Now, I think… if the internet connection is lost, then how much time server will wait to close the connection? Where we give timeout? So, that is actually the timeout, Mukhla. That is the timeout.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Set it up, understand it, certify it.
Mayank: I see the get call as well in the log. What is all about?
Mayank: We're in here?
Mayank: Vinod… however I'm getting confidence to develop application using AIMCP and Agent, that will get more confident, Vinod. Like, practically, we will understand it.
Mayank: I'll leave you a link Ragh also before the project begins. Sabhak sahifana.
Mayank: interview content, you have to master these things up, rather than having a project. That will be our final projects when we will be having all those things, Clare A2A, RAG, MCP, all those things will be the case, okay? Great. Acha, telling you beforehand, everyone, we will be using GCP for our first project. How many of you are aware about GCP?
Mayank: Google Cloud Platform?
Mayank: Don't know. Highly suggested, again, to check it out, to see that how you can create a…
Mayank: Account on the same?
Mayank: And yeah, that would be helpful.
Mayank: Just to give you a glimpse of your project, before I give you a break, so just wait, everyone, before I give you a break.
Mayank: And…
Mayank: So, upcoming project, I will be telling somewhere like this, Mandal, just to show you, like, how we will be doing the project. Like, I can… actually, it's a financial, finance project.
Mayank: Madeen AI. I think this one was the one, right?
Mayank: So, Ismay, I will be taking up you from the problem. This is a very good MDE kind of a project as well, Md one.
Mayank: So, SME will be understanding about the credit risk detection.
Mayank: how AI request flow will be there, front-end, back-end agent system, and…
Mayank: Diagram by diagram, we will go in depth. So, full-stack A architecture, how the same is getting used, okay?
Mayank: Little bit on the document chunking and everything, then how Cloud Run and everything works.
Mayank: So, you will have to put in the effort, because I will be explaining you these things
Mayank: As they will come up.
Mayank: And, yeah, then we will see the RAG agent. Actually, your project, RAG is also there, but should be fine. Single versus multi-agent, the complete workflow, so this is how you will be having your project.
Mayank: Sat down and created all these things.
Mayank: Yeah, GCPI system architecture.
Mayank: Just telling you, I think it will take another 1 or 2 weeks before… two weeks at least, before we start that.
Mayank: Any specific reason why GCP? Because GCP gives you 3 months of free access, rather than 1 month. So, when we do project on GCP, you will be able to practice them at your end.
Mayank: As compared to Azure, which is just one month. Plus, anyway, we have to cover Azure and AWS as well. Just, I thought of using GCP as the first one. Teja?
Mayank: Cool? Chauhan.
Mayank: Great. So…
Mayank: Now you can have your timer of 10 minutes. This project is without language. Don't worry, don't worry, I will tell you a bit. Should be fine.
Mayank: Okay? Don't worry.
Mayank: Mayank, when are we expecting to finish and start the project? Two weeks back, start. For three to four classes, I will take in your first project.
Mayank: But again, understand the concept. Projects, too, I can take so many things. Take care.
Mayank: Okay, so good of you, and I hope all of you are able to hear me.
Mayank: Coupons, I actually try, I'm not able to create them right now. Let me do it first thing in the tomorrow's class, okay?
Mayank: How much energy do we need, which is not discussed in the course to crack a job in the field of AI? It depends on the type of role which you are, trying to target. Let me come out as well from this. So, yeah, cool. Great. So, again, please advise, but I hope all of you are able to understand and appreciate the in-depth understanding.
Mayank: And how we are trying to master each and every concept, that will genuinely be very, very helpful, so please do that, yeah? Now, again, just taking a quick
Mayank: 5 minutes. If any question I missed out, please ask the same, because once we start, I would just want to now focus on the practical, which all of you were waiting for, yeah? When are we starting RAG? Again, the quote.
Mayank: I told you this in the very first class key.
Mayank: For me, I can teach any of these things, thankfully, because I'm learning this day in, day out.
Mayank: It will depend on once we master MCP and then projects, then we will do that. Because when I will start rag, then you will seek start over, but when will A2A start? So, RVMing classes on 26th and 27th? Acha. 26th will be holiday for sure.
Mayank: Cool, everyone? Make sense?
Mayank: Can I write any certification based on our course, and also will we use GCP authorized agent service in our project? Not GCP authorized agent service. I will not have an authorized access.
Mayank: So, certificates, I think most of them, once we complete the course, you should be able to attempt, because concepts are not more than this, okay?
Mayank: What is 26th and 27th row Y holiday? Again, let me clear it out, just a second.
Mayank: I am the Kinda.
Mayank: Everyone, do you see this? 26th?
Mayank: 26th?
Mayank: This will be holiday, okay? Telling beforehand.
Mayank: Why is it a holiday? Because I'm traveling somewhere, so I will not be available. But yeah. See ya?
Mayank: CCA certification is in demand. Companies are pretty good with people who have that.
Mayank: And yes, I am trying to collate all the resources.
Mayank: Actually, there is no festival or nothing, I am one beef.
Mayank: So, I think 2 months before only I told you, I am on leave, because I have to attend something.
Mayank: Job opening for Fresher is there are not any which I have received. If I receive anything, I will tell you. 4 to 6 or 3 to 6 years is what I have, which I'm forwarding, okay?
Mayank: Great. Cholo. Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: Did you share with Uday Kopar Nay? I will share the same tomorrow.
Mayank: Chica?
Mayank: Can you repeat the certification name? CCAF, Malh Claude Certification, but you cannot give that without company malab. Companies ask you.
Mayank: So they… it… actually, they made it into 4, that's the reason of my delay as well. So, yeah.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Great, let's move forward.
Mayank: StreamMarable HTTP might be in a different system, yes. StreamMobile HTTP ideally can or will be in a different system, yeah?
Mayank: Landing agent certification? Honestly, I'm not aware about that. I am not the best person to understand on the certification side, because I don't believe a lot in certifications, Thanga?
Mayank: With streamable HTTP, we can create remote MCP servers. Take care, everyone.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: Let's move forward, if all is done.
Mayank: Do you have any course on non-coding tools completely? Dr. Kumar, I'm working on that. Gemini is the first tool I'm targeting, so next week I plan to record it. Abhihodasa got a lot of delay, right?
Mayank: Shalom. Cool, everyone. Let's move forward, then. Let's try to… CMCB Practicals.
Mayank: Creating our own MCP servers. A coupon I will be sharing tomorrow, I don't have that. A kapil haven't, saw your message.
Mayank: Pecat?
Mayank: So, once it comes, you will go around that channel. How can I connect you personally via email? You have to email me, but
Mayank: Honestly, I think many emails are there, I will go over them on Monday. Because this week, I was traveling, so I didn't get the time, yeah?
Mayank: Very tiring, traveling is cello. Let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: I think all of you will have VS Code.
Mayank: it is enough.
Mayank: Dear listing. Cool.
Mayank: Let's… let's start, let's do this.
Mayank: So, before we move forward, everyone, into the overall practical part, and I think, actually, the practical part is the easier thing in MCP or any concept, but first, let me quickly now make sure that you do understand how this awesome
Mayank: results which I have shared with you will help you to very nicely revise each and everything, so pay attention. You can just do it step by step, and it will do all the steps which we have mastered. So, again, client to server initialize the request. The best part with JSON RPC, it is able to make sure that
Mayank: That it tells you what all is happening, so pay attention, everyone.
Mayank: Now again, it is interactable in nature, so the reason is that it will be able to
Mayank: Totally just play along once you click on play, or you can do it step by step.
Mayank: If you notice, everyone, share it again.
Mayank: I think that's Udaygo.
Mayank: Ignatable.
Mayank: What's the difference between JSON and JSON RPC? Hardik discussed in the last class? Trying to see the same. Remote procedure calls for RPCs.
Mayank: Link, link, link, where's the link?
Mayank: you know.
Mayank: b… You know.
Mayank: See if all of you are able to attend, access it.
Mayank: Able to access?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Just one more thing. Keep these links handy as well, although I'm planning to move it to my website, but agarapko is Samjan out, you can… I think you can use it for your interview. I don't think any interviewer will have any problem if you open this in front of him and tell that, hey, this is how MCP works. I will be giving you this for all the concepts which we do, yeah?
Mayank: And this is a complete… Overall case. Tika?
Mayank: So, pay attention.
Mayank: If you click on the JSON, you can see the request as well, everyone. I think now, most of the things will make a lot of sense. So, how we are initializing the request, and this is the JSON which we sent.
Mayank: Best part, we have seen the same via our MCP JAM application, again, which is very, very important. Similarly, everyone, this is exactly how you get the response, then how you can initialize the notification. This is for a STDIO server, of course. Once the request is there.
Mayank: That will be sent to the server. Then we can do the tools list.
Mayank: And tool slash list gets called up, everyone.
Mayank: After that, everyone, we can see the same list recipes, get recipes, search recipes. So, normally.
Mayank: To understand the concept, we use very layman kind of an example, like, you will see that everyone is going to use this kind of an example, everyone. So yeah, that is why we have taken a very simple example of list recipe. Then, Client Server tools called
Mayank: We are actually now calling the search recipe with tagQuick, so it is an argument, everyone.
Mayank: And now we are getting the response. Weeknight pasta, 5-minute salsa.
Mayank: Then, we can Client Server, So, we are saying… prompt slash list.
Mayank: Okay? And my server actually is not having prompt. My server told that, hey, I'm just having tools.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So it will give an error.
Mayank: So, just like any JSON call normally, it is just JSON RPC.
Mayank: and client-server, how they are now connecting for a long-running task. So this, I think, I will be covering for the timing, we have not covered this. But yeah, this is exactly how these things happen, everyone. Ping and all these things can happen. And in the end, we can shut down as well. So, in a shutdown, we see something like this.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So… Before that, one more very important thing. So, if we will go back onto this one, everyone.
Mayank: I discussed that why JSON RPC, and now it will make a lot of sense. Lightweight, plain JSON, human-readable at a glance.
Mayank: Transport agnostic. So, JSON RPC, everyone is transport agnostic. Shape, shape, over STD, IO, or HTTP. Now, this line will make a lot of sense that we have cleared this complete,
Mayank: different, different type of transport layer and shutdown. Two-way by design, either side can send a request, notification built in, no ID, fires and expect nothing back. So, yeah, this is a very good revision of what all we have done, and I'm pretty hopeful that this will be really helpful in understanding
Mayank: And quickly revising the complete concept, before any interview or anything. So now in the next part, let's move on to the practical part as well.
Mayank: So I hope this was clear, everyone. Pretty good.
Mayank: Sara will be making a lot of sense. You have seen this multiple times in your life, malam, in your two weeks of… two weekends, rather.
Mayank: Solo, let's move forward then.
Mayank: So, now, everyone, let's… continue our discussion and start with the practical part of our MCP.
Mayank: To make sure that we can understand it, we will be creating a…
Mayank: Easy Server first, and then we will…
Mayank: move on to a project where we will be creating a real-world server. We will be making sure that now that we have understood the concept, we will be creating a locally running server, add the same to Claude desktop, and then also see that how exactly,
Mayank: I will be showcasing that. Claude also, we can see all the logs and everything.
Mayank: Further, then, we will also make a server on, your complete
Mayank: this HTTP URL server which is hosted, which anyone can access, which will be running on… over the cloud or any server, so that those are actually connected via the HTTP stable protocol, everyone. That would be also very, very helpful in the sense.
Mayank: So, now with that, let's start. Just to quickly set the context, we will be creating a recipe box. Pretty simple approach overall.
Mayank: list recipes, then we will have get recipe?
Mayank: And we will have search recipes. Now, one more thing to notice, everyone, which I think I've covered a lot of time while we were covering this, MCP is in the process of
Mayank: Transforming from a legacy to a modern system.
Mayank: That said, just like how Windows 7 and 10 are still used, I think, more than 50% of the PCs.
Mayank: Many of the MCP servers still are following the legacy system.
Mayank: It was launched in the last… week of July, I guess.
Mayank: But, to understand the same, you should be aware about the complete system which we have mastered.
Mayank: Then, we will move on to the modern system and understand what they have changed, what is the stateless future and everything. But, that said.
Mayank: This complete understanding is very, very important, again, because we need to understand that what is changing
Mayank: We need to actually be able to make sense of it.
Mayank: Further, we should actually be able to understand that how people at anthropic
Mayank: level our thinking, what architecture they are making, why they are shifting away from that architecture. So, all those things will be very, very much required. Just few of the parts have changed, which we will also discuss. Now, let's start with this.
Mayank: So I hope all of you are clear with this, everyone.
Mayank: All of you are clear with this still long?
Mayank: Since the NCA get depreciated, how does it happen? So, Vyom, that is what I told, like, it sent up a Discover, nothing else.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: I will cover what is the stateless and everything, and this… all what you have understood, that will be clear.
Mayank: Cholo, let's start, everyone.
Mayank: Cool, can all of you please open the…
Mayank: VS Code for me, if you want to code alongside with me, totally on you, but I hope all of you have this VS Code. This all has been shared with all of you, so yeah, should be fine.
Mayank: to you?
Mayank: So, just giving you a time, so, Gaurav Ko, if you have to open something, quickly open the same.
Mayank: That's beautiful, let me… Fire, I have to reach out to that.
Mayank: person who is hiring, so that I can understand the requirement more properly. Then I will be forwarding your CVs, so that the CVs are relevant, and actually you are able to get the job.
Mayank: Pika?
Mayank: 1CB which I forwarded was good, but somehow the…
Mayank: coding part was where the person faltered. But yeah, should be fine. As we learn ahead, that'd be helpful.
Mayank: Pia? So…
Mayank: The code is not in Git repo. Mayank, can you please concentrate on teaching? Ajoy, sorry, someone asked for the job, so that is the reason. Extremely sorry.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: So, now, everyone, let's try to move forward, and this is something which we kind of created earlier as well, that is your MCP by using the fast MCP.
Mayank: But now, let's try to make sure that we are able to understand more things about this, complete approach.
Mayank: Now, to make sure that you understand the theme from scratch.
Mayank: First, very important thing is to understand that how you can define MCP servers.
Mayank: Now, of course, since it's a protocol, everyone, just like how for creating HTTP or APIs, we have fast API
Mayank: Flask, and all these different, different kind of libraries already available. In a very, very similar manner, we have everyone
Mayank: Libraries which can help us to create MCP servers as well.
Mayank: Now, if you will notice, everyone, in this.
Mayank: Majorly, you will be coming and seeing two libraries, which is the simple MCP one, so that is nothing but the official MCP library.
Mayank: by your clot, or anthropic. And second, everyone, is your fast MCP1.
Mayank: Which… Is, again, created by someone to make sure that they are able to make…
Mayank: MCP servers a lot more easily. So, we will try to understand both of them and see that what exactly is the case. So, let's try to actually quickly see the history.
Mayank: The code is not in the repo, huh, I will… I think… let me quickly push it, one minute. So, till the time, like, the till… what code I have, let me push it, okay?
Mayank: It is on my local, actually, so that is where you might not be able to see it, but no worries, let me just… give me a minute.
Mayank: Now I think it has been pushed. Can you check once quickly? Can you do a git pull?
Mayank: Can you do a git poll quickly?
Mayank: Link?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Ocho siepro que euros.
Mayank: I think now everything should be there, Mehlam. I have just pinked it, so where is it, where is it? Complete MCP?
Mayank: Pirro.
Mayank: Where is this folder?
Mayank: Correct.
Mayank: MCP warm-up.
Mayank: Committed.
Mayank: MCP will… Okay, let me try to… one minute, just let me check. Fetching origin… If pressing commit…
Mayank: Your branch is updated to update intact file MCP warmup, nothing adds to the commit, but intact files appear and get add to track.
Mayank: Just a minute, let me quickly check.
Mayank: MCP warm-up, you might not be able to see, right, everyone?
Mayank: only via TFL. Some vital file I have to tell, can't see your desktop? No, the desktop is there.
Mayank: SB you cannot see the MCP warm-up, apologies, let me try to add that.
Mayank: Sure, why it is not there? Have I ignored that?
Mayank: Git, gitignore.
Mayank: Range, strange, strange.
Mayank: A show invalid path while LRA, let me fix it.
Mayank: Just a minute, everyone, let me fix it.
Mayank: Just focus on the learning ones, I will fix it and add the code by when the class gets over. Just as soon as the class gets over, I will do that. Okay?
Mayank: I hope that makes sense.
Mayank: There is, I think, I'm trying to actually make your notes a lot better. Actually, have you on all these notes helpful, the way I'm making it?
Mayank: What these notes are, we are making it helpful.
Mayank: Thus kili, I think that was facing some issues, so let me fix it. Not sure that why there is an error coming up. So, Japayap, you will go on any class.
Mayank: I have to add, for MCP, you can see the class summary. Kudos to the person, I forget the name, but yes, he helped a lot, so he's creating these things up, and then I'm using the same from them, okay? So, Chalo, let me just use that.
Mayank: For the timing, focus on the learning part, then we will understand and master this. Thinkya? Shalom.
Mayank: I have to run the getting node and all these things, so I will do that. Should not be a problem.
Mayank: Cheer, chill.
Mayank: I will fix the errors, don't worry, I will fix the errors. Thank you.
Mayank: Can you push the code before the class if it is pre-coded? It is not precoded as such. I try to majorly code few things alongside, so that would be the case.
Mayank: Shalom. Great, great, great. Let's move forward, everyone. So, again, everyone, we will have to make sure that we are downloading these libraries and everything via pip install, and both of them give the same MCP inspector, which actually we have seen. But now, since we are focusing up properly on the
Mayank: overall, practical. Let's quickly try to understand the brief history, everyone. So, this very nice diagram can also be very helpful in the history part. So, again, the same is required because you can be asked to use either the MCP library.
Mayank: If, by any chance, a company is not supporting the fast MCP, though I don't guess that is the point now. And a very easy way to understand it is with the TensorFlow and the Keras operation, how TensorFlow was the one from Google, then someone created Keras. Kind of very similar thing happened here.
Mayank: Anthropic released the original MCP specification and its official Python SDK. So, if you will search on Google, everyone, MCP Python SDK,
Mayank: It will take you to the official SDK, Software Development Kit, for… Python?
Mayank: via the MCP, which is your Anthropic. So, if you will notice, everyone, you can install the same MCP CLI, there is via pip as well.
Mayank: They have moved to some V2 version 2, and then you can easily create the same in a very similar manner.
Mayank: And earlier, this was very, very difficult to start and work on. I don't think I can show you the previous
Mayank: code, though I will try to write it down, so you get a
Mayank: overall idea of how difficult it was. Now they are kind of converging, like, how
Mayank: fast Keras and TensorFlow kind of converse. So, moving back, everyone, what happened was that they came up with this thing. Then, again, not long after, because it was a little bit difficult, it was very verbose. You had to write lots of code for creating a simple MCP server. An independent developer, Jeremia Lovin.
Mayank: Okay? He is a founder of a… co-founder of a tool as well. He built a standalone MCP… fast MCP library. Now, just to point out here, many of you might be aware about FastAPI.
Mayank: How many of you have heard about FastAPI?
Mayank: Just to let you know, like, they are not directly connected.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: It is not that people and FastAPI, they created Fast MCP.
Mayank: So your interview, malab, you should not get confused on this. It has been created by an individual developer.
Mayank: So, FAST MCP is not directly created by Fast.
Mayank: API, like the company and everything behind it. That is the reason if you will go in here and see their way of defining everything.
Mayank: Versus if you search Fast MCP,
Mayank: very, very different they are, like, the way they are created and everything, and many students have this problem. It is in Prefect HQ, the reason being because
Mayank: The person, this is Jeremy, he is the founder of Prefect HQ, okay? So, if you will quickly search. So, just these things are helpful in understanding how things got, kind of…
Mayank: Define. Okay, so in that case, it is very, very helpful.
Mayank: And overall, if you see founder, Jeremy Lohman, Prefect. So, yes, this person came up with fast MCP, everyone.
Mayank: And the best part is that
Mayank: Fast MCP and FastAPI, they are very, very compatible with each other. Like, if you see Fast API,
Mayank: They are used to create API servers, because if you think about this.
Mayank: Actually, all the tools in your MCP are very, very close to just APIs. Now that we have understood the same in depth, I think all of us understand that how they are genuinely very, very close to just APIs only. So, anyway, if you are defining everyone.
Mayank: a simple API server, just by writing a single line, you can change all of this into an MCP. So in that ways, they are very compatible, but
Mayank: They are not from the same parent company. Even though the name can be misleading, that is the case. Now let's move forward, everyone.
Mayank: So, again, Now, if you will notice, this kind of became very much used upon Fast MCP.
Mayank: And Fast MCP 1.0, like, the first version was so popular that Anthropic, okay, people and Anthropic.
Mayank: They folded a version of it into the official SDK. So now you will notice that how the same is not very, very difficult, everyone. And again, standalone Fast MCP remains what most real servers use.
Mayank: The official SDK renamed its own Mental class to avoid the confusion. So just to make sure that you
Mayank: are aware about the same while you're using it, because using will be very, very simple. In that case.
Mayank: A very good example, anyone who wants to understand this, is exactly TensorFlow and Keras.
Mayank: TensorFlow was created by Google to write your neural networks and all the CNN and Jain.
Mayank: it was very difficult to write and work with. Someone created KANAS, which was genuinely very, very easy. Google hired that person, and then further made sure that
Mayank: all the good parts and everything of Keras is something which has been taken inside of TensorFlow. The same thing has happened here as well, everyone, but still this distinction is very, very required. So now what I will do, everyone, I will just make sure to open a terminal in here. So let me quickly open the…
Mayank: 10 minutes?
Mayank: And I will clear everything up. Let's… Just try to go out.
Mayank: create CD… First, MCP server. So, I'm creating a folder agreement.
Mayank: No such file, okay, my bad, main directory. First, MCP… Sir what?
Mayank: Now I can CD inside the same.
Mayank: Clare H and everything. So, if you will notice, everyone, now we have made sure that we are having this folder. MCP warm-up is something which I use to explain you around the same as well.
Mayank: I hope each and every one of you are clear with this thing till now.
Mayank: I hope each and every one of you are clear with the same thing now.
Mayank: Great, let's move forward quickly, then.
Mayank: Is it pre-coded? What I'm going to code? No.
Mayank: Not pre-coded as such.
Mayank: But a few other parts, the previous liability is.
Mayank: Okay? Actually, I might have the gold, one minute. Let me provide you it.
Mayank: Just a minute, let me look.
Mayank: push to GitHub, yeah? Add the code, stop with that.
Mayank: So, I'm going to show you by writing few of the code, few of the code I will be using. The… I will just show you the legacy code, because that is also, you can encounter somewhere, like, again, majorly in the company and everything.
Mayank: Okay, so just one minute.
Mayank: Just a minute.
Mayank: How many of you have ever tried to, create a pip package as well? Let me know, we can create a pip package off our MCP as well, but let me see, Pallab. If the time permits, I will do that.
Mayank: Do you need to quote alongside with me? If you want, you can, should not be a problem.
Mayank: But I will suggest to first master these things up.
Mayank: So, that, at least, understanding is not taking a backseat.
Mayank: So, just for a minute, everyone, I'm pushing in the code, like, a few of the things which I had in me.
Mayank: And then you need to set a completely new project and folder as you have started from scratch. Hamada, I will be showcasing that to you.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: When… why more of none of my message? Extremely sorry, Rahul, can you ask it again? I try not to miss any messages. Extremely, extremely sorry. Just, like, lots of messages, but I stay till the end to clear all the doubts.
Mayank: Extremely sorry from my end. Teja?
Mayank: Chalo. Let's move forward then with this, everyone. Let's try to do… I will be doing it from the scratch, but we will be quickly coming up to the thing, okay? We will quickly just catch up.
Mayank: So, now everyone, what we can do, once we have created a folder, I can just make sure that I write it uvinit.
Mayank: So, now we have the first project initialized in the same. So, as you can see, this is going to be my main file, everyone. Let me close all others.
Mayank: Let us save this.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: swallow should be fine, great. So…
Mayank: Since we have already created this MCP warm-up, you will notice that how this is the main file, everyone, where we maintain each and everything. So, first, MCP server.
Mayank: We can add the description and all these things up. Okay, so right here in the current folder, we have set up a complete folder.
Mayank: Now, what we have to make sure, everyone, is that
Mayank: We are adding the libraries which we want, so what you can do, UV add MCP?
Mayank: So, this is a separate library, everyone, and UV add Fast MCP.
Mayank: This is a separate library. So, clearing everything up…
Mayank: Now, we have a virtual environment, everyone, which you can see, so let me just… Quickly.
Mayank: showcase the scene. So, in this environment, everything is there. We have the file as well. Let me just create a new file.
Mayank: Where I will just write down quickly so, it is your…
Mayank: What was the name of the file which we have? Yes.
Mayank: Let me quickly create a file, everyone.
Mayank: And here, I will not be coding from scratch, because this is something which we just have to show you the
Mayank: Earlier way, the…
Mayank: low-level or legacy way. So, you appreciate that, okay, how far we have come in the complete approach, yeah? So, in that case, now if you will notice, everyone, I've just pasted the code, and I've shared the file with all of you as well. Though you will be getting the file and everything
Mayank: Alongside with this. So, till now, I have created a UV environment. I have added MCP and fast MCP.
Mayank: This, you just have to quickly read everyone, not actually create like this, but I just want to show you the pain as well, okay? So, earlier, what we have to do, everyone.
Mayank: We have to create the… tools, and everything like this. So, you have to create a list tools function.
Mayank: Tell all the different, different tools.
Mayank: Then you have to write some code like this, that, okay, this is list recipes, when you will be calling a tool.
Mayank: If getRecipe is there, so we have to check each and everything.
Mayank: And that was not the case very, very much time back, like, just, I guess, 6-7 months before, this is how we used to define our servers.
Mayank: So, again, you can read through this code, but what I want to showcase is that earlier, if we have to create an MCP server where we are having these three tools.
Mayank: this was the exact way of writing that code up. So…
Mayank: A little bit complex, a little bit verbose in that sense.
Mayank: Something which you would love to avoid, right?
Mayank: In that case, That is where, of course, we have fast MCP come up, everyone.
Mayank: So, first, if you will notice, we are writing the list recipe, the description, the schema, because all this will be sent when we call the list tools function, tools slash list call.
Mayank: Similarly, when we are calling the particular tool.
Mayank: We will be making sure that we give the name of the tool, and the argument of the tool as well, so that when the name gets matched up.
Mayank: I will get the arguments and use it as well. So, again, a little bit complex, don't want you to spend a lot of time here.
Mayank: What I want to showcase is that… and again, we can run the same as well, everyone. I've given all the commands. So, if we just…
Mayank: Click.
Mayank: this particular code.
Mayank: python3 recipe, low level.py.
Mayank: it will try to start up a MCP server, and the same will get started. That should not be an issue at all. We can inspect it via the MCP inspector as well.
Mayank: But, for us, the way we will be creating our MCPs will be much easier.
Mayank: And that is going to be via… fast MCP.
Mayank: Now, in Fast MCP, everyone, it is generally pretty simple. So, we just do Fast MCP import, fast MCP,
Mayank: Just like how we do a lot with our overall, fast API case.
Mayank: Now, the best part, I could just…
Mayank: Copy the recipes, everyone. So, this recipes will be used as an example. Let me close this up, and let me also do one thing.
Mayank: Let me just quickly… Before I move forward, I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: How more of if else nesting, hell, and all these things. Like, how the code is difficult, that is my main takeaway from this. Malhan, this was initially how you used to define the MCP servers.
Mayank: I'm just showcasing, not going in-depth, not spending even more than 2 minutes. Just showcasing, ki from where we started. That is also required. Plus.
Mayank: Believe me when I say this, you can still see this code.
Mayank: you can still see this code. Clear?
Mayank: in any company.
Mayank: You can still see the code, so you don't have to be afraid. You don't have to be clear. Mayanko, Mayank told us very simple things. Clear, everyone?
Mayank: Async Def, why are we using? So, to make our function asynchronous in the call, like.
Mayank: If multiple calls are being made and everything, we are able to do that.
Mayank: Acha, I have to explain you about the asynchronous and everything. I will try to provide the recording, because I find many people who are not aware about this thing. Teja?
Mayank: One minute, everyone, just let me activate the right environment as well.
Mayank: Sweep.
Mayank: not me in meaning.
Mayank: Wait, wait, slash, okay.
Mayank: Jeez?
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Asha, should I explain it step-by-step or write the code directly?
Mayank: Milam, how comfortable are you?
Mayank: Step-by-step or write the code directly.
Mayank: Step by step, Deca. Are you saying this one?
Mayank: Murthy that this one is all step and pieces?
Mayank: Are you seeing this one? How this is all step-in pieces, and not easy to understand?
Mayank: Murthy?
Mayank: Take care. Ha. Malhan, first, everyone is able to understand the problem here?
Mayank: Everyone is able to understand the problem in here.
Mayank: Okay, how this is very, very difficult. I'm not explaining this, because you will not be writing it like this now.
Mayank: The whole idea is that I just want to show you it is difficult, nothing else.
Mayank: Although, if you will read it, it will make sense, but love, we have…
Mayank: that level of Python knowledge, but shall…
Mayank: Now, if we notice, everyone, the same thing if you have to write in the latest MCP versions, or even in the fast MCP space, that is very, very easy.
Mayank: Now, what I will do, I will just quickly create an MCP server, so fast… Fast MCP.
Mayank: Okay, recipe box.
Mayank: Now, pay attention, what I have to do.
Mayank: I will just be now defining the tools. So, this thing makes it this much easier, like, genuinely, I'm able to get the whole thing in here very nicely.
Mayank: So, what I will do, everyone, I can just write def.
Mayank: and list recipes. It will be returning a list of dictionary.
Mayank: And I'm just completing the code, so I'm just taking help of the autocomplete, but I guess…
Mayank: It should be pretty simple to understand.
Mayank: I'm just making sure that I am able to, in this recipes items, return this complete recrecipes.items.
Mayank: And similarly, everyone, what I can do, I can just define the next MCP tool.
Mayank: MCP.tool.
Mayank: And I could define get recipes, and as you can see.
Mayank: I can just, based on the ID of the recipe, get a particular recipe as well.
Mayank: This is what we were doing in here.
Mayank: Right? This is actually what we were doing in here.
Mayank: The same thing, in a much easier manner, can be just done via this.
Mayank: Via the MCP, so I will… let me now explain the code. This is a dictionary, everyone, which we are using. It is having an ID, it is having the title, minutes, and tags.
Mayank: Then we are having list recipe.
Mayank: First, we create a MCP, so fast MCP object we are creating.
Mayank: The very first tool or function or API which I'm creating, everyone, is List Recipes.
Mayank: In the same, we are just returning ID and title by reading this, so for key and value in recipes.items.
Mayank: I'm seeing that, hey, my ID is this 123.
Mayank: And… k… Sorry, title is this…
Mayank: V slash title. So, whatever I'm getting in the value, the complete title.
Mayank: For getting a particular recipe, I required a recipe ID. Here, I don't require anything.
Mayank: And this is very, very much how we normally write the API code. I hope that makes sense, everyone. Anyone finding difficulty in understanding the two tools?
Mayank: For anyone for whom this two tools are not clear?
Mayank: But they are very, very simple, I'm just writing a function, nothing else.
Mayank: If we try to understand, this is actually just writing a
Mayank: function, or in defining an API.
Mayank: And similarly, everyone, in the end, we are seeing that how we have the recipe ID, now we can do MCP tool, and we can search the recipe by tag as well.
Mayank: And in the end, everyone, all we have to do is, we have to just make sure that we can start up our server, so if
Mayank: Name equals main. I will just say MCP dot
Mayank: And yes, if we try to compare them side by side, This is why…
Mayank: Even people at MCP Official Laddery thought that, hey, We should be…
Mayank: integrating this thing into our own, because else no one will be using it. So that was the whole idea, everyone. Now, if you will notice, this is how easily we can create our MCP servers.
Mayank: And the best part, here you don't have to write the list MCP calls or get MCP calls and everything. It will run itself, because that is where the fast MCP library is going to help us. So generally, it is that easy, everyone, that just by defining this particular line of code.
Mayank: We can easily just use the same.
Mayank: Now, one more thing to notice here, to test it out when you are kind of doing it for the very, very first time.
Mayank: There is something which is known as MCP inspector, which we also learned and saw in the very first case. So now what I will do, if you want to pay attention.
Mayank: I will just run this command.
Mayank: So, I will quickly just run this command.
Mayank: NPX MCP inspector Python 3 recipe box, fast MCP PY.
Mayank: Now, I've already shown you how to install MCP connector initially, and the second I run this.
Mayank: it will start up, so it is saying MCP inspector port is in use, okay? So let's try to understand how can we change this port up.
Mayank: Let me go to Google.
Mayank: Let's use Gemini for this.
Mayank: And that's good.
Mayank: how to change the port. So, already my 6274 is being used. Let's see where it is being used first.
Mayank: Go to this particular port.
Mayank: Yeah, so MCP Jam is actually running on this port, everyone. Okay, so that is the reason it is not working. MCP Jam is actually running on my machine on this port, so no worries, we will just quickly see
Mayank: how we can… so either I can kill my MCP jam.
Mayank: If required. Or I could make sure that I am just changing the port. Normally, there will be some slash slash port configuration.
Mayank: Okay, not sure why this is so slow, let me go to ChatGPT.
Mayank: ChatGPT.
Mayank: Paste it.
Mayank: And now let's see this.
Mayank: Hopefully, it will just give the answer. So… yeah, so we just have to give the port like this.
Mayank: I hope all of you are able to understand, right? It is not hyphen hyphen boot, that was not the case, okay?
Mayank: Building MCP is good with Python or Node, which is preferable. A language doesn't… has an effect.
Mayank: So, now I can just copy this, everyone, and make sure that I'm giving 6280 a support.
Mayank: Okay, so it is still saying this is wrong, let me check it.
Mayank: And this is where, again, AI is a very good saver. Let me just paste it.
Mayank: If this doesn't work, then we will kill the MCP jam to free up our port, okay? We don't want that it uses it a lot.
Mayank: But hopefully, we are just… I think either it will be slash slash port then. Okay, so it is Client Port, yeah, that is even what I required. Remember, sorry.
Mayank: See, the second you hit this particular, call everyone.
Mayank: this MCP inspector will get open. Very, very similar like MCP Jam, but yeah, now you will very nicely be able to
Mayank: see all the things which I was showing you by MCP Jam.
Mayank: Via the same thing. So, before I move forward, let me now explain you the complete thing in a step-by-step manner.
Mayank: So, pay attention, everyone.
Mayank: First, I showed you that how
Mayank: we can create a low-level MCP
Mayank: by using the earlier official version of MCP library, and why that was very, very difficult, how we were creating a library, and that was very, very difficult.
Mayank: This part, everyone is clear, can I get a smiley face?
Mayank: Can I get a smiley face if this part was clear? Ki, this was problematic?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Next, everyone, we understood that how the same thing can be done by fast MCP library, which, again, was created by someone which helped us to create our MCP servers very nicely.
Mayank: And it has been integrated into the official MCP library as well.
Mayank: Then, Mayank, why are we learning it? Because in companies, we can still find the previous code. The code which is written like this.
Mayank: Because I specifically remember, just 6 months ago, I was creating my MCP servers by writing code like this.
Mayank: Plus, at the end of the day, it may have been the case that many companies
Mayank: They don't use the libraries which are not official or otherwise, though I feel with Fast MCP we don't have any such issues.
Mayank: So, we have created our server.
Mayank: Now, everyone, the next Obvious step to do or Ranjit.
Mayank: is to see the same in a visualized manner. Of course, we can start up our MCP server and connect it with Claude and everything, but first, we need to also see the same right in front of us.
Mayank: Because, till now, whatever we have seen practically.
Mayank: More or less, we have seen by the lifecycle and everything, by the servers which were already created.
Mayank: This server, I'm getting right in front of us, so it is a local server.
Mayank: Both of these gets connected to something known as MCP Inspector.
Mayank: And MCP inspector doesn't care how you build your server, which I think is also very logical. MCP inspector just care that, hey.
Mayank: Can… is your server defined correctly? So that is all what MCP Inspector cares.
Mayank: And one more thing to note here, everyone.
Mayank: Though I will be showcasing you the steps via MCP Inspector, which we have learned, you don't have to learn them to create MCP for the time being.
Mayank: That said.
Mayank: Of course, when we will learn MCP and try… if you will try to make any advanced changes, then all those things will come up.
Mayank: So, till now, I think everyone… everything is clear.
Mayank: Till now, each and everything is clear.
Mayank: Can I get a smiley face if everything is clear?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Now, to start MCP Inspector, everyone, it says that, hey, I will start on 6274 port.
Mayank: But… Unfortunately, our this port is already being used by MCP chat.
Mayank: So, again, nothing difficult here, just how, when you run things on local host, you have to make sure that your port and host is actually active.
Mayank: Either I can kill my MCP jam, everyone, so I can kill this MCP jam.
Mayank: Like, this was the error or the problem which I faced. If you will see everyone here.
Mayank: When I tried to run, It is saying that, hey.
Mayank: The port is already in use, Mehm. Why are you… how can you use it? It is like you are trying to make your website active on Google.com.
Mayank: So, you will get an error that, hey, how can you make your website active on Google.com? It is already in use.
Mayank: So either we could have killed this, everyone, because we have to make the space.
Mayank: Or we just quickly debug the same, and I did the same very, very quickly. So… because, again, it is just copy-pasting the code on ChatGPT.
Mayank: And… MCP inspector say that, hey, you can tell me the port like this. Client port.
Mayank: I said that, okay, you start on 6280 now, don't start on that.
Mayank: And once I do that, everyone, I see that how actually I'm able to have the
Mayank: complete port getting started in here. So, this is the link, everyone.
Mayank: 127006280.
Mayank: And you can open it by copying this particular link.
Mayank: So, easily, you can just copy this, and you will be able to see something like this, which is an MCP inspector.
Mayank: I hope this is also clear, everyone.
Mayank: now MCP inspector. We have done… seen this MCP inspector earlier as well. Okay?
Mayank: Please stop it again, tell Step 2, run the code.
Mayank: I did not get… please provide the link. I cannot… it is a localhost hunting thing, everyone. How can I provide the link for this?
Mayank: SCGs about Pooja?
Mayank: It's a localhost running window.
Mayank: It is running on my local host.
Mayank: Anyone who can tell me how can I provide the link for this if I have to provide it?
Mayank: Any way anyone is aware?
Mayank: of a concept.
Mayank: Yes, it is, no? SAI tunneling.
Mayank: NGROC, yeah. Tunneling by ngrok.
Mayank: I can do that.
Mayank: Chica?
Mayank: MGROC can be helpful, because it is running on my machine, I can give it via that, okay?
Mayank: So, what I will do, everyone, I will just quickly close these MCP servers, clear everything out, just show you by running, refreshing it, and showing that how this has been died now, so nothing is running, and I will do the complete step again. So, this is the command, everyone.
Mayank: We have to just make sure that we are giving the Client port as well here.
Mayank: And normally, to make it a little bit more easy, what I will do is, I will change this client port to
Mayank: So, I love to run my things like this, 9999.
Mayank: So that I know that, yes, I'm in control. So, I'm trying to do this 9999.
Mayank: Paste it.
Mayank: And now it will start on.
Mayank: a different port. So, if I run this, See?
Mayank: Now, on 9999, I'm having my NCB inspector, everyone.
Mayank: And again, I think in your case, if you're not running FCP Jam, your port will be free, but yes.
Mayank: And now, I think, because we understood everything in depth, you can just connect to the same every month.
Mayank: And it will be very much like how we have seen it. So…
Mayank: If you will notice, everyone, I can just make sure that I show you each and everything in here. If you go on protocol, you can see all the different, different things, how we have mastered them.
Mayank: So, initialized call getting made.
Mayank: Response?
Mayank: Then, we have the client server telling that, hey, we have initialized
Mayank: Then we are having Client Server Resource List.
Mayank: But we don't have any source?
Mayank: Tools list, we are having 3 tools, everyone. And we have not defined this tools list. Fast MCP is taking care of this.
Mayank: Similarly, Client Server prompt list.
Mayank: There is nothing prompt, no prompt or anything.
Mayank: And finally, resources, template, no template as well.
Mayank: So, when it gets connected, everyone, when your MCP connector starts, it hits all these calls, okay? It hits all those different, different calls.
Mayank: Which is nothing but your… tools list.
Mayank: resource list, prompt list, and this, prompt resource template list as well. So, that is the whole case. I can clear the same out and showcase to you the same thing properly again. See?
Mayank: All of them got fixed up, and it happens real-time very, very quickly.
Mayank: And if I want everyone, I can see the tools in here, so how all of these are the tools.
Mayank: Prompt is empty because, of course, we have not created the prompts. We will be creating it in the next part.
Mayank: Resources is also empty.
Mayank: I can make it dark mode.
Mayank: You can see that how can I disconnect from the server?
Mayank: And everything?
Mayank: So, let us try to disconnect it, and everything is, gone. Connecting it again, we'll start it again.
Mayank: I can go on Tools and call this List Recipe. So it doesn't require anything from my site.
Mayank: I can do executeTool, and see?
Mayank: I got all the things.
Mayank: In the protocol.
Mayank: Yeah, so you will see there is a tool slash call where list recipe is there. So I call the list recipe.
Mayank: I'm not sure that why it is not logging it out. I think I will have to make sure that I log it separately, because…
Mayank: If you remember, there was a log functionality, which we discussed in the
Mayank: part of our capabilities, so if we do capability negotiation. There is server logging as well, so that is what we will use to log the same, but for the time being.
Mayank: Protocol is happening, all these things up here. So, list SCPs, and we are able to see each and everything in here.
Mayank: I hope this thing is clear, everyone.
Mayank: The code is written in GPS code, but you said you will do it in GCP. Nay Murthy, I told that project we will be doing in GCP. The Lang chain project we will be doing in GCP.
Mayank: GCP may… why will I tell there? Teja?
Mayank: I hope that makes sense, everyone.
Mayank: Ki how this is working?
Mayank: MCP projects are locally krata. The MCP project doesn't require that. We can host it, but yes.
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: First, is this thing clear now?
Mayank: How this is happening? This is an STDIO server, yes.
Mayank: This is an STDIO server, everyone. I hope this thing is clear.
Mayank: Vi escuria.
Mayank: Obvious could happen?
Mayank: Can we get another tool which input is needed? Harley to be done the same.
Mayank: Why is it showing in protocol? Because that is all part of the protocol. Logging is separate, like, we can do the logging part as well. Oski…
Mayank: I… let me just try to do… I forgot the code, but let me still ask.
Mayank: Okay, let me just do one thing, okay?
Mayank: Let me… I forgot the syntax, but let me do one thing.
Mayank: Can we do this?
Mayank: And… stupid.
Mayank: Change.
Mayank: Though… tool, so it logs as well. I think it was possible, let me just check it up quickly.
Mayank: Huh.
Mayank: First MCP DeSync. Asynchronously, it will be able to do that. Let me copy this.
Mayank: Paste it.
Mayank: I will explain it, don't worry, okay?
Mayank: Did you go?
Mayank: Let me… At least on the server.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: MCP inspector is a host with Client, yes.
Mayank: Cool, we'll start.
Mayank: Do we define STDIO in Steamable HTTP ourselves, or Fast MCP take care of it? Ideally, we have to define it ourselves. Like, I will be creating a…
Mayank: that server as well, we have the STDIO thing as well, but I… when you define it like this.
Mayank: It just runs on the server, which you can access anywhere, okay?
Mayank: So, now, everyone, let's move forward. What I have done is that I have chained this getRecipe tool. So, earlier my tool was very, very simple, in where it was genuinely just a simply written tool.
Mayank: Like this.
Mayank: Where we were not having any logging functionality or something. So I just pasted the same to ChatGPT and asked it that, okay.
Mayank: Providing me the same.
Mayank: So that I can get the recipes, and it can log the same as well. Now, if you will see everyone, we have already seen list recipes.
Mayank: GetRecipe earlier was like this. Now we have just added the
Mayank: complete logging part as well, so let's try to see this as well. Again, the same part. You'll just… Oauth is only supported for HTTP paste. Okay, let me check what exactly happened here.
Mayank: So I think we have… Use something. So let me go back and give the error.
Mayank: Mallabbit will fix it. Should be fine.
Mayank: Should be fine. I will do this separately, everyone, that would make a lot of sense, so for the timing, let's…
Mayank: Let's, let's, let's just jump back with their approach, because this will be showcasing I,
Mayank: the HTTP one, the remote server which we will create. So, let me showcase that there, should be fine.
Mayank: Okay, let me remove it, and go back to the current view.
Mayank: Okay, so…
Mayank: Cool, everyone, so now let's try to understand the same, like, how exactly I will be just restarting the server, okay?
Mayank: Clear everything up, restart the server again.
Mayank: And again, just refresh it.
Mayank: In here, once I run it, easily we can run any other tool as well, so I can get the recipe. In here, I will just provide the recipe ID and execute the tool. And see, I'm able to get everything.
Mayank: Protocol get recipe was called. It is combining the parameters, how the same was sent to everyone, but now you know that how it is just on RPC2, and how you're getting the response. It is an STDIO server, okay, so it is a STDIO, where
Mayank: I'm able to send in the input, so this one, when I send everyone.
Mayank: I'm able to send it as an input, and it has been taken up, and the output, whatever is given, that has been shown. Now, just to help you quickly revise, this kind of has…
Mayank: culminated.
Mayank: into this complete architecture diagram, everyone, which I think now each and every one of us is able to understand.
Mayank: So, what exactly happened is that we are able to just quickly see
Mayank: That… how we have a server in place, how we are having a complete host.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: this… host, everyone, it gets connected to my…
Mayank: two clients, or I can have, like, Multiple clients in here, everyone?
Mayank: So I can have clients.
Mayank: This host will be something which will be connected via my cloud or any AI.
Mayank: So I will be having Claude, or any other… yeah, everyone?
Mayank: which I can connect my… Host 2?
Mayank: Then, I can have… my… Client connected to multiple servers.
Mayank: Either it can be, let's say, or HTTP-based, HTTP streamable, Or it can be STDIO.
Mayank: Now we have created our own getRecipeServer everyone.
Mayank: get recipe.
Mayank: Where we have given it tools.
Mayank: Where we have provided it with tools.
Mayank: Or we can create our… so, in future, we will be creating our HTTP server as well.
Mayank: Okay, so we will maybe try to see the same server, let's say…
Mayank: Or I can, for the timing, mention any…
Mayank: Go G drive server or something.
Mayank: And it can be HTTP, and it can have tools and everything else as well. And that is how you can easily create your MCP server in a very, very simple sense. Now let's try to move forward and see how can we quickly add the recipes and
Mayank: our, sorry, resources and prompts as well. Then we will make sure that, since we understand how to get an MCP server and everything, we will understand on the client part as well.
Mayank: And then we will do a little bit advanced kind of a project, because over the next few parts, we will just be coding in MCP now, rather than actually creating these dummy small projects. But yes, for understanding, this part is very, very important.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense, everyone.
Mayank: Here in the current code, I have not used Claud LLM call, right? No, no, no, we have not used it. Ideally, when the KAULD will be used, then it will be…
Mayank: taking the call, which recipe has to be called, like, if I ask Claude that, hey, call…
Mayank: Get me the… items in Client SCP ID 1, so that is how it will happen. Clear?
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Mcp inspector is your client, so it is starting up a client which is connected. Okay, Purun? Purna?
Mayank: Can we connect one client to HTTIO and another client to HTTP server? Yes, that is possible. Totally, totally possible.
Mayank: Ni, kapil again, to clear it out.
Mayank: MCP Inspector doesn't care if fast MCP or MCP water is installed.
Mayank: It says that, okay, your… MCP, whatever you have defined here, it should be properly defined.
Mayank: It is just like a front-end. It doesn't care how your MCP server is created.
Mayank: Clear, everyone?
Mayank: It doesn't actually care how your
Mayank: MCP server is created, it just tries to connect with the same, nothing else.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: So MCP inspector is just the UI, or, like, in our case, it is actually your…
Mayank: Client and, server… sorry, client and host.
Mayank: So MCP Inspector is both kind of client and host here.
Mayank: It doesn't care, it just sees that, okay, there is a server which I have to connect to. It doesn't care, like, the server can be anyways, anywhere, I can… in here, I cannot add the server, but yes, otherwise, I can add the servers and all these things as well.
Mayank: Clear?
Mayank: What is the difference between MCP Jam and MCP Inspector? Nothing as such, just MCP Jam is a little bit more advanced.
Mayank: And yeah, at this point, this seems like a modernist API call, yeah, kind of like that, okay?
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: So, now everyone, this thing is clear that how we can create a very simple kind of a server, and now if I show you the official MCP SDK as well, you will see that how…
Mayank: A few parts of the syntax are different, but otherwise, it has also emulgated or taken over the complete thing, so if I just make it dark mode…
Mayank: MCP, MCP server, how it is defining the tool. So, yes, you don't have to define the tool like that now, everyone, but yes. Overall, this is how the latest version of MCP works.
Mayank: This, similarly, is MCP… fast MCP, everyone, where you define the same in this manner, the one which we have done.
Mayank: And yeah, now, I don't want that you go in depth of this complete thing, because you will be covering it, how to define and everything, unless and until
Mayank: You are…
Mayank: given a task in a company where you have to define a proper end-to-end MCP server, but otherwise, the way we are defining the server and everything, that should be more than enough. We can make the function and everything more complex now.
Mayank: But the way of defining it is very, very simple. The way you define a function, or an API, that is how it will be used, everyone. Now, just let's quickly move forward and see how we can create our, that as well, the source and everything. So, for the same everyone, what I will do…
Mayank: Quickly, I will just, create a resource.
Mayank: So, let me just use it here.
Mayank: Say it as resource.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: First, I will have valid tags. So, this is a resource, if you think about this.
Mayank: I'm just trying to make sure that I'm creating the tags which are present, so that my Client.
Mayank: it is able to get that, okay, these are all the tags which my server supports. I hope it is able to understand everyone.
Mayank: Does MCP Client can handle multiple concurrent requests to its connected MCP server, and how? It depends on how you have defined your MCP server.
Mayank: The exact way in which your normal server works, where it is able to take up the multiple calls, if instances, or it is asynchronous, or everything in nature.
Mayank: Those all things are exactly the same.
Mayank: So, if your normal server… like, the way we define and do that in normal server, that is there, exactly the same architecture.
Mayank: MCP is just the protocol around that, so nothing in your basic creation of HLD or overall your server changes, okay? So if it is an asynchronous concurrent, it can take the concurrent call, it will be able to do that as well. Okay? It is just the protocol.
Mayank: A progress program, I will explain you, that is in the part, so don't worry on that. First.
Mayank: Everyone, I hope you're clear till now. Can we move on to creating a resource?
Mayank: Can we move on to creating a resource?
Mayank: So, till now, we have made sure that we have created a MCP server right in front of you.
Mayank: I've shown you that how it works by showcasing it here.
Mayank: And yeah, I think now we are getting a server as well.
Mayank: In MCP server, it is showing progress token. Ha, that I will explain, don't worry. Basically, it is pretty simple, but yeah, we will cover that. How come JSON REPC come from getRecipe?
Mayank: This you are saying?
Mayank: HQ?
Mayank: How Vikram this is coming?
Mayank: Thisithaya, last four classes, that how JSON RPCs, how they communicate.
Mayank: How does MCP communicate, everyone? Palla, what is the language?
Mayank: Which they understand and communicate with each other.
Mayank: Just on RPC 2.0.
Mayank: Pallop.
Mayank: That is what IBM learned, right?
Mayank: What is the protocol here, everyone? Sorry, what is the transport layer here?
Mayank: So they are speaking JSON RPC, and they are speaking and connecting it with STDIO.
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: Do we have resources here?
Mayank: No? Do we have any prompts here?
Mayank: Do we have any prompts here?
Mayank: No, not yet. How many tools we have?
Mayank: How many tools we have?
Mayank: 3?
Mayank: Okay?
Mayank: Hi, Abhin Hardik. I have just created a dictionary. Let me ask you the other things. Do you understand each and every step in this process, everyone? Are you understanding each and every step in this process?
Mayank: Each and every step.
Mayank: Are you having the confidence? Can you explain it to an interviewer?
Mayank: If he asks you to explain these steps, Everyone?
Mayank: Confidently, you can explain the same?
Mayank: Do you have to change anything in here?
Mayank: Do you have to change anything in here for the steps?
Mayank: Well, the MCP handled this, right? MCP handled this. Which LLM is being used? No LLM is used here as of now.
Mayank: No LLM is being used here as of now.
Mayank: Everyone, add… so, tell me one thing.
Mayank: Where I'm hitting the guest recipes, am I entering it manually, or Claude or ChatGPT is entering it for me?
Mayank: There is no, right? We are handling manually.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: Are we renting manually?
Mayank: Let's move forward. If this is done, everyone.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: What is Client and server in your fast MCP, please? Client is this… MCP inspector?
Mayank: Server is our one which we start here, so when we start the server, everyone, it starts on my local up. So that is what the server is.
Mayank: Okay, and in here, server gets started as a sub-process of my client, because they are in SDIO.
Mayank: I hope that is clear.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: Make sense?
Mayank: So, let's try to quickly do two things. Define a resource, prompts then you can do, and connect it to my Cloud desktop.
Mayank: I hope that makes sense, everyone.
Mayank: Can we do these two things quickly?
Mayank: Then, tomorrow, we will be creating a good project on MCP, and I will maybe show you how to make it live, and how you can share it with each other.
Mayank: And how to make it on any cloud as well. It's all that we will also do.
Mayank: Okay? Secret keychain? Keychain… Secrets, OS, keychain developer, something for authorization, nothing else.
Mayank: Yeah, please try to just take the screenshot and ask it. It is just some authorization token and everything, okay? Nothing else, okay?
Mayank: Pallop, you can go to the bottom, it should be fine. Great.
Mayank: So now, everyone, let's try to add the resources as well. Again, it is pretty simple in the case. What we have to do is…
Mayank: We just have to now define that it is going to be an MCP… One minute.
Mayank: MCP dot is source.
Mayank: And I will just make sure that I am adding recipe?
Mayank: tags. Okay, so I'm just making sure that this is the resource.
Mayank: Then I can say define valid tags.
Mayank: I'm going to return a list of strings.
Mayank: And I'm returning this. Now, since I've added a resource, everyone.
Mayank: Let me try to see if it gets refreshed itself. So, let me just do this thing. Connect this.
Mayank: Do we have resources? Yes. So, seems like we don't need to refresh our servers, everyone.
Mayank: It is actually able to, like FastAPI, it is able to take up our changes.
Mayank: And, yes, now it is able to easily just tell me that, hey man, you are having a resource as well.
Mayank: And these are the valid resources, which we are able to see. So, it is generally that simple, where you just define a resource. And now, of course, you can define a prompt as well, everyone. So, for the prompt, what I will do, pay attention.
Mayank: I will just now define at the rate MCP.prompt.
Mayank: And you can just define let's see… plan.
Mayank: weekly… Meals?
Mayank: And, yes, now you have the prompt as well. So, very, very simply, of course, you can add these primitives.
Mayank: Again, what I will do, let me go here. So, I will have to disconnect and connect it safe again.
Mayank: So, since I've added the prompt just now, everyone, and my server is running.
Mayank: I have to disconnect to my server and connect it again. So that server, when it restarts now, it will be able to tell that, hey, I'm having the prompt as well.
Mayank: Fast MCP doesn't require you to restart, like, restart and kill it here, so pay attention. Closing it up.
Mayank: And based opening it up.
Mayank: And now I think all of you are very smart that you can open and see the same, right? See how it is giving me the prompt here?
Mayank: So… Similarly, if you see the resource, everyone, Resorts… Tools resource list, see?
Mayank: How it is telling that, hey.
Mayank: I'm having the complete URI of recipe tags. This is just used as a… identifier, okay, recipe slash…
Mayank: tags, because my AI will be much… be more better to do that, okay?
Mayank: And then it is giving me that I am having the valid tags as a resource, and see?
Mayank: I'm having to prompt everyone.
Mayank: I'm having the resource, so that now, when I will ask my Claude or ChatGPT that, hey, can you
Mayank: Oh.
Mayank: Tell me what are the…
Mayank: tags or anything, it will be able to get the CMI resources. So, yeah, we are now having all these things, everyone. See?
Mayank: All the tools, everything.
Mayank: I think all of you now understand the source read, prompt, get.
Mayank: All of these things will now be connected to our basic understanding, because generally, all of these things are something which we have mastered and learned as well. Capability table, what all happened, error codes, what are the error codes, transport, how it happens.
Mayank: reading the local servers, HTTP-based servers.
Mayank: And this, I think, we will have to check still. But yes, all of these things are something which we have seen, everyone, and now we are able to see the same
Mayank: not just in something which Mayank was giving, like MCP,
Mayank: JAM or any other application, but via the vanilla MCP inspector, which is a part of your Anthropic MCP, as well as Fast MCP as well. So this MCP inspector, everyone, this is from the official MCP
Mayank: library. Okay, I've not created it.
Mayank: And it is also following the same approach which I've told you, so this helps you now to understand that how, yes, actually it is able to have each and everything properly in here. Now, in the next part, everyone, we will
Mayank: try to make our server useful, because if you think about this, as of now, you will feel that you are just kind of going around the same things. Well, yes, but the same is required, so your understanding becomes
Mayank: 110% clear.
Mayank: Now, what we will do, everyone, like, the command is pretty simple to run this, but what I will show you in the next part is that how, by running a single command.
Mayank: Which is your UV Run Fast MCP.
Mayank: installed.
Mayank: Claude Desktop.
Mayank: And I will just do recipe box.
Mayank: fast MCP. So this command, and don't worry, I will be sharing it with you, so we will just make sure that by running this command.
Mayank: it will install my recipe box in my cloud desktop, so that
Mayank: the claw text on which I'm running everyone.
Mayank: If I go in here, so lots of things we are having running.
Mayank: And if I go on connectors.
Mayank: I think I will have to restart the same, but still, let me search it.
Mayank: Okay, I will have to restart it, but don't worry, I will showcase the same to you.
Mayank: this MCP server, the One which I ran, which I… Created, everyone.
Mayank: I am able to now easily just also add it into my Cloud desktop, just thus making it directly useful. So, what we will do, everyone, in the next part now, we will create a little bit advanced, kind of a project, so moving step by step.
Mayank: Via which we will see that how, for our
Mayank: applications which are having a DB, how can we use Cloud Desktop or any AI now to work with that, thanks to MCP, which was not possible earlier, so that will be our very, first kind of a minor project. Then, if required, and we will try to do it either
Mayank: via plain vanilla, or maybe via Langchain easily. Then how can we create a little bit of advanced project as well, where we will create our own agent, and with that, we will be able to either search jobs or other things by connecting
Mayank: other state-of-the-art MCP servers, be it for Nokri, LinkedIn, or whatever is provided, so that we are able to use our application with AI a lot better.
Mayank: So I hope this thing is clear, everyone now.
Mayank: how I'm giving the code and everything, don't worry. Each and everything I'm giving, but first, understanding-wise, is it clear, everyone, or not?
Mayank: Well, now I think each and everything which I showed you, Giha, how this happens, you are able to make sense of this.
Mayank: each and everything, because now it is connected to the real server and everything, okay? Acha, one more thing, everyone. This is all which is required for interview level, because Japay, if you can see.
Mayank: 90… 7-8% of people, believe me, are not able to explain me what this is.
Mayank: Which I've closed this. Mallab… MCP…
Mayank: Creation is very simple, MCP. This is how you create an MCP server, okay?
Mayank: But what happens in the backend? Now you're aware of the same.
Mayank: Clear, everyone?
Mayank: I hope the same is clear. I'm giving you the code, I'm giving you everything.
Mayank: Just one request.
Mayank: And also I might extend tomorrow's class by 4 hours, by 4 hours, because tomorrow I plan to do a little bit of major project, but I just also want to move away from these basic things, Matap.
Mayank: By now, two things must have happened. You would be like, Mayank, I know all these things now, let's do a little bit practical thing, which I will do. And even I am confused, right? Sorry, I am also kind of very poor, because I don't know all these things, you know? So, revise the classes, do the code, see each and everything, and then we will focus and master the same.
Mayank: Cool.
Mayank: Quickly, tell me, everyone, if the first MCP server file you were able to see or not.
Mayank: Quickly tell me in on GitHub.
Mayank: Are you able to see the folder?
Mayank: Vasudevae can also check notes.
Mayank: Great, what is the next concept after MCP, Langchain? MCP with Langchain, Langchain, multi-agents, and then a project?
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Cool?
Mayank: Ma'am, please help with some of the actual examples. To Work Kulk Raghana, we will be creating a application, Japay, there will be a DB as well, and then we will seek how it is useful.
Mayank: Clear, everyone. Tomorrow, what if you can push? Let me try to push it today, but I try to code and everything, Tyga?
Mayank: Cool. How was the explanation and everything, everyone?
Mayank: When is RAG? Time again, RAG, maybe, at least one minute and a half month.
Mayank: Any plan of Langgraph as well, huh? Langgraph, you will be mastering as well, everyone, don't worry.
Mayank: Don't worry, time those Purushamaz. Just give me a little bit of time.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Ha, let me fix that up, should not be a problem. Can we have different defined prompts with different tags with respect to each tool, which will help LLM with grounded response, right? Please confirm, Mayank. Different defined prompts with different tags with respect to each tool.
Mayank: how we can connect the same. You can just define the tags and everything, and it will be able to use it up. Plus, LLMs are now a lot
Mayank: smart overall, so they will be able to connect the same and everything. Hi, I'm fixing this error, Prakash and everyone, I'm fixing the error, okay? Don't worry. Please update GitHub, it's not been updated since 22-23. It has been updated.
Mayank: Code and everything is there, but let me fix the other thing as well. Thinka?
Mayank: When shall we connect our Langchain agent to our custom MCPs? Next weekend, okay?
Mayank: Chica?
Mayank: Great.
Mayank: Language documentation is in the official one, only everyone is on the official one. Okay? So, cool.
Mayank: Great, great, great, great. With that, I hope everything is clear. Let me just quickly raise… give you the ability to raise hand.
Mayank: But yes, now you have lots of things to master, everyone, because tomorrow's class, most probably it will be a little bit difficult if you have not revised. I'm telling you beforehand. And the reason is very simple. It will be a little bit tactical-based directly. Take care?
Mayank: 8 minute.
Mayank: Yeah. Now you can raise hand if you want.
Mayank: I do this because many people, they raise hands at the starting and feel kani. I just want to give everyone a fair chance.
Mayank: Just give me a second, let me quickly see the doubts.
Mayank: In the chat, and then I will move on to that. In Langchain MCP, where is the server running in their info front report?
Mayank: malik Either it will be a local server, or it will be a HTTP server.
Mayank: When is the course ended? Abhinavi, I don't know, we are teaching. We generally, I don't know. It will be somewhere in January or February, everyone, okay?
Mayank: Any update on Cloud Uday Code Coupon tomorrow?
Mayank: I tried to create it today, I'm catching some errors, I will try to create it tomorrow.
Mayank: Yes, so everyone, the class is done. If you want to drop off, if you don't have any doubts, you can drop off. I'm just clearing the doubts. That said, I will be uploading just after the class, each and everything, for sure today.
Mayank: And the…
Mayank: complete transcript and everything. I have asked a person to check the same as well, because someone was saying that there is a little mismatch.
Mayank: But yeah, you will get all the resources. Tomorrow, code I will also try to push if I can, but yes, tomorrow code is going to… tomorrow we will be doing the complete practical in-depth.
Mayank: Sure, look, great, great. Transcript of 6th September class was left. Take care.
Mayank: I'm unmuting you. Today class is over. How did you build such level of patience?
Mayank: malab, these things I know for so many times, but I'm teaching you in depth.
Mayank: you will not be able to revise it. Show that, how you connected the CMM CP2 clot also. A kapil, I think.
Mayank: You are not paying her attention. We will be connecting that in tomorrow's classes.
Mayank: Venkat, for this, you will have to mail, reach out to me.
Mayank: Code by code by including the file, but you're leveraging existing code. Expecting code step by step by scratch, including the file creation. Murthy, again, they could revise, I cannot think he is me…
Mayank: I'm not using any pre-built code, Matlap. I'm genuinely just writing the code in front of you. If you want, kya write it like this, so I will be really honest, don't do this in today's world. AIC space me, you don't need to do that.
Mayank: I am… generally, I think I cannot be slower than that in code writing. I'm creating the file right in front of you, I'm doing everything, though I'm not sure that what do you mean by step-by-step, by scratch, including the file creation? I am not leveraging the existing code. Generally, I'm not leveraging it.
Mayank: Challow, great, great, great, great, great.
Mayank: Kula. Teja.
Mayank: Give me the email address, everyone. No, let me unmute people one by one. Krishna?
Mayank: dipika?
Mayank: and Rashim?
Mayank: and Harshit. So you, in the same case, you can go.
dipika vijapur: Hi, my uncle.
Mayank: Guys, you can unmute yourself. Krishna.
Mayank: dipika?
dipika vijapur: Hello?
Mayank: Nope.
Mayank: Speaker… okay, wait a minute, it's Mayank, it's my end, it's mine.
Mayank: Sorry, totally on me. So, the speaker is same as my mic, as it's like I said.
Mayank: One minute.
Mayank: Sure, yeah. Can you try to say now anything, Krishna?
Mayank: Krishna, Deepika, anyone, can you try to say something now?
dipika vijapur: Yeah, hi Mike, am I audible?
Mayank: Here's the PR, you're audible, thank you.
dipika vijapur: Good morning, Mayank. Mayank, really very nice class. First thing is, I would like to say gratitude to you, and I just want to understand where exactly do I need to look for notes, because, like this MCP thing, I missed the class. I was trying to look for notes along with that. So, is it the GitHub, or it's the Kraft?
dipika vijapur: So, can you just tell me where I need to look? I'm getting a little confused where I need to go.
Mayank: And that is going to be true for everyone, and I will make it fixed.
Mayank: Today as well. So, all the codes and everything which I write, the bigger files and everything, those will be present in
Mayank: GitHub, okay?
Mayank: Everything related to all the codes.
Mayank: this, what I'm coding, those all will be present on GitHub.
Mayank: But any link which I share during teaching, anything which I'm sharing while I feel that, okay, well, I'm teaching the same, that will be there on the craft. Because that is a little difficult to mention here.
Mayank: So, in that case, I'm trying to make sure that your GitHub is having each and everything, so if you go on GitHub.
dipika vijapur: Going down?
dipika vijapur: example that you gave us, like that MCP thing and all, right? So, the URLs which you shared today.
Mayank: Yes, that.
dipika vijapur: I mean?
dipika vijapur: Yeah, yeah, so these ones, yeah, other ones. So where I can get all these details, Mayank?
Mayank: So, again, I will tell you how I try to create the notes, so that will be very clear. See, you have this craft link, okay?
Mayank: Do you have this craft link?
Mayank: Where, while I'm teaching, I try to add all the
Mayank: links and everything. Just as an example.
Mayank: Last class, when I was using this artifact, this one.
Mayank: I shared the code in here, so MCP, all the things are present in here. MCP lifecycle, stimulator, MCP lifecycle.
Mayank: Project AI newsletter, if I have to give any prompt. See? The prompts are present here.
Mayank: Because these are a little difficult to share on GitHub, that is why I share it here.
Mayank: Then all the documents of this, all the excalator diagrams and everything which I create.
Mayank: Now, what I do is…
Mayank: Same thing I try to make available on GitHub as well, but GitHub is a little bit more structured, and it is having other things as well, along with your assignments and everything, because all these things are really difficult.
Mayank: So, what I will suggest is that while you are watching the recording, or otherwise, just go to craft link to understand if there was a link, and just copy that, any prompt or link. Otherwise, just git pull on the GitHub, and you will get all the things there.
Mayank: So that I will, add for the last weekend as well. So after 20 to 23,
Mayank: 2930, I think we did not have the classes, if I remember it right. 5th, 6th, I will also add, although the codes are added, but I will add it like this weekend as well.
Mayank: Pick?
dipika vijapur: Yeah, yeah, thank you, thank you, Maya.
Mayank: That is how you have to follow it.
dipika vijapur: Yeah.
Mayank: I will have to follow it so that you can revise it. Plus, I will make it a little bit… as of now, also, it is a little bit very much in-depth, rather, to be very honest. But I will… I've asked someone to fix it and help me fix it, like, someone was saying that they are a little bit decent, but I will do that as well.
dipika vijapur: I'm feeling a little lost in this.
dipika vijapur: Kahajana nodes klei, craft klei.
Mayank: Nih malik Jati ha meibole shivi fixed kar detraft kalingiapi hain.
Mayank: But let me make it a little bit easier. Abhi kalyan, when you focus on a class, is it helpful, here's a note summary.
dipika vijapur: Yes, yes, very much, yeah. Actually, that's how, at the last moment, we can revise before the class, right?
Mayank: Okay, let me make it a little bit better by… after tomorrow's class, or Matrav, the person I've asked, I think he will be available tonight, so let me ask him, and I will make it a little bit better, and all the links and everything, I will try to make it, but just to answer your question, Palaicraft, then get up.
dipika vijapur: Thank you so much. Have a good day. Thank you.
Mayank: We'll add all the diagrams of Excalibur as well, from Craft to the Git, to Git as well.
dipika vijapur: Yeah, so all this local URL also you're going to be adding in the craft, because I.
Mayank: Local URL doesn't make sense, Kyoki, you cannot ex… you cannot ex- access it, right?
dipika vijapur: Correct, but we'll have an idea, like, what the URL might look like, right?
Mayank: That I will have to add in craft, actually, but I'm not in GitHub.
dipika vijapur: Please, for the reference part, like, what we can check in the… so how we can… we can use our phone number and others.
Mayank: Pallop, if you see this thing I've added, I think I have to refresh it.
Mayank: This is added in the last…
dipika vijapur: Yes.
Mayank: Okay.
dipika vijapur: Okay, thank you.
Mayank: One thing which I will genuinely ask all of you for help, if anything is there which you want me just
Mayank: when you are asking the same, just remind me that Mayank has added to Craft as well, because that will be helpful for people who see the recording as well, because generally, as a mentor, I forget many times, like, it is a little bit difficult.
Mayank: So that is the case, okay?
dipika vijapur: Yeah, sure. Thank you, Mayank.
Mayank: Thanks. Krishna Rashim Harshit?
krishnakumar: Yeah, hi, Mank. Good afternoon. Like, while I'm trying to clone the.
Mayank: There is some error, let me fix it. I think Windows people are facing some error, let me fix it.
Mayank: That, I think, in Windows. So, again, that is a little bit issue sometimes which happens of the way the characters are there in Mac versus…
Mayank: your Windows.
krishnakumar: Yeah, why MCP had to exist, that problem, that is the problem.
Mayank: Let me fix it, let me fix it.
Mayank: I think, I understand that invalid path will apply that is the case. Let me fix it, okay?
krishnakumar: Okay.
Mayank: should be fine. Pallab, I mistakenly added that very wrong type of an approach in GitHub.
Mayank: kind of got lost in this, but okay, let me fix it in a bit, and it will be done.
krishnakumar: Sure. So, Raman, one more question. In my organization and a client, now they are using Cloudflare, so any, any idea on, like, how, what, what is it? It's called, like.
Mayank: Cloudflare is used majorly for traffic handling and everything, so if you…
Mayank: Well, cool. Like, just normally read about it the same as ChatGPT and anything, it's pretty easy, like, in here.
Mayank: I think this runs around 20% of the internet, yeah, it is mentioned.
Mayank: So, Cloudflare is kind of… The bridge between anything which is getting connected.
Mayank: 45% of the Fortune 500 companies. It is a little bit on the networking side, like, the infrared, everything of this is a little bit on the networking side.
Mayank: Okay. So any requests which you sell, that can go via Cloudflare, and it can make sure that any invalid, dangerous, all those requests, it can
Mayank: figure out and clear before it becomes a problem. So, that is where, actually, it is not a… like, now they have made it Agentic and everything, but now every company's making it AI and everything, but honestly, it is not the case.
Mayank: You have to just focus on it like a network architecture level, try to understand it.
krishnakumar: Okay. Okay, man, thank you.
Mayank: So, many companies, like, as it is mentioned, 45% of the cloud Fortune 500 companies using Cloudflare.
Mayank: It's pretty awesome technology, but I've just tried to read about it. It helps you in saving any…
Mayank: Concerns, any, errors, multiple, and then any attacks as well.
Mayank: So it can make sure that if you have connected your request to route via Cloudflare, it will be handling all of that very nicely.
krishnakumar: Okay.
Mayank: Ping up?
krishnakumar: Thank you.
Rashim: Hi, Mayank, good morning.
Mayank: Irishing, yes.
Rashim: Mayank, last week I tried to connect, Cloud desktop to, Outlook, and I'm able to, get the summary of my mails, so your last class helped, actually. Apart from it, Mayank,
Rashim: this STDIO, the way it works is, only the… it will connect on the same machine. Now, outside the machine, it will not work, right? The SDDIO.
Mayank: STDIO, malab, again, if you're not proxying it, ideally STDIO kind of runs like that.
Rashim: Yes, yes, yes, okay.
Mayank: Okay, something starts off as a subprocess, they both can access their input and output. Those cases, Abhsi, we are able to use it.
Rashim: Okay, so Mehank Abhi, right now, we have made MCP, and we have tested with some sort of a, like, a simulator key, how to get those, those things, like, how to get the tool list and all.
Rashim: When we, have… when we connect that, connector or MCP server with the cloud, it will, further, automatically, based… based on our input on the cloud, it will connect… connect that and get the output.
Mayank: Yes, we will see that tomorrow.
Rashim: Okay, okay, and finally, our agent that you have made with Lanjain, it will connect to that MCP and get the tooling for.
Mayank: So, ideally, my plan there is that we will be creating a MCP server.
Rashim: Right.
Mayank: I will try to make it live on the internet, Bhlab, so that anyone can access it.
Mayank: Usme told us I will have to take extra time, because Usme, we have to define… I have to tell you how to make it live via other things, but yes, once we make it live over there, then we can run it inside your
Mayank: Langchain as well, that would be the idea.
Rashim: My very last two small questions.
Rashim: what I'm visualizing, like, if I, if I want to connect, my agent to MCP and then MCP to database, like, I have, tables, let's say tables have some profile data, some transaction data, some content data. So for…
Rashim: every read operation, I need to make a tool in that, and that, that my LLM will decide key, based on my prompt, which is the best tool to call. As a workout, finally, e-visualization.
Mayank: Exactly.
Rashim: Okay. And when kalki class jo practical karang Yuske liye kya Padna important hai, because I have a revised yesterday.
Mayank: devices.
Mayank: And just make sure key.
Mayank: code NP what I've gained, because tomorrow we will be writing majorly the code part only, because, theory, I think I've covered everything, just the…
Mayank: new modern VLA architecture is a little bit left.
Mayank: But first, I want to do a practical with all of you. Those may… I don't think… if you devise the thing, that it will be more than clear.
Rashim: Parm mein kyo MCP JME wo server b… server Bharse lek Klaodka Agent ak karne kiosk.
Mayank: in the MCP jam.
Rashim: I'm sorry, messy mistake, ogi, my understanding kart.
Mayank: in the MCP Jaum kuch nih, Vaik application niran inspected to have multiple clients just say ak PC mein autha hai, jo akke PC may install authenta Cloud ChatGPT.
Mayank: use karta hai. mehdi kahi to aka.
Mayank: khair.
Mayank: ha cursa.
Mayank: Ap or kiad karakhair.
Mayank: Okay. Toh ika karta hai, ye unko use k ki, basically same cheese kart ja example kil GPT ha. It is a host.
Mayank: Abhi MCP aka johi Client ye connection dhiche hor y ana.
Mayank: normally HC is available niyuti.
Rashim: Right, please.
Mayank: kleiyhi.
Mayank: where exactly this is coming, I think Charity Bridge Al Rahmana.
Mayank: One minute. Toho backend may use ChatGPT who use Karaha hai.
Mayank: And it is…
Mayank: adding all these things and everything. You can see me, an understanding of concepto. I think plot is a lot better in this.
Rashim: Destok kan.
Mayank: Madhlah BUS tarike seh MCP… MCP champasekh beach manager, Rahuski dar hai.
Rashim: Okay.
Mayank: mehij me aka passi aapko logs already sahikauma.
Mayank: I will route it properly.
Mayank: understanding kim important. I found this tool, and I loved it, so I shared it with all of you. Honestly, to be honest, I have created a way through which, whether it was running on me, on the backend.
Mayank: It's a little tricky, so I will share the steps with all of you. This is from Claude's side.
Mayank: I've done the same.
Mayank: Now this is actually real logs. So you told us a lambagi meska. For example, if I clear it out, now the logs are clear.
Mayank: Vaishnape.
Mayank: If I will close plot, right?
Mayank: Todd de chope.
Mayank: Let me hide it.
Mayank: You… It… I will show you this tomorrow, mothlav SAI. This is a shutdown, which was sent.
Mayank: The second I open Cloud again, pay attention on this.
Mayank: Jop it.
Mayank: real-time Vora initialize.
Mayank: then initialized, over those servers initialize Krandheh Take a local agent, Claudi.
Mayank: Server Client Pura kapur real life, maybe the Karo app. I will showcase this tomorrow, maybe. Manh GB kuldehi figure out, ki how we have to work it out.
Mayank: Real-time blocks.
Mayank: Thank you.
Rashim: And your tools ka list hai, I'm able to see in Klaude in the connector section. But yeah, resource ka tag ka use… well, resource tags ka ka use who usually.
Mayank: JAHA primitives mein Yusuf.
Rashim: Quickly.
Mayank: Major Leap 2Z Yuskartem, so that is the case.
Rashim: Visual tools used quickly.
Mayank: That should be very helpful.
Rashim: That's what I asked.
Mayank: Nemo, normally, because we don't use prompts and resources that much, so Smeh, what we will do is, tomorrow when we will ask it, it will be able to get the same, because they are supplementary thing.
Rashim: Subway.
Mayank: prompt is something which is given malabhaka.
Mayank: So, prompt eki ha ga rifil ask it that, hey, plan me the weekly meal kalika, rather than writing it itself.
Rashim: Okay.
Mayank: toward us a…
Mayank: Okay.
Rashim: Thank you, Ming. Thanks a lot.
Mayank: Harshit?
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, hieng. Meng, couple of things. Ekto Juye Araratina Arj,
Mayank: Get me correct?
Harshit Goyal: Ankit Mehrah.
Mayank: Abhi.
Harshit Goyal: Same error na. Same error akke wo 14 hours walajkur sa na. Yusu me jo aka Yusu bhai, same error.
Mayank: Thanks a lot for today.
Harshit Goyal: Well, who knows?
Mayank: Capital.
Mayank: Thanks a lot, Vikkanido.
Harshit Goyal: Mayank, there's another question I want to ask, like, hey,
Harshit Goyal: For the MCP, right? And on the… in the organization, Jaum custom MCP bename kuch, example dip boga malik custom MCP malap kuch, real-time example.
Mayank: Majorly chauh meias kasi bantaya. Amapas ek system motha jiska already amarpas.
Ankit Singh: get my butt.
Mayank: APIs with you.
Mayank: But, MCP venata. Let me think on this, let me think on this.
Mayank: Nikit let me try to make a project, just maybe are having maybe a front-end or something, Arjun, and in there, we can show you the… just to show you, tell you an example, let's say that Abhih akke pasik… acha mehi meh ke examples. Let me show you the example. Very good example. One minute.
Harshit Goyal: Basically, I'm not able to relate that real time, man, because, you know.
Harshit Goyal: But your organization rah koi, like, aka Purak AI kap platform Manage kar rah, and they give us the endpoint where we use those universities.
Mayank: Because we are creating an MCP there, let me showcase that.
Mayank: ganheta aka.
Mayank: So, Srini.
Mayank: kan kele kari US-based.
Mayank: Everyone else's will you can understand it.
Harshit Goyal: Mhmh.
Mayank: So, Jaise ye humne ech system raha hai Client dia, b… all of this is based on APIs and everything. Thinkya.
Mayank: Yeah, Pura aka pura ye ak meh mei system na hai, Jayapam jake, Client customers reach out karte, lead management kind of thing hai.
Mayank: Bharthy abhinavi ape puri puri tables gigi leads ka hai sara.
Mayank: Teja?
Mayank: Complete leads Karita list meh akaarhi hai.
Mayank: Abhi sap to amar a API se power, right? All this is getting powered by APIs. Make sense?
Mayank: Now, I can show the same in APIs properly, I can see the analytics and everything in APIs, right?
Mayank: All these things are there where you can change this SMS template and everything.
Mayank: Synthesis is getting loaded, one minute.
Mayank: Yeah, so I can share this template and everything, right?
Mayank: All of this is APA?
Mayank: But now, of course, you will have to understand the API and everything. If you will change it, it will be hitting the call and all these things.
Mayank: I have now asked my team to add an agent here. I've generally asked my team to add an agent here.
Mayank: Now, once that agent will be added, okay.
Mayank: Rather than me teaching my agent, this is the API, or adding it separately, what I will do is, for all my MCPIs, I will create a MCP server.
Mayank: And then, for example, I will ask my agent that, hey, can you tell me the analytics for today?
Mayank: it will try to understand ka, I have this tool in MCP.
Harshit Goyal: Mhmh.
Mayank: It requires these, these arguments. It will fill this up itself, and then it will try to give me the answer.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: So, in a much better sense, in a lot, lot, lot better sense, my AI or agent can give me the answer by connecting via an MCP server, which is kind of in between the… all the APIs between them. So, for example.
Mayank: I could ask, can you tell me about this lead, Rudh Mehta?
Mayank: And it will try to get all the information about the lead here.
Mayank: Key, complete, complete information about the details we tried to get in here. Key, what was the recent activity.
Mayank: But agent or AI can do all of that in real time because of MCP, because I will create the tool, so I can create get lead info.
Mayank: as one of the tools, and that tool will have… just ask for the name of the patient, and when I get the name, it will receive all these things, and then I can just make it a lot better, like an AI does, right? So that is where a real-time, real-world thing is used. So if you have to give any AI or agent access to your
Mayank: overall machine, where multiple tools and everything is there, which are getting changed. MCP Server is a pretty good approach of that.
Mayank: Chatboard, or anything?
Harshit Goyal: What you're saying that, let's say, you need to do analytics, or maybe any, anything on a.
Mayank: Anything…
Harshit Goyal: lead… lead. It will be creating a MCP server, and behind that, within the MCP server, there are this, there's a tool, cat lead details, and that lead details does the API call to the
Harshit Goyal: pool system, and then return it back to the…
Mayank: Right?
Mayank: How it is doing it. I don't care if that system is doing an API call or something.
Mayank: My work is just in the… till the… MCP1.
Mayank: the tool called. I don't care how the system is.
Harshit Goyal: MCP mein tool to define karang y usmeh thom me API k kalyan?
Mayank: It is not a… it is not a… it is not a…
Mayank: direct Singham. It can be in other cases as well.
Mayank: Ideally.
Harshit Goyal: Okay, is case, use case meh?
Mayank: API call you, okay. But it can be combination of API call as well, not just a simple call. Sure, it will not be an API call, it can be combination of multiple APIs as well.
Mayank: So, Muralho, I will be just focusing on that action. So, just in a similar manner, example k here, Gmail mega everything is present.
Harshit Goyal: Hmm?
Mayank: I could just make a Gmail MCP server connected to my cloud and tell that, hey, send an email to this, and the email will be sent. So that is how it can be done.
Mayank: Yep.
Harshit Goyal: Got it, got it. I think this is… this really helps to understand how, in an enterprise, this MCP server works, because, yeah, I mean.
Harshit Goyal: as you explained, like, kay API says Sara chal rahul API ko agent pel kani kleiya, meh MCP server bena ke dengane, toh usuy mara pura.
Mayank: It is much better, that is what I started as well, Key, how it'll be much better if we do the same.
Mayank: So yeah.
Mayank: That is the idea, kyoki MCP server, then you will be maintaining, so tomorrow, if I change anything.
Mayank: For example, tomorrow I'm changing multiple APIs, I'm adding new APIs, whatever.
Mayank: I don't have to give it to my agent separately. GiveHI change this API, I change this new API.
Harshit Goyal: Haha, right.
Mayank: MCP server, happy everything is present, just connect and get everything.
Harshit Goyal: Yeah, I think, good, good, thanks, thanks, Ming, just to give you an understanding.
Mayank: On the BDC in your project.
Harshit Goyal: Chaudh, Chaudhi wa la pix kartanya toust.
Mayank: Neeny, Neeni, extremely sorry. Can you just ping me the error if you have it handy?
Harshit Goyal: Let me reproduce that, and then.
Mayank: I'll just, if you can help, like, strange, no one told me the commits as well, but thanks a lot, thanks a lot for this.
Harshit Goyal: Sure. Thank you. Thank you, Meh.
Mayank: Goshua.
Mayank: Great. Vasudev? Ankit Abhinash?
Vasudev N: Hi, Menka, good morning.
Mayank: Good morning.
Vasudev N: My, my couple of questions here are related to STDIO and, this, streammable HTTP. So, when exactly these, two we use, like, the server…
Mayank: We are not using it, we define a server. So, when we are defining a server.
Mayank: That is where we define what kind of a server it is. Is it a STDIO server, or is it a HTTP-based server?
Vasudev N: And what is the benefit? Let's say now you… the latest server which you are creating now, as you have shown the practical, we are using SDDIU.
Mayank: Yes.
Vasudev N: Okay? What if I… if we use, streamability? Because that's just a post-call. I don't think.
Mayank: And then I will have to host it. Then I will have to host it. There will be a proper network calls coming in question.
Mayank: They will be connecting via different HTTP-based thing. So it is not about a choice, it is based on the architecture. For example.
Mayank: Gmail server, I cannot have it on my local, right?
Mayank: If there is a Gmail server, For example.
Mayank: it will be making an API calls. This file system and everything, it is present on my local only.
Mayank: Correct. Plus, many times it happens that for the initial kind of a… approach.
Mayank: We are having the local server, like, we can have servers starting up on our local.
Mayank: And then they can hit any other APIs or everything, so it is not based on…
Mayank: A brain on any choice.
Mayank: It is based on what you are trying to achieve. That is what it is being made,
Mayank: Based on.
Vasudev N: Because the Excel draw, which you have seen, which you have shown the practical, I have also seen, it is by default, calling this, streamable HTTP.
Mayank: Yes, because it is a type of that sermon.
Vasudev N: Okay.
Mayank: It is not calling it by default. The server has been defined as T-Mobile HTTP.
Vasudev N: Mhmh.
Mayank: As a very simple example, I will explain to you, if you have to create a server which gets you anything on your machine.
Mayank: Time, file system, right?
Mayank: those can be STDIO servers directly, right?
Vasudev N: Okay.
Mayank: But, now, take the same scenario that you, just as example I'm taking, just go to Claude, and if I ask Claude here.
Mayank: That, hey, can you tell me, about…
Mayank: Yeah. In here, if I ask, can you tell me what is there in my complete MCP folder? On the web, do you think plot will be able to get that information?
Vasudev N: Well, yep.
Mayank: No, right? No, it cannot, because it is on the web, let me tell you.
Mayank: Can you tell me what is inside?
Mayank: My… complete MCP folder.
Mayank: Yo, please cut up.
Mayank: Yeah. So there we go. This is running on the cloud servers. It can, of course, not expect, access my complete MCP folder. So yeah, I will have to make this HTTP-based.
Mayank: Right? But for anything which is present on its own server, it can just check the same.
Mayank: So that is a little bit how it works. It is based on the type of server and what it's trying to do. I mean, it has gone to actually the
Mayank: drive and everything, but of course, because it is not having the access. So, Jayapay, if I want to give it the access, it will be an HTTP-based server, because my machine and cloud are not directly connected that way, right?
Vasudev N: booking.
Vasudev N: So that…
Mayank: It is kind of based on the server and the kind of what it is kind of.
Vasudev N: Yeah, so for us, it's enough to understand the architecture and these server types, and we should have the knowledge what exactly the standard I.O. and stable HTTP, but when we are connecting to the external MCPs, we don't need to bother on the test.
Mayank: You don't need to bother there, you don't need to bother there.
Vasudev N: Okay, okay.
Mayank: Okay, and just one more thing to add, like, based on your, understanding, just a simple thing, because many people confuse this up.
Mayank: up…
Mayank: even though my server here, which I have created this one, right? This one is a local HTTIO server, I can make HTTP calls inside it, like this plan weekly meals.
Mayank: I could make it send email, and then I can connect to
Mayank: APIs which are present for Gmail and do that. It is still a STDIO-based server, because my server is now just making the call.
Mayank: But server to Client is happening via…
Mayank: SBDIO, and this now is doing… this is doing its work, but I don't care how it is doing the work, I don't care about that in MCP.
Vasudev N: Understood, understood. So it's on base need, like, it's on our need, actually, how we can.
Mayank: Kind of, yes, it is based on our need. Okay.
Vasudev N: Okay.
Mayank: How it is doable and everything.
Vasudev N: Hmm.
Mayank: And what all we can quickly run, and what are the kind of things which we are trying to do with it. So it is kind of based on that. Okay.
Vasudev N: Good. And the thing, Mayank, the last question. So, tomorrow, the demo which you are going to, the practical demo which you are going to tell us, like, the client and server configuration and all, so, are we deploying this in any Docker container, kind of, or,
Vasudev N: Like, like, because last, like, last,
Mayank: I have these things, but I think it will take time, so I will tell. I will try to either deploy it on Fast MCP Cloud, or BiPi, or Docker, so I will choose one of them, like, I will focus on.
Vasudev N: And at the end, we will have some kind of URL, HTTPS URL, and that we will include in the connectors, cloud connectors, to connect our local server through the cloud, right?
Mayank: Huh, well, that would be the case.
Vasudev N: Yeah.
Mayank: Local servers can be done in a separate manner that I will showcase, but yes, that would be the case.
Vasudev N: Look, yeah.
Mayank: End of the day, I would want that.
Mayank: whatever we have created, how can we have it in a way that it can be used across? That is the final thing, because, yeah, then you can say that, hey, I have created an MCP server, and I know it depth.
Vasudev N: Yeah, we are eagerly waiting for that.
Mayank: Ninibo, I will try to do it in tomorrow's class. Now, theory is done, but theory was very important, because…
Vasudev N: this is…
Mayank: Otherwise, interviews may… they would be just asking theory, first thing. Second thing is that.
Mayank: Then, creating this is easy, like, you can go to ChatGPT or Claude and ask it to create a server like this, and it will give you the code.
Vasudev N: Yeah, yeah.
Mayank: But to understand, like, why it is happening, that is a big thing.
Vasudev N: the last guy, he raised a good, concern on this also, because the… when we work in the enterprise level, because I am also just taking an assignment to work in that way, because I need to create… because, as I said last call also, we are maintaining the complete, microservices concept, Mayank, so I'm trying to deploy this
Vasudev N: for us, for our project, I'm trying to deploy this entire, whatever we have, the APIs, everything, I want to come in together and call, in tools, and create a microservice, which we call as AS MCP server, kind of. And then our microservices, like, we will also deploy an agent, so for that, I'm just eagerly waiting, like, how.
Mayank: Let me try to do one thing. Let me sit today and try to make your project a little bit more advanced in that case. Rather than moving step-by-step in that manner, I will make it a little bit more advanced, having a front end and everything.
Vasudev N: Right.
Mayank: I can showcase Yuki, how they get connected to the same thing.
Vasudev N: Thank you so much, Singh.
Mayank: It would be maybe much, much, much better for.
Vasudev N: Exactly, exactly. Thank you, thank you so much.
Mayank: placements.
Mayank: Ankit?
Mayank: Shivan?
Ankit Singh: I'm angry.
Mayank: I anchor, yes.
Ankit Singh: Mayanka, actually, I have to visualize… I have not able to visualize that MCP inspector, right?
Ankit Singh: So, meh naga hai kapil…
Mayank: If you're able to learn it, you have me Samantha, you're not able to understand it.
Ankit Singh: MCP server jo hablo connect karai MCP inspector pe rate.
Mayank: Hmm.
Ankit Singh: and resources, and and prompt, right? So, majorly, once I go through, like, our organization-level things, right, so I can see, like, aki mahapih, maximum people are making only tools.
Mayank: Right?
Ankit Singh: But resource and…
Ankit Singh: Jo prompt, prompt, which one is my understanding as of now? Prompt, like, suppose we are creating a tool, so most probably we can add some kind of prompts, like, how we can call the tools. So that kind of prompt, you have to. ako better response melega.
Mayank: Mother, they are supplementary and Sudhier things, kind of, which you can also add, yes.
Ankit Singh: Meh ko list mehiya, like a tool list meh, just a tool banana hai, toh, majorly, person is doing, like, creating a tools only, right? They are not focusing on prompt, and they are not focusing on
Ankit Singh: Resources.
Ankit Singh: in, in, in this, in this time industry, right? So, Mehra asked ki hai, ki…
Ankit Singh: there's a prompt to Banayra, like, what is the best approach? Like, anyone going to create a MCP server, as a best approach, as per my understanding, like, agar MCP Cloud Naidu who I have to, something they are think like that, right? They have to add some of the resources and some of the.
Mayank: Yeah, it is not like that. See, the best approach is to make sure that, first, you understand it, so if you will see my primitives, where I explained the primitives and death.
Mayank: You will understand, kHa, why primitives are used. There, I've explained everything, okay? Then you see, kH resource actually helpful? Like, for example, today is when we created this SB server, resource was actually helpful because it gives me the valid tag.
Mayank: Okay?
Ankit Singh: Mhmh, mhmhm.
Mayank: To… That is the case, ki…
Mayank: in your MCP server, you just see kH, and this will not be something which you can take just by default, you will have to actually check key, okay?
Mayank: Is my… am I getting lots of requests where the tag is not right? So then I can add that, and I can mention in my…
Mayank: Tool that, hey, Just get all the right tags from this and everything.
Mayank: So that is something which we can try to kind of do.
Mayank: Okay, so, for example, if you're saying that, hey, my MCP is being used, but I'm getting lots of error because people are sending wrong tags.
Mayank: And that is not there. So should I then cater this horse?
Mayank: Then if you feel that many people are using a similar kind of a request, like, for example.
Mayank: in the MCP server, in our recipe one, that, hey, create a complete, complete
Mayank: Plan for my, weekly meals.
Mayank: Then, should you create a prompt for that so that it can give resources in a much, much better sense?
Mayank: or anything which you want to create. So those are the decisions which help you to take a call if you want to extend or make your MCP or anything better. That is what we will also do.
Ankit Singh: But still, I am not able to connect, JC tools when I have to Jase. First example, I need to connect a GCP
Ankit Singh: accounts, right? So I can create one NSP server based on our SSO, internal SSO. We can create, like, what kind of authentication required. Once user reuse, they can connect and they can debug anything.
Ankit Singh: Through him.
Mayank: Let me… let me explain you what they call.
Ankit Singh: What do you get?
Ankit Singh: resource kahan pe help kar rah.
Mayank: Let me explain you. For example, Abhjaseh yeh aka tools, these are your tools which you have created.
Ankit Singh: Mhmh.
Mayank: Now, let's say when you are getting this search recipe tag, people are sending whatever tags, like, you know that, hey, these are just 5 supported, but they are just sending any tags and anything, yeah?
Ankit Singh: Hmm.
Mayank: No?
Mayank: Your aim as a MCP creator is to make sure my AI can work properly. That's the final aim.
Ankit Singh: mhmhmhmhm.
Mayank: Kara puso kam…
Mayank: Let's say that, hey, today is a holiday, just as an example. Toho tag me holiday kage JADH chanyga, because Sunday is supported, holiday to me is supporteda, right?
Mayank: mein, right?
Mayank: However, those here, there are examples, like, we call vegetarian.
Ankit Singh: Oh.
Mayank: you notice, kibai, I have created tools, and they are getting… lots of my tool calls are failing. Of course, in real world, we will be having a proper…
Mayank: Logging and everything to showcase that, hey, this call failed and everything, right?
Mayank: And you notice, kibai, people are sending Kushpi tag page, rabiho k bhaki, you know, they are sending any tag page they want.
Mayank: So you would say that, okay, let me create a resource.
Mayank: And let me say here, search recipes by a single tag.
Mayank: valid tags, R… Present in recipe.
Mayank: tags. Just as an example, I've done this.
Mayank: Up now, Claude will Loki in one minute. Let me get the valid tags. I know that I can call the resources list.
Mayank: That waste Client and that can complicate.
Mayank: And yeah, then it is all good. Then I can just make sure kiss that he can… now I will not be sending. If I say holiday, it will maybe move to Sunday there.
Mayank: So, in that ways, I'm making my… I'm making or assisting by not failing the calls. That's the whole idea.
Mayank: Similarly, just as a very basic example, resources may have files we're gonna be shared. As a very basic example, if you have a GitHub repo.
Mayank: Okay.
Mayank: me yash Priya.
Mayank: The UDMB file.
Mayank: So that your Claude has an idea, Ketchup what is the project about?
Mayank: Rather than making mindless calls, it is able to actually understand the same first.
Mayank: Same goes with prompts.
Mayank: If there is a request which is coming multiple times, okay?
Mayank: As a very basic example, let's say send an email to the manager. Toh ya ape a much better prompt this akti ho thaki.
Mayank: when the Claude is trying to connect to your MCP and make that request to be Asam Mukhaya hai, so it is able to
Mayank: make a much better call and much better overall thing. So that is the idea.
Ankit Singh: Okay, I got it.
Mayank: Sara kan jo MCP k a hai wo assist kantah hai, hame kisi cheese ko kanteme.
Mayank: better kasi kar sakte, ushisbe prompt resources or prompt help Kante hain. Kyuge tools ai action ok sidah.
Ankit Singh: Yeah, both those direct action, okay?
Mayank: prompt a resources Asa o gai ki achank ko aur better ka se bhai, matlam example k lia hai.
Mayank: Abhar aapkoi isshu bhana kita, pi, right?
Ankit Singh: Abih.
Mayank: Rather than just getting a phased sahoo, right?
Ankit Singh: agar mein agar understanding kar rahu, tohase tool meh create kia, toh, suppose doho ek legal document me verify karna ya a kush bharna.
Mayank: BK.
Ankit Singh: Based on the policy.
Mayank: Right?
Ankit Singh: Toh kyah hoga ki ham Nayak tool create kia, Jase get legal document kool ki ha, that particular person, like, what kind of, mhub that is, premium person, or, like, a regular person, or they have any kind of,
Ankit Singh: Kind of coupons, which is dipika, right?
Mayank: Hmm.
Ankit Singh: Toh kya hua, Jamini tools create kaya, toh agar AI gaya tools create karne pei, toh.
Ankit Singh: they will get, like, they call the MCP server, and they get the legal, related events, yeah, this person are legally authorized for this particular premium-related…
Ankit Singh: activities or something like that, right? But resource mein log ye dal sakte hain, as a resource, like, yeah, these documents, like, these are the.
Mayank: People look.
Ankit Singh: for our premium customers, so that should be validated with this, right? So once we add as part of the resource, so might be once AI call karega, mehi tool malab get legal tools ko, toh woh kaya karga wo resource bhih check kar automatically, right?
Mayank: Exactly.
Ankit Singh: Okay.
Mayank: will plan Hari? How can we assist it? Malhav, I explained this when I explained Primitas in depth. That was the reason ki I explained. Kumapai explained each and everything.
Mayank: So just see the same again, and then you will understand khaw tools kahi, okay?
Ankit Singh: No, but maximum in industry as of now, like, people are creating only tools they are not.
Mayank: actions, and 99% of the AIs are getting smarter.
Mayank: kantha hai.
Ankit Singh: Mmm.
Mayank: I think that is the case where it works. Klaod kum normally koi cheese bhati tohi jata us aapseh mei kanakna fast jojat woh.
Mayank: What week is that?
Ankit Singh: Second question, yeh hai, kiabihase, right? Toh, apnek middleware bhata thak middleware mein, we can do, like, a dynamic tool colleagues, right?
Mayank: Yes.
Ankit Singh: Toh, Abhi MCP server bhi Azure dynamic call kar sahan.
Mayank: That is not the concept. Kyuki, MCP server pina, it is a different way of doing it.
Mayank: MCP Aparne tools, you don't own the tools.
Mayank: VAP, we own the tools.
Ankit Singh: Hmm.
Mayank: So there is a difference. It is a very, very basic difference.
Mayank: ki MCP mein, you are just using… you have to see MCP as a voice, you kind of don't care. Ki bhai Yuskinda kibne tools kya hai.
Mayank: MCP p kulkar.
Mayank: So, that ways there is a difference.
Mayank: owning it to Oprah, calling it Arti.
Ankit Singh: Lan Singh mehar koi agent BANAREHIN.
Mayank: Right?
Ankit Singh: And then, I want to call some MCP server. Because that is modern Swick Khaki, lot of person is working on the MCP.
Mayank: And the other.
Ankit Singh: I can consume that MCP server to our internal agent, right?
Ankit Singh: Tom Mehra console… medically.
Mayank: MCP is MCP connector.
Ankit Singh: So, suppose that k 100 of tools, so, we have to load 100 of tools?
Mayank: Nayak tools ni noduli na. akke paso zirah to slash list tara na?
Mayank: Shhod tools kisanapkos information Aria.
Mayank: If you think about the same.
Ankit Singh: Mhmhm.
Mayank: Or ideally ape kar rhkind tools benao context. So, if you go on MCP here.
Mayank: It's very simple.ko just take MCP extra ad ganda hai.
Mayank: MCP adapter banana hai.
Mayank: MCP.
Mayank: Eshkindiri tools hogara is angie aki STDIO wala padhadi aka bhajkhi kan.
Mayank: Yuska.
Mayank: Toh, Mehrahit tools akuch kumar gaurav saur tujk MCP mehdi, right?
Ankit Singh: Hmm.
Mayank: Pot… Ideally, if you think about it, though, Sari call paying him, oh, Sari ki sari will be listed.
Ankit Singh: Nay mira y kanai mein summer, mein gai bh rahul me pachaist tool dihiya.
Ankit Singh: Just think about that, k mak MCP server banana rahul banara hun, jo ki hybrid cloud kaly, aka yeh malab applicable one ha chai. Hybrid cloud me aka GCP aka hai gaurav hai.
Ankit Singh: and GC… Azure AWS, Asakta, Alibaba, and XYG, or Asakta Internal, right? So, agar ye patch maripas platform hai, right? Ham ne Hariq platform click MCP tool benabiha, and Hariq platform k MCP tool pesolo ki 100-100 tools hai, 1000.
Mayank: No, no, no, we can technology.
Ankit Singh: Okay, 100, 100 tools,
Ankit Singh: Agar meh meh agent bhara aki, the same agent?
Ankit Singh: will install to everyone, and uske bhar kayoga client is decided, like, aka, Amhaj AWS platform Yujk karna hai, toh.
Ankit Singh: We have to use, only we have to pass some kind of platform, and we.
Mayank: So, understood. That… we can do that segregation. So, what we will do is ki… job ki MCP tools, right?
Mayank: That, we will treat like any other tools, like here, Jessi aapit tools menareki, right?
Mayank: PK?
Ankit Singh: Okay.
Mayank: Uske mah fir aap jo middle vermelh kart. But normally, hum me asi chaitanya, normally jo, MC hum aki tools sahoo kal details hai, but MCP mein hum try kartheek chauhika SARi bhale ky aute na pechange bhosahin. But to answer your question, that is possible. Bharab Jhase a apne joy ape pre-built middleware kendar
Mayank: tool… dynamic tool, same logic naga. Because at the end of the day, they are just tools. Toh me toh, make sure y contact, agar mein lakta aki akyari baat, kay agar GCP Azure, these tools are not required.
Mayank: We will not even send them to LN.
Mayank: Because LLM may not anywhere not be calling the tool, so those is… that is possible.
Mayank: But, when you do tool slash list, you will get every tool. There, you cannot limit it up.
Ankit Singh: Okay.
Mayank: Malhar, when your agent will PC, when you will be defining your LL language chain, right?
Mayank: It will be hitting that to slash list and getting everything. Abhan, if you don't have to send it to your, let's say that, that's not a problem.
Mayank: If you don't understand… Then what?
Ankit Singh: Then, suppose that kind of model, if we have to build, so what kind of best practices to offer for the agent?
Mayank: It is exactly the same way, exactly like it is done here, kind of. In other words, very simple, if you see this. We just get all the tools, and we treat this as, like, any other tools, like the way we have tools with… we, like, we create ourselves, right?
Mayank: So, we can use it like that, normally. Now, any requests which will come, we can just use it.
Mayank: Or otherwise, if you have to just normally make a call, that is also possible. So, if you are seeing these tools here. So, just like we are treating it like just normal tools, nothing else.
Mayank: So, totally possible, no problem.
Ankit Singh: Okay.
Mayank: Just like how we would do the complete, complete, complete, complete your middleware and everything, it can handle all these things up.
Mayank: Just that, one thing to note here.
Mayank: This, when you're loading the tools, you will get all the 100,000 heavy tools.
Mayank: So now it's on you, key, where you want to divide it. Before agent, after agent, before LLM call, where you want to have that thing.
Ankit Singh: Okay, okay, okay.
Ankit Singh: Yeah, we have to pass, like, ape condition or something, like, okay.
Mayank: middleware, whether middleware now, you can do that, or you can just maybe remove it before and everything. Well, that is normally how we just will be doing the tools at our end as well.
Ankit Singh: Mhmh.
Ankit Singh: Okay. Okay, Kanteks JADASO, right?
Mayank: Yes, that's right. Basically, that's right.
Mayank: That's the idea, okay?
Ankit Singh: Okay, yeah, man, thank you so much.
Mayank: Thank you.
Jitendra Biswal: Hello.
Mayank: Alright. One minute, so this was Ankit.
Mayank: Shivan Jitendra Ravinash.
Shivang Shritu: Yeah, hi, man.
avinash singh: Yeah, hi.
Mayank: Yes.
Mayank: Oh, Shivan, let's start with it, yeah.
Shivang Shritu: Can you hear me?
Mayank: Yes, yes, you're audible.
Shivang Shritu: So, Bank, I… I didn't get the chance to speak to you, so I have a few questions. So, I… first is, what all, cloud, basically, subscriptions do we need to have to use connectors?
Mayank: Cloud subscription to use connectors. Connectors in Cloud Code? Cloud, sorry?
Shivang Shritu: 8.
Shivang Shritu: No, no, in cloud, which, I mean…
Shivang Shritu: Which, actually, you showed us, right, in our last class.
Shivang Shritu: Like, on the AI newsletter project.
Mayank: Mhmh.
Shivang Shritu: So, can… can we do that project with the… I mean, without having any subscription to cloud?
Mayank: You can, but few things will not work. Plus, you will have to work it with… you cannot routine, you cannot then automate it, because that works with a lot co-work only.
Mayank: And…
Mayank: Otherwise, you would have just limit-related issues, but otherwise, you don't need anything. Because just Cloud desktop, you will not be able to run, right?
Mayank: So, that would be just the case.
Shivang Shritu: So we need a Cloud Co-work subscription.
Mayank: No. You can do it on Cloud directly here, the one, the Cloud desktop. Sorry, Cloud Web.
Mayank: Just go and do it on CloudWeb. Yeah, yeah.
Shivang Shritu: For desktop? Desktop application do we need to install?
Mayank: No, you can do it here. If you don't have subscription, it will give you an error. I think it doesn't work, so you can do it here only then.
Shivang Shritu: So, basically, whatever you have showed us, right, in our last class, so do we need to pay anything for, to complete that project?
Mayank: No, you don't have to pay anything at all. It's just that, if you…
Mayank: Yeah, it's just… Jitendra, you are, like, after it, yeah. So, just that…
Shivang Shritu: 14 gold, yeah.
Mayank: Sorry, so just that. You… your limits might get over quickly, that's one thing.
Mayank: So, that's, of course, second, but otherwise, you don't have to pay, but yeah, you will not be able to use this Apple Notes.
Mayank: Plus schedule. This, you will not be able to do it.
Mayank: This thing, and this thing.
Shivang Shritu: Okay, so, I mean, do you have any subscription on this? Meh islei pooch Raun kyo ki mehana chatin lia kuch a subscription linee sehlah kan chal jayga, toh agar kali ko subscription.
Mayank: Nikita with Nikki here.
Mayank: agar aap chauh tua bhne subscription ki Pura kar sakte ho. Bas limits kaishuayga, joap kut rhase Vit karna ba sakta akajkante sushai.
Mayank: Because I think laud desktop without subscription, as far as I remember.
Mayank: Teja app uti nahi hai.
Mayank: So, what cheatless?
Mayank: But Apko is a subscription najhi, Apakar web page, are you happy to load web page?
Mayank: Not a problem.
Mayank: Yasia?
Mayank: calendar, Gmail, everything is connected. Alpha Vintage.
Shivang Shritu: YouTube pe matla bh cloud ka course, mehi au se patch me ne palli upload.
Shivang Shritu: Oh, just let it go.
Mayank: Everything's guttered.
Shivang Shritu: Abhih SAI, right?
Mayank: We can… you can watch it.
Shivang Shritu: And, I just also wanted to know how much Gen AI do we need, which is not going to be discussed in this course? Like, what… why I'm asking this? Because to, crack a job in the field of AI, because the…
Shivang Shritu: prerequisites I got from the counselor, right? So, before enrolling into the course was just having Python, deep learning, and NLP only.
Mayank: Yes.
Shivang Shritu: So, I just wanted to know if, I mean,
Shivang Shritu: So, like, how… how we need to cope up with these things? Like, Kasi…
Mayank: So, that is the prerequisite. I think till now, you will be able to get the hold of it and everything, right?
Shivang Shritu: Yeah, like, deep learning NLP tohi ka ha. Jayka basics bhata ako kush projects Mani kiata tha toh basics ka idea hai, but, jaise rakes k bh multiple types, toh kya boh ha.
Mayank: That is not in Gen AI. Actually, RAG is a separate concept. Obviously, MCP is a separate concept, not in Gen AI, but you can club it in Gen AI.
Mayank: And I think… I feel that Sidhani MCP tests, but I think not none of the live patches it has been taught into. Jain ay meh fine-tuning ya ak LMs kasi bhtea tension mechanism ya sab ni kavakaran.
Mayank: We are just using AI. OpenAI inapke models mill rare.
Shivang Shritu: kuch additional lagar aka kuch.
Mayank: Agar aapko lakhta hai ki… agar aapko Lakhta hai ki bsup Chiri ako interview meh chai tohu gav ko pandi padihe lakse hai.
Mayank: Otherwise, scores ki na hai, Dekin naga akar aap job level peucho Mhjal kasi tokenization se lekhek, wo sa baap ko patau an acha y hai.
Mayank: Because we are not going into how to create an LLM and everything, so that is not what we are working on here. We are just using it directly.
Shivang Shritu: Basically, yeah, deep learning kobi have… Joby algorithms, right? RNN Bhara, LSTMGRU, sah meh. Theoretical understanding we have, tactical exposure BHS meh.
Shivang Shritu: or transformer architecture bhih mehoda hai. Toh, basically, Jain AI ka mujhe chai eta, kyogi uspek kuch idea ni milpara hai, ki kya padne se matlap SAI ki I don't want any stone unturned.
Mayank: Okay, I will give you another different approach. Just make sure that you are sitting in the interview.
Mayank: You cannot do everything.
Mayank: we are covering this thing, do you have the basics right? Just try to read a little bit more about this fine-tuning, attention mechanism, all these things. Just try to read a little bit more about how to… how does LLM actually works, and all these things. Let's it in an interview. If you still feel that, okay, there are some questions which you don't know, then go and master them.
Mayank: Because otherwise, having this approach key, no stone unturned, that is a little bit contradictory. Krishnak, so everything, every time there is something left, right?
Shivang Shritu: Na y at least Uthna chia ki interview clear hojayhas.
Mayank: So, I think if you will do around the… how much experience do you have?
Shivang Shritu: Experience is, almost 5 years.
Mayank: So, Skele, I think that you should learn about the fine-tuning transformers architecture, and all these things, and about this tokenization, and all the different, different things which comes up. Those are what is required, okay? Majorly, I guess I'm covering all about the Gen AI basics as well. If you will see people used to teach Gen AI with land chain only, right?
Mayank: Prompt engineering, context engineering, these all things are, as well, just… that should be more than enough.
Shivang Shritu: So, Jobhi humlug kabhi pad rahen, uske mat, uske basis pay humlug age future mein kapi jobs dekang, right? Agentic 3.04 jokhi.
Mayank: Yes.
Shivang Shritu: Or, actually, now getting into, the course, doubt, so I wanted to know, like, what is the exact difference between, basic, that MCB, primitives we have, right? Resources, tools, and prompts, right?
Shivang Shritu: And, mehijana cha to prompt saur skills ki beach me kya difference, because we see skills on.
Mayank: Skills and prompts, skills are just, well-written prompts only, though you can treat them as more or less same.
Mayank: Skills and prompts are almost the same. Skill is a prompt which has been
Mayank: Kind of written in a way where it is telling you where to connect, what to do.
Mayank: Just that skills can have few things extra as well. So, skill can have a script as well.
Mayank: Prompt might not have a script.
Shivang Shritu: Do one more thing, like, yeah, that… and that made me clear about this, and aapki alaba.
Shivang Shritu: Because, you are handling with other courses and all, right? So, ye janathi, kasi wo cheese handle ho sakta hai jaisei dawut sahoo kaha post k karne toh…
Mayank: I have created, again, I will tell you, I have already, I tried to create a readout in the class. I do understand that Hardik you have to wait, but…
Mayank: Throw it aside, try to answer the doubts myself, rather than having a TA or anything.
Mayank: Because I feel that sometimes that breaks the complete thing.
Mayank: That said, I have created Mayank GPT Japay, I've trained it based on all the things which I teach, so that it is able to answer the same as well.
Mayank: Otherwise, you can email me as well. So, QA, in the class, then email, then MGPT.
Mayank: And then hand raised and asking the same at the end as well. So this is 3-4 layers of doubt solving, which is there.
Mayank: Which we try to make sure. Normally, I try to not have a TA or anything, because I feel just because of the way I'm teaching.
Mayank: That might be definite.
Mayank: So, that… those are the different, different scopes of doubt cleaning, I guess, we are having. And in your… I try to peer the doubts in your group as well, but normally they… they are normally different kinds of doubt related to
Mayank: the resource and other things, which I try to fix as well.
Shivang Shritu: Or yeh, Mehta ka wah yana, male to man.
Mayank: Mail to Meh Kagaval. This week, I was traveling, or last week, there was some emergency, but I tried to clear the mails around Tuesday or Wednesday, I tried to clear once in a week, clear the routes.
Mayank: This week, I was not able to see the reply, I was traveling, I was at home.
Mayank: hopefully… by Tuesday, you would be getting that reply.
Shivang Shritu: Okay, fine. So, Sari doubts team mehrei, or kosto aapne jobhi thakur kaya mat lab. That… that… that is fantastic throughout, or…
Shivang Shritu: ganji kay meinay, orhij explore kathna confidence mu cha nahi hai, Abhi thak Mehrah last class thak meh pura aceh wo saara concept deka hai.
Shivang Shritu: Bhiya exposure Mehrah, toh BMI.
Mayank: Now, that is the idea. When you sit in an interview, though, you have things to talk about, rather than just saying that, hey, I can create an agent.
Shivang Shritu: No, yeah, because jo indeft mehi aaphare hain wo, that is completely… aapko Milna saktah cheese, bhar mein abhin mehnei deka hai, aur dharaga a ki course ko aapipne indeft mein, aur job issues johi Ari umskohi aap ache se handle kar rah…
Mayank: standard.
Shivang Shritu: community develop scale abihi.
Mayank: Just trying to put in that effort.
Shivang Shritu: I hope that it'll continue, right? Because…
Mayank: to me.
Mayank: On my end, so it will continue for sure.
Shivang Shritu: You only am enrolled into this course, right? I also asked you on LinkedIn before enrolling, right?
Mayank: I'm being honest every time, and then maybe I would have told it from my end, so it will not be a problem.
Mayank: I either will teach things in depth, even if I have to extend the course by 2 months.
Mayank: Okay, I'm telling you now, after you complete the course and otherwise as well, when you will sit and interview, you will be able to see… speak so many things which you will even not be aware. Kiri aka say, okay, how do I know this thing? So, that is the reason I keep on explaining these things in depth.
Shivang Shritu: Or, please, matlab ye bhapodasana, ye system design Bhagara pe akal questions interview me JADHRA toh…
Mayank: Oh, I was cut.
Mayank: I'm in the middle of creating a contentment time email, but I'm genuinely not able to get the time, so let me try to fix that, and then.
Shivang Shritu: Meh Abhinav aage chauhteweh matlab chapki po.
Mayank: Nayakut to be honest, system design mein muja aapko Lakh krkhek content.
Mayank: But, yeah, I will try to do that. At this time, I promise. See, that will be done.
Shivang Shritu: kum kasar sachin introduces.
Mayank: Otherwise, we'll do that.
Shivang Shritu: Okay, okay, thank you, Meng. Thanks a lot.
Mayank: Chiteiddhar…
Jitendra Biswal: Yeah.
Mayank: Yes, you did.
Jitendra Biswal: Hi, Mike. I've been waiting, I mean…
Mayank: Excuse me, sorry, Arma. I just… you know that how it is. It's your questions, I will try to make.
Jitendra Biswal: One or two, some questions, otherwise…
Mayank: But that doesn't work in the long run. Like, if you have 5 questions, I will make sure to answer everything, right?
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, anyway, so there are a couple of things, like, see, you, you're given the MCP.resource, MCP.prom.
Jitendra Biswal: Yes, so I got it that I added, like, you know, helper, stuffs.
Jitendra Biswal: So… so is it a keyword, or can I create my own kind of things?
Mayank: Which thing? Can you repeat, sorry?
Jitendra Biswal: Is there any list? What other things can be created?
Mayank: I mean, there is MCP resource, MCP prompt, and MCP tools.
Jitendra Biswal: That's it, 3 year in.
Mayank: they are not… that is decorator, that is not just anything which I can use.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay, okay, got it, fine.
Mayank: Decorators you are seeing, not the decorators which I used.
Mayank: At the rate mcp.tools, at the rate MCP.resources.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, okay. So that way, it will help those… no, that's a decorator, but only thing is that I can provide the… some of the resources, like, that will help for the, like, it will help for the MCP, or it will help the, the… I can say…
Jitendra Biswal: To LLM.
Mayank: It will help the LLM to make a better tool call, like, I can put it like that, to use your NCB better, let's use it like that.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, so engage better idea. Okay, okay.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, my next question is, so let's say I have deployed an MCP, like, you know, like, HTTP. Okay, so how do I, you know, what's the name?
Jitendra Biswal: Who knows?
Mayank: We have that easily. We have… we can create versions of MCP.
Jitendra Biswal: So, so, whenever I'm, like, you know, connecting.
Mayank: Hmm, so…
Jitendra Biswal: So, do I have to change the name, or do I.
Mayank: But then you can do the versioning. MCP support versioning. Madham, it is just like any other package. So we have the package versioning, right?
Jitendra Biswal: Mhmh.
Mayank: MCP supports that.
Jitendra Biswal: Until I was done.
Mayank: Oh, it's sister.
Jitendra Biswal: It can be versioned, right?
Mayank: Oh, it can easily be virgin.
Jitendra Biswal: Whoa.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, my next question is a little bit, out of things, like,
Mayank: Before that, I hope… I hope you're able to understand why can I limit the.
Jitendra Biswal: Not out of things, like, I want to have a LLM, okay? Like, a very small LLM, and install in my server, okay?
Jitendra Biswal: And, if I have to download this particular kind of holding face.
Jitendra Biswal: Do I have to build it with a GPT, through GPU or CPU?
Mayank: It depends on you.
Jitendra Biswal: So, if I'm making a, like, container, and I want to deploy it, do I have to deploy it in the GPU or CPU?
Mayank: It depends on how strong your LLM is, what all it is.
Mayank: it can just run on as GPU as well as CPU as well. Depends on how much resources intensive and everything it is.
Jitendra Biswal: I have 8 and… 8 and BM, okay? So, I think you… it has… it has 24, V, yeah, the workflow round.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, 24 GB virtual RAM. I got a LLM that is having, I think, 4 or 5GB, sorry, 7 billion, parameter.
Jitendra Biswal: So… so what is the way to deploy it? I mean, I'm trying to.
Mayank: Volama and everything is there, simply you can do via Volama, LM Studio, all these things are there to directly deploy it.
Jitendra Biswal: Volama, I can, deploy it.
Mayank: Yes, if it is on Hugging Face, you can just directly run the command.
Mayank: And have your, server, like, have your machine running your LLM, not a phone.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, welcome, welcome.
Mayank: Okay, if you have any studio.
Jitendra Biswal: Anything in documents, Kiran just… because it's a.
Mayank: Even just, honestly, I don't have a ready-made document, just go to Claude and ask it, it will be… it is pretty serious talk, not a problem at all.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay. So, can't.
Mayank: Go to Florida.
Jitendra Biswal: What Agile will deploy those things?
Jitendra Biswal: Can I have an agent, like, you know, because I have.
Mayank: No, you don't have an agenda.
Jitendra Biswal: And if I give the server name, everything, all the access, will it deploy it?
Mayank: It can, but you will have to create that, like, I think your agent will need access to your server.
Mayank: I do need the tools so that it can run the commands there, so authorization done when your agent can run the tools, so it can easily do that. Not a problem at all.
Mayank: It will need the command line tools to run the commands, but yes, it is easily possible.
Jitendra Biswal: Oh, beautiful.
Jitendra Biswal: Okay, fine, that's it. Thank you.
Mayank: Just do a simple search of Claude, it is very, very simple to run up.
Mayank: Oh, hogging face.
Jitendra Biswal: I mean, if I find an issue, I'll send an email, I mean.
Mayank: I'll just send the email, I will have a look.
Mayank: Pew.
Mayank: I have a nutshells.
avinash singh: Oh, Maya, today's class, we have covered the MCP studio and removable STP.
avinash singh: I just need to understand, like, in production-based system.
avinash singh: We'll be using the SHRMP only, you know?
avinash singh: What do independent portrait.
Mayank: People.
avinash singh: What is the importance of studio there?
avinash singh: I mean…
Mayank: So, again, if you are having… that is what I was explaining there as well, key.
Mayank: STDIO doesn't just mean, like, I'm having this STDIO, but it can connect further to other… other, APIs as well, right?
avinash singh: H?
Mayank: So, it can use, then, my resources, just as an example.
Mayank: It is going to use my machine resource, right?
avinash singh: Mhmh.
Mayank: I hope you… that is clear. If I am hitting Gmail, send email here.
avinash singh: Fair enough.
Mayank: It will be using my machine resources, okay?
Mayank: Now, if you think.
Mayank: GitHub, Gmail, Tribe, they can also give you an STTIO-based MCP, where they say that, hey, get it all on your server, on your machine.
Mayank: Hit it via your machine, we are not owning any source or anything.
Mayank: Make sense?
avinash singh: Okay, so there we'll use this studio.
Mayank: But at the other end, now there can be a case where
Mayank: we are using it in a separate manner. For example, be it?
Mayank: GitHub or Gmail, all these people are saying that, hey, we have our own server, now you hit the call, so they are now handling all the scaling and everything there.
Mayank: Able to connect the dots a little bit?
avinash singh: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Mayank: So don't think of it like STTIO is just for my local things. No, no, no, no, it can, like, I can have a Gmail thing else.
avinash singh: But I thought that it would be only for, you know, for local machine that we can, you know, things can communicate in between.
Mayank: Another reason I have mentioned as Venki, actually, if you see this, This one.
Mayank: So there is a Git, which is a…
Mayank: Like, let's try to see this. This is actually a local one.
Mayank: This Git is a local one. Why? Because it can run command on your Git only, right, within the servers.
avinash singh: Totally got it.
Mayank: So that is the case. So, it is not like that. But yes, if you want a server where you are doing the heavy lifting at the server end.
Mayank: TOEFL, it will be, based on, not local level, it will be then suburban.
Mayank: So that is the guess.
avinash singh: So, my second doubt is, like, let's say in Lang Chains, what you taught, and I figured it out. So…
avinash singh: A blank chain tool is nothing but just a Python function. We wrap it with.
Mayank: Does the market.
avinash singh: curated.
Mayank: Unlesias, ya.
avinash singh: I just need to understand, we have conceptually… I just need to understand that
avinash singh: the tool which we had created using Langchain, how is it different from the tool which is exposed by the MCP server?
avinash singh: What is the real problem does MCP solve?
avinash singh: The plain Langston tool doesn't.
Mayank: Okay, so let's say that you are…
avinash singh: what I'm…
Mayank: Good, yeah.
Mayank: Let me explain it.
Mayank: Let's say that you want to define 10 tools.
Mayank: inside your Langchain agent, okay?
Mayank: Now you want to use it, so you're using it, okay?
avinash singh: Okay.
Mayank: Now, let's say that you want to share the same with your friend. How will you do that?
avinash singh: Okay, so there, MCP… we can put it in MCP.
Mayank: This is just one of the use cases, I'm just coming to others, yeah. Now you can… you will make sure that, okay, you share the code file with your friend, okay?
Mayank: Next up, then you say that, okay, you want to do some changes. You enable 11th tool.
Mayank: How will you do with your friends? Chalo, you will send the code again. Now, how will you do with cross-department?
Mayank: Closed department.
avinash singh: You got it.
Mayank: You can, you will see that, Mayank, I will get a GitHub repo. Take care.
Mayank: pool, you will get a GitHub repo.
Mayank: No…
Mayank: How will you make sure that, okay, someone doesn't break your code, someone doesn't… you are doing some change, someone overwrite your change and everything?
Mayank: Okay.
avinash singh: P.
Mayank: thing from a Google or Gmail then.
Mayank: Gmail is saying that, okay, everyone, you download the same and install the tools and everything.
Mayank: Then you try to make sure that you are every time updating the same… You're going to get pool.
Mayank: Okay, you install the libraries which is required and everything, all that thing you do. Isn't it a problematic thing?
Mayank: If you think about this, like, there's a lot of management, there's a lot of things which we have to do, right?
avinash singh: Over here, MCP solves a lot of use cases, which could be breakable in this case.
Mayank: Exactly. So MCP is nothing but a glorified API call, I always say this, but… Then…
Mayank: to say that, okay, go to your cloud, download the same.
Mayank: add them one by one. It's much better give… wait, this is the link, just add this link.
avinash singh: You got someday.
Mayank: And you will be able to accept it.
avinash singh: Yes, yes, it's.
Mayank: for the ease of use for the AI space.
avinash singh: Fair enough.
Mayank: Understood. Key any ganagi kit, pull, borrow, just do anything, no, no, no, just to do one thing.
avinash singh: Bharwadar, if you have to, you know, you're going to put a new case scenario, then again, you have to…
avinash singh: Jitendo in GitHub and everything.
Mayank: Oh, exactly.
avinash singh: Yeah.
Mayank: Exactly.
avinash singh: One more thing. So, just need to understand, by end of October, when we'll be in a position to give Agentic AI interview? I mean, to say that full-stacks Agentic AI engineer role.
avinash singh: This is terrible.
Mayank: I think Ragh will be left, you know, topping the topic, which is very much in-depth. Well, again, I'm still taking the call how much in-depth I have to go in RAG.
Mayank: The RAG, of course, can be taken from very basic to very much in-depth.
Mayank: So…
avinash singh: told that it will take a month or a month and a half, then again.
Mayank: Again, it will… Ballab Ragh, I will take it around.
Mayank: It is September right now. By October end, you will be having projects, you will be understanding things, so that should not be a problem. That should be doable.
Mayank: Because land change… and if you think we have covered all the project, we'll have all the concepts.
avinash singh: So, Langchain, till now, you have covered Langchain in very depth. Very depth. I mean, I can tell you, I've joined a Udemy course.
avinash singh: And post se compare karuto matlab comparable haine. So you, you, human in the loop, middleware, everything. And I guess, and you also told that, if we had covered everything in Lan Singh, same thing will be applicable in LandGraph and everything.
Mayank: Oh, LandGraph mean, LandGraph node, but other free ones. Like, let's say ADK is there.
Mayank: So, yay akaam Jat hai, let me go with Python.
Mayank: But, everything is almost the same. Simple agent, Yeah.
Mayank: Then we have… Let's see… This is not the right trip for one minute.
Mayank: 3 meetings.
Mayank: Python Quick Start… Well, concepts are same. Middleware agent.
avinash singh: Moreover, 80-90% thinks the same.
Mayank: 70%, I would say, not 80-90, 70% of them are safe.
Mayank: So, everything is, like, almost the same in here. You will have agents, you will have model for agents.
Mayank: How you can connect, like, other different things, like template workflows.
Mayank: sequence, group agent, nothing else. So this will get a little bit more clear with your, that same black graph.
Mayank: But then, human input is human in the loop.
Mayank: Similarly, let's say this, AWS AWS Agent SDK, I think there is something in AWS as well.
Mayank: Strand digits.
Mayank: So, this is also very much…
Mayank: Very, very simple fact, if you want talks.
Mayank: Although I don't love reading talks, because everything is coming from docs only, so tools are there, custom tools.
Mayank: MCP tools, multi-agent system, structured output.
Mayank: Streaming.
avinash singh: Same thing, same thing, I guess.
Mayank: Also, the sync the date.
Mayank: storage. So I will, as I told you, Garg, if I even take 4 to 5 months in mastering you Lanjain Lagraph.
Mayank: Or even one framework in depth. Others, you will be able to do easily if I just take a crash course, 3-4 hours class, and then do the project.
Mayank: Or rather, if I directly even do the project, you will be able to master it.
Mayank: It is at that level.
avinash singh: One more thing, from last couple of days, I was trying to, you know, making the same thing, I was, you know, using that, Anthropic API, as well as OpenAPI. So I just need to understand, Aparne Bola aki grop mein, you'll get, you'll get free things over there.
avinash singh: And it has different models under it, like fixed models, voice models.
Mayank: It is only free and open source only, but yeah.
Mayank: Open source.
avinash singh: Things are… but I can see that there are things, which is paid also, the models which are available, because.
Mayank: It will be having certain limits, etc, but it will not be free-free, but yes, it will still give you very good limits, the GROQ grow, right?
avinash singh: CSS, the Q one, not the K1.
Mayank: So it is, again, same thing. We'll be having multiple models, but it will have some limits for anything.
Mayank: But, yeah, that would be the case.
avinash singh: And, Mohank, apne ye jo apna abhav, that's physical therapy and wellness, voila.
Mayank: Yes.
avinash singh: Just need to understand, Aparna is ko deploy kedar kaya hai.
Mayank: Abhira selfie per day.
avinash singh: Okay.
avinash singh: The analytics and everything which is there for Sepaha.
Mayank: Today, we are using… we are using SuperBaseDP.
avinash singh: Okay. These are all rough.
Mayank: There's a complete architecture, remind me, I can cover it in the next class, maybe.
Mayank: Well, a proper architecture is there. Tampa, we have covered multiple things. We are covering… connecting with multiple things as well, so that is following a proper…
Mayank: Way of doing that will look properly.
avinash singh: Okay, okay. That's how you had done that thing.
Mayank: I will… what I will do is I will take half an hour to discuss around that project.
Mayank: That, I think, would be helpful, Madhab. I will showcase the code and other things.
Mayank: Yeah, fair… directly showing that as a project might be a little technical, putting a technical batch. Let me take the call. If it is possible, I will do that.
avinash singh: And one more thing, let me know what are all the things that I need to focus along with this course. I mean.
Mayank: How much experience do you have?
avinash singh: Race and a half.
Mayank: Fair enough.
avinash singh: Yes.
Mayank: Five and a half, right? 5.5.
avinash singh: Yes, sir. 5.5.
Mayank: Yeah, so you can do DSA, you can do system design.
Mayank: And majorly, whatever projects you have done, if you can try to see that, how can you either integrate AI into that.
Mayank: Or you can make sure that how can you explain them properly.
Mayank: That would be the expectation which I think people will have, along with the AI concept, which I think will be taken care in this batch. Now that, for example, MCP, you know, but now you know the architecture as well, right?
Mayank: Okay. Now I will teach you, ketcham, why MCP moved away from this architecture which we have spent two weeks discussing.
Mayank: if you know things in this much depth, that is where you are high level, not like… and again, coding tool will take a… coding will be required, but I think…
avinash singh: coding-wise, I'm pretty good. I just need to understand, let's just say, nowadays, you know, Jay Sabharad Company used to build their own models over there. Nowadays, everything is harnessing whatever models which is created.
Mayank: Because…
avinash singh: Nobody's.
Mayank: Treating that is very difficult, Mtlav.
avinash singh: difficult be, but the hardware, they are not, you know, having it, like, the.
Mayank: Hmm.
avinash singh: Companies which are having that kind of hardware with them.
avinash singh: So, I just need to understand, so everything will be going around, Agentic loop, I guess, going forward, rather building
avinash singh: That's end of it.
Mayank: Honestly, it is not like that, like, normally it was also the case. It's like, we got AI now, let's try to see how we can use AI properly, that is all. There's only nothing else.
Mayank: If you think about this.
avinash singh: tuning.
Mayank: That is the case, I think it's…
Mayank: Okay, Pallop, we have to just harness it, we have to use it, right?
Mayank: So how we can use it best, that is what comes in the hardest part.
avinash singh: I just need to understand, Mayank, I… Meh organization, Meh, they were using this GCP. It's my BigQuery, and everything was there.
Mayank: and…
avinash singh: So… but Manjo Sacharam. So, most of the jobs, I guess 50%, they're asking for AWS kind of things.
Mayank: Doesn't matter if you know GCP in depth.
Mayank: Should we find.
avinash singh: Okay.
Mayank: Because cloud credits are similar, not a problem.
avinash singh: Yes, yes, yes. Okay, thank you, thank you so much. That was excellent. And, amazing class. Today class was amazing.
Mayank: Feedback on the radar's.
avinash singh: No, that's correct.
Mayank: have it to showcase.
avinash singh: And Mayank 8 or cheese Bhad Sriyan. Let's just say we have covered that Lenk chain, and now we are covering this MCP thing. So, are we going forward? Is there any place, or you can share the detailed syllabus with us, with the timeline that we're going to.
Mayank: Oh my gosh.
avinash singh: kings.
Mayank: Let me try to do that. My idea, I can just give you an idea. My idea is to…
Mayank: Cover, after this, Langchain, and then land graph.
avinash singh: Mhmh.
Mayank: Then, projects around the same.
Mayank: Then I will make sure we pick up the different, different ones which we promised key, ADK.
Mayank: AutoGen, other different, different kind of things. We do directly projects or crash course kind of a coverage of that.
Mayank: So, that would be my idea, but timeline-wise, let me try to share it, and Ragh, I'm still gauging how much depth I have to teach. I do have to go in depth, like Ragh, like MCP have taught you.
Mayank: Or do I have to just do it in a general sense, or a usable sense? So that… let me… just give me…
Mayank: two weeks more, because honestly, right now, my… like, I'm having generally worst test of the days with respect to the time side. So, just, once I get some… catch some breath, I will try to get that, okay?
avinash singh: So we'll come out with that Ashishism.
Mayank: Hari was a mix of both things, some in my control, some other ways, but I will try to do that, okay?
avinash singh: Oh, very lovely. Thank you, thank you, Mr.
Mayank: Thank you. Great.
Mayank: Shivan, yes, so for that, I have a few projects up, but I hired people, like, I think one I've hired from your batch as well.
Mayank: So, if there is future more projects, I will let you know. Honestly, I have less time at my age, so I'm not picking up a lot of them.
Mayank: Pradhi, I have to make sure that I teach you properly, right?
Mayank: Abhijit?
Mayank: Zach?
Mayank: occupital.
Mayank: Hello? In the same order, Abijitas.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Yeah, yeah, yeah. This is Mayank Chuuka, not Abhi.
Mayank: Serious ideas.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Yeah, actually, my son's ID I'm using for this.
Mayank: Okay, yes, yes, I'm buying, Hong Kong, right?
Abhijeet CHUGH: Handy, have you ever fell out on telemilu?
Mayank: I was staying dead.
Abhijeet CHUGH: kaly akong kALU.
Mayank: Gotcha. I came back to Bangalore on Thursday.
Abhijeet CHUGH: And actually, Pushnehdid, like,
Abhijeet CHUGH: MCP mein Abhita kabh yeh padhai ke kasi banana kasi karna. And I think Mani long back pura course khe MCP mein. We also have to enter, do a… put an entry in the cloud.json file or MCP.json.
Mayank: I will be covering tomorrow to add your custom MCPs. You have two ways. Either you do it via connectors, which I've shown you, or there is a cloud desktopconfig.js form where you have to add your MCPs, which we will cover, like, just what I did, right?
Mayank: We will be covering that, but that's the first thing which we will do tomorrow.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Like, first thing when I started doing this learning, started MCP, 3, 4, 4, 5 months back, thaki, it's very risky as well, because agar ham kisi ka bhi market koi bhi connect koi.
Mayank: MCP side.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Aparna integrate karaenge, we have to be very careful. Kahi Parh Biag chopawa terminal access Deh dia.
Abhijeet CHUGH: you gone, right? Kumatane. Toh, yashis kum kasi kay aka ki…
Mayank: who I will be taking up in the project, so that is there. We are… so, see, Abhi thak if you will see I have Teams had complete MCP for you. Now we are creating our own.
Mayank: Creating our own next step is to integrate in plot. Then next step is to use provided by people.
Mayank: And then next step is to create a complete end-to-end project, or maybe, let's say, making your available to others. So when I will showcase you the MCP created by others, that is where this concept will come, not tied.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay, it could be, like, putting in a guardrail in MCP at our end at host, right?
Mayank: It is not about the guardrail. Again, with the guardrail, there is a very generic word. It is like, you just use MCPs which are,
Mayank: properly checked, like, which are not… just like any other application, so now MCP is kind of the same thing, right? Just use MCPs which are…
Mayank: Very much properly from a testified source, not like anything is there.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay. But, there could be possible… basically, there are 100 and 1,000, and we find that one use case, what we are looking at, it's an open source, then we have.
Mayank: for two weeks.
Abhijeet CHUGH: We cannot test it, or we cannot do it, because there are thousands of,
Mayank: For example, there are multiple MCPs which are from the official provider, so we are sure that that will not be a problem. Otherwise, normally, if you are getting it from GitHub or from open source, you have the stars and everything.
Mayank: Plus, they do get checked, like, normally if you are getting it from Sidhri or any other as well, they are properly checked.
Mayank: But then there can be issues, like, not so sure how many of you remember this, there was recently a security incident last… two months back.
Mayank: Hugging Face one. Hugging Face Dean, it was in Linux, where it was in NPM or something.
Mayank: So, that kind of issues can creep in anywhere, when people can try to access your terminal, etc. But yeah, just try to use justified sources, nothing else.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay. One more, like, in, in our,
Abhijeet CHUGH: Last, last week, last project, Glad Desktop Pavanayata, we connected through…
Abhijeet CHUGH: Smeh, we have a draft email, right? Laxman? Yes. It is all completely on… depend on one… one, brain at the end, which is basically Claude, which is SONAT. Because Claude itself is not very good in, creating an image, right?
Abhijeet CHUGH: take care. We need some… suppose we have to integrate some infographics, or we need to add.
Mayank: some emails.
Abhijeet CHUGH: stages, we cannot do that in the draft. So, for that…
Abhijeet CHUGH: Is it possible that in the same architecture, we can also include another, like, ChatGPT or any other,
Abhijeet CHUGH: Any other LLM?
Mayank: Awesome.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Getting that information.
Mayank: Here, two things here.
Mayank: First, is that in this architecture, using another LLM is not the right call. Using…
Mayank: A tool or an MCP to create image is a better approach, first thing. Okay.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay.
Mayank: Second thing, via Claude, you cannot have two LNMs. Via your own… when you will be creating your own lan Jain agent or something, there you can have the brain swapped.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay, by coding is… by coding we can…
Mayank: coding will control. Therefore, Claudhopper will use its own bin only.
Abhijeet CHUGH: chota sa tip chai, because what is happening, that so far, whatever you ask, Kash is fine. This one, like, I have gone through your classes again and again, at least two times. Uske bhad.
Abhijeet CHUGH: After 2 or 3 weeks, I don't even remember ki… Manusme kA padata, I maybe remember the…
Abhijeet CHUGH: because my notes even Arrows, a Kusha Rohbar, I… I forget how it… we have done that there. Bhar k middleware per day, middleware.
Mayank: Multiple.
Abhijeet CHUGH: at least… Abhi, actually, it's a learning process, like, we know, we learned the process, and then we are ready for the interview. Now we are, I think, in AI world, it's… things are going very fast, and we have to be also ready for the interview within a few weeks and within few months.
Abhijeet CHUGH: I'm… I don't know how to get ready for those interviews with these co… answers those questions, because when we'll start up, people will start asking questions, interviews, then we know, ki… Yadne, ye pada yadny, usko kasarik, overcome concerns.
Mayank: just go and give the interview. This is not some exam key. We are revising it every 3-4 weeks. If you have understood the concept with me properly, it will be revised. If you have focused on the basics and everything.
Mayank: Okay. Then you don't care if you know the middleware key, how there is a middleware, and what is the more concept about it, which I've talked in very much depth.
Mayank: I don't think syntax or anything is required.
Mayank: Plus, you will never be fully ready for an interview. Just go ahead and give the interview, see where you are lacking, and revise it, nothing else.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay. Because they interview gayatap, they interview Shailek.
Mayank: So, interview is a exercise where the first C24 will fail, most probably, and that is where you get help out of it, so not a problem.
Abhijeet CHUGH: teak… Last week…
Mayank: this.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Last thing I…
Abhijeet CHUGH: Man aapko, Aparna mein ko Bolatha Mehmh k lia, uske lia, 20 plus palaik klei, yes, aka kaleihi.
Mayank: I'm trying to honestly find someone, but I don't have anyone who is hiring at that range. Okay, 20 plus years, or even 10 plus as of now.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Mhmh.
Mayank: reasons, there is a more salary thing. Plus, normally, whoever I connect with, now, I… so, see, by nature, I try to help people who are
Mayank: in their initial journey, like this, KUUNova, which is a.
Mayank: I know that person, and that is, again, based on some other
Mayank: Case, whether that person is also starting up.
Mayank: So, I want to connect with companies as such, whether I try to stay away because they have very longer processes. What the problem with companies is that they might ask you that, hey, send me the CV, but I cannot assure you the call will be there. For example, in Zenova, I… for a worded CVs, two people got the call. They have given interview as well this week, but they were not selected.
Mayank: So I want to own up that Rinki H5M saying to you, Keeper, you will get a fault, so you will get a fault, rather than me just forwarding your CV, which you might also be doing.
Mayank: Okay. So, that is the difference there, or Abhi… Usme, I'm not able to get anyone who is hiring in that range.
Abhijeet CHUGH: That…
Mayank: That said, I am still looking out, so I do have your profile in mind. If anything comes up with around 15, 20 years of experience, I will forward it there.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay, okay, alright.
Mayank: Okay, so that is the case. Like, right now, the opportunities which I'm sharing, that are the one which I know that people will get up on, for sure.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Because when you say that it's, don't send over 20 years or 10 years plus, I never say.
Mayank: Well, the problem is key, again, because the POC have told me, give me a hiring 3 to 6 years only, 3 to 6 or 7, the salary range and everything, so I don't want that unnecessarily. I get your hopes high, and I will not be sharing that, because if I share that as well, they will not consider it.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Oh, that's funny.
Mayank: That is the case.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Tekage.
Mayank: But if anything comes up, I will surely do that, not a problem. But I just say I don't want to keep any false, okay, I'm forwarding the ZVA and move it lost, okay, just that is something which I don't…
Mayank: Every CV which I forwarded last week is where I talked to the person and told him, Jitesh, this one is good, what is missing in this, so that the people were able to get called for the interview. So that is the approach.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Okay.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Take care, sir. Thank you, G.
Mayank: I will just try to make sure, yeah, I will put in the effort and get that done.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Thanks for your effort, as well, for people…
Mayank: He didn't know what I mean?
Mayank: I remember that, I remember that, but as a SANE, I want to give the opportunities which are genuinely
Mayank: malab converting, not like each other, man, I will give me the CB, I will forward it, and then forget, no. I should have a person whom I can hold and say, yeah, check Kyow, why are you not selecting? So that I can give you that feedback as well.
Mayank: Abhjase, that's why I was asking for Rup, like, the person who got an interview, but he was not selected, because I have the feedback, so I will tell him the feedback.
Mayank: So that way, you will be able to grow. So that is my idea.
Abhijeet CHUGH: Panjica.
Mayank: Could you…
Abhijeet CHUGH: Thank you, thanks a lot.
Mayank: Zach?
Zackariya Yoosuf: Hi, Mike. Hi.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, in the organization where I'm working, we have a Microsoft ecosystem.
Mayank: Okay.
Zackariya Yoosuf: And, it's a big organization, and we have, almost all departments, what you can think of, actually.
Zackariya Yoosuf: So, my question is, you know, whatever we are studying, what we… how can I, I want to build something, you know, I'm working in the department, I have access to SQL.
Zackariya Yoosuf: So, can you give some, Guidelines, or guidance.
Mayank: That's good news. Yup.
Zackariya Yoosuf: I have 20 years' experience.
Mayank: Yes, right? Okay.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, yeah. And I'm, mainly supporting, you know, mainly the payroll and…
Zackariya Yoosuf: timesheet and everything. Employees, you know, HR, basically. Also, with finance, also working.
Zackariya Yoosuf: So…
Mayank: Yeah, so see, first thing.
Mayank: For… what you have to do is forget about AI agents and anything.
Mayank: Just see the thing which is most…
Mayank: Time demanding or effort demanding from your…
Mayank: users, learners from your colleagues. Like, as an example, if you're in the HR department.
Mayank: Do you get lots of queries, etc, which you can automate, which you can help people answer faster? So…
Mayank: Anything which we are doing in the AI space, in the tech space, is to just get some tangible work done.
Mayank: We are not creating applications because we like it, we create them because that has a tangible output, okay? By now using Sweaky, people can order food.
Mayank: Same goes for AI as well. When you are using AI, it is not that we are just doing it for fun, it is having a tangible output.
Mayank: You can generally now talk with ChatGPT Cloud and get answers, plus other tools as well, other AIs as well. You can now do a lot of things.
Mayank: Same approach you have to follow here as well.
Mayank: Okay, actually understanding what are the pain points, and at 20 years of experience, you are very nicely placed on that.
Mayank: see the pain points and see that, okay, if that can be sought. As a very basic example, can you create a lanchain kind of an agent?
Mayank: And have a… have it hosted by a Steambit, so that
Mayank: That can then be used through
Mayank: Answer the questions related to, or queries related.
Mayank: So, that is where you will be seeing your learning useful, and it will not be ever 100% overlap. Like, no course in this world
Mayank: They'll give you that 100% overlap.
Mayank: key…
Mayank: It will be like, you learn the new buyer. No, none, I can write it down in the paper, but you will have to seek cha where I'm able to have 40-50% of the things you know.
Mayank: And where then you were able to create it. So, you will have to find those things, and then see where you can create or automate stuff there. So, that is the…
Zackariya Yoosuf: Okay, and see, the thing is, we already have a, AI team, and they are already building agents, you know, like, for coding, like, rug-based, right? Okay. So, yeah, but, but, in the system, like, the…
Zackariya Yoosuf: So, what I'm looking for, how I can integrate, this knowledge with the system I'm building, right? For recurring, knowledge base and, giving answers, that is already there for each, each department level.
Mayank: But what system are you building? What are you trying to achieve with that system?
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, system is, I can say, for, for, timesheet, yes. Yeah, it's there.
Zackariya Yoosuf: And, other than that, for, you know, for procurement section, supply chain, you know, there is a… we have, we have a system, like, where you will order the,
Zackariya Yoosuf: Items, and it will go to the store, and, like, you know, wherever the frameworks, it's there.
Mayank: So, no, that is what I'm saying. He just tried to find the pain point. I'm being really honest here.
Mayank: For example, if you just timesheet, right?
Mayank: Can you make sure that via using an agent or anything, you can provide the analytics faster, you can help people fill the timesheet faster, make less errors?
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, whatever, you mean to say whatever, the repeated workflow, that we can automate using the agents, is what you're saying, right?
Mayank: Either you will have to save time or money. These are the two.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah.
Mayank: matters.
Mayank: Okay, LSMD.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Correct. By analyzing the pattern, how it has been done for the previous months, then that we can
Zackariya Yoosuf: Make it automate for the current period, and something like that.
Mayank: there, exactly, and otherwise, as well, you can tell, you can have a thing added, you can sit with the AI team and tell that, hey.
Mayank: Let's try to create a system via which we can tell people to take holidays if they are having holidays get over, or if they are fitting in their timesheet, but they are missing out or making some errors, how can we fix that before?
Mayank: Or otherwise as well, can we make the filling of timesheet via Slang, where Agent can help us do that?
Mayank: So, rather than logging into some system, if we can create an API, and we can provide an MCP for that, so that will help the team save time.
Mayank: Okay? Otherwise, it's well on the analytics side and everything, so that would be a little tech side. But don't unnecessly fix AI, like, believe me, AI is just useful in 50% to 60% of the use cases. It can be done by simple automation.
Mayank: To either save money or time. Apart from that, nothing else matters. Just for fun or hobby, nothing will be mattering. So in your case, if you're doing so many things around you, like, you are doing the procurement part, right?
Mayank: So can you… can you, try to make sure that you can create multiple agents who can take up the work?
Mayank: And try to…
Mayank: expedite this procurement process, find the errors, find multiple vendors, all these things up. So rather than you starting from scratch, those are kind of creating the first level of
Mayank: Thing. You can create that very nicely in Claude, if you think about this.
Zackariya Yoosuf: In Florida, it's very…
Mayank: easy. You can create multiple agents and stuff, and they can do the work for you.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Okay, now the knowledge base, we can connect to SQL, that's not a problem, right?
Mayank: Sql, you can connect to the knowledge base, but again, that is not that simple connection, because for RAD, it is not that sensible. You just give it the data. But for other things, it is, but it should not be returning you thousands or lakhs of those, then it will not have any useful.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yes, yes, yes.
Mayank: So that are the decisions which you have to take, and what I will normally suggest in that case is that since you are in a company, just sit and find some time with the people who are in the AI part, and then see that what they are doing.
Mayank: Because for you, this is a good to-do thing, for them, it is a must-to-do thing.
Mayank: So, they will be
Mayank: to tell you that within your company's boundaries, within your company's architecture and everything, how can they… how can you actually use these things up? That would be the idea.
Zackariya Yoosuf: So, what… you told something, MCP, in timesheet, what.
Mayank: Yeah, you can create the MCP in the timesheet so that people can fill it via Slack or without logging into the system directly via something. That would be much easier to implement.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Oh, okay.
Mayank: That is, yeah, what are the automation and everything, nothing else. About making things easier, nothing else.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Mayank: Yep.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Okay, thank you.
Mayank: I would suggest, if I were to have been at your position, I would have sat with the person who is handling the AI team, and get a good repo or a good connection with him, and ask him that, hey, I also am learning these things up, this is all that I know, I know these things in depth. Can you tell me, like, how you're using it, and how can I do it? The reason is that
Mayank: Then you will get an idea about how things can be done within the company's boundaries, okay?
Zackariya Yoosuf: So rather than.
Mayank: When you're throwing an arrow in the sky, you will know that, okay, where exactly to aim.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Because…
Mayank: Again, I can give you a generic advice, that personal advice will be a lot more tailored to your company-specific case, right?
Mayank: So, that would be my suggestion, or my step.
Mayank: Or maybe I will just ask, like, since you're at 20 years of experience, people will be under you. You can just call a meeting and say that, hey, what is the problem, or what is the thing where we are spending the most time getting the most queries?
Mayank: For example, if you're in the hiring department, then, hey, do we have to go through resumes and everything, can we automate that?
Mayank: And don't think of that.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Right, so I already automated all this.
Mayank: But there will be something. See, the problem is that there can be… optimization can be done always.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah. So, just…
Mayank: If that is automated, then you will be spending time some other thing, right?
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yeah, correct.
Mayank: just try to fix that, nothing else. We have been doing this thing to save time for the last…
Mayank: So many years, like, since eternity.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Okay.
Mayank: The new problem will arise.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Yes.
Mayank: Okay.
Zackariya Yoosuf: Book? Okay.
Mayank: Thank you.
Mayank: Occupitunant.
Mayank: Sorry if I'm making the name wrong.
Mayank: occupied LNR, but do tell me the name as well.
occipitalnet: Yeah, hi, ma'am.
occipitalnet: Thank you for the class. I mean, it was really, really very detailed, and I really, when I joined, I was not expecting that, we will have things so much in detail that, I mean, we don't have to give time, from our side to cover the things, because everything is now being covered in the class itself.
Mayank: Thank you.
occipitalnet: So, that's… that's the first thing. And occipital letters, because I started my career with computer vision, and occipital, is a part of the brain which is actually very much related to vision, of… a vision, thing of the brain.
Mayank: Oh, okay, okay, okay.
occipitalnet: Yeah, so that's, that's how my…
Mayank: The vital nerve, right?
occipitalnet: Yes, ossipital. And net is because neural network, net, net.
Mayank: Good name for a computer vision company, you should open that.
occipitalnet: Yes.
occipitalnet: Mike, I have a few questions related to my career. It's like, I am into AI industry since 2021. It has almost been, like, 5 to 6 years. As I said, I started my career with vision, computer vision, the traditional computer visions, and
Mayank: on CV and everything in that, and…
occipitalnet: Yes.
Mayank: STM and all these things, yeah, CNN, everything.
occipitalnet: Yes. And, and parts of deep learning also, I.
Mayank: I've also done that, yeah.
occipitalnet: Yes, so I was working in Bangalore, and I worked primarily into explainable AI terms, saliency maps, where I was doing research, like, why my model is predicting what it is predicting.
occipitalnet: So, now the thing is that, I mean, we also deploy, we also, deployed those features at Client Site also, but the thing is that now it has been, like, almost two and a half years.
occipitalnet: Unknowingly, I joined a consulting firm, basically.
Mayank: Okay.
occipitalnet: They were building this AI COE team in their, company, and they wanted people with pure hands-on on deep learning and vision, and maybe, future trends, whatever is coming in. I mean, willing to take up those.
occipitalnet: So I joined that company, but now the thing is, we are getting projects, but the projects are very, very limited.
occipitalnet: So, understand, from the perspective that someone with 5 years of experience, I'm still building those RAG bots, like, maybe some kind of advanced rag, hybrid search, BM25, that's all sorted.
occipitalnet: But, the thing is that because of all this AI thing and all this cloudy thing, my code quality has…
occipitalnet: drastically reduced. I mean, even to write a simple for loop, I feel, like, very, very difficult nowadays. Not confident, I wouldn't say I cannot write, but not confident. It has become a very day-to-day practice that, you know, you just put your code, get the output, you put it back in your system.
occipitalnet: So that's how things are being. Now I am willing to change.
occipitalnet: And again, I want to go back to my, co-development, thing.
occipitalnet: And I want to take up all these things, like deep learning. Jenny, I… simply, it really feels like I'm just utilizing the API calls, so…
Mayank: Yeah, that is the case.
occipitalnet: Yes, ma'am. So, I just want to understand, like, I mean, I also have, by the way, just wanted to add up on this. I also have taken Saura GANhous for advanced classes, for all those deep learning concepts. So, I'm taking those classes.
Mayank: Paul is not teaching advanced deep learning concepts there, he is teaching AI advanced concept, no?
occipitalnet: Yes, yes, yes, yes, the same thing. But he's, also including different, different deep learning concepts, so, in the back end, so that's how… Yes, yes, it's fine.
Mayank: I will suggest that, Malhab, for your case, what I learned is that you should actually be joining some research lab, maybe Google DeepMind, or IBM, or any of these things, because that is where your tenant will be best used.
Mayank: Because any consulting company, they will always work on what client needs. And there is always… because I have also done research in the same LSTM CNN-based things, and the deep learning, so I have also learned that, and done research work is there.
Mayank: Although I did not like research a lot, so I did not went forward with it.
Mayank: And that was not even in my long-term goal. But that said, I will highly suggest that for you, the best, if you learn… if you love your research side. See, writing code is not an issue if you are facing… sorry.
occipitalnet: Sorry, Mayanka, I'm betting you.
Mayank: No, no, no, it's always, no, no.
occipitalnet: Yeah, I love to develop things. I mean, I am done with research, because you don't see your things getting used elsewhere, and it took you, like.
Mayank: 6 or 7?
occipitalnet: 7 months of hard work, and after, like, seven or seven months, you feel like, you know, whatever you did is already now being done by others, and already being used in the market. So, I am all okay. I mean, that… I liked it in my initial career.
occipitalnet: But, now I want to do pure technical work. I mean, not in the research side, but I want to implement things, I want to put it in production, I want people.
Mayank: Then I will suggest to go to product-based companies, if you are in a client consulting-based company, the project and everything will keep on changing. But if you are in a company like Suea SOMATO, or Aval, or any other of them.
Mayank: That would be much better in the sensei, you are creating something which are directly in a project, and you're owning that up.
Mayank: Rather than a client project where you pick it up, do it, and then you move on to the next one.
Mayank: That is where then I guess, you will enjoy your work a lot.
Mayank: The product-based companies are a lot better, because you own that code, you owe the product.
Mayank: You actually write the code and make it better, and you keep on working on that.
Mayank: So that is much, much, much better than…
Mayank: Then, let's say this consultancy well apart, because in consultancy, you will always have projects which are shifting.
Mayank: And you will have requirements based on just client require, need, and everything. But in product-based companies, good when you also get the time as well to, kind of expand on top of that, so yeah.
occipitalnet: Okay.
occipitalnet: Frank, I'll definitely, take this into consideration.
Mayank: Which experience do you have?
occipitalnet: I have total, like, 5.5 years. I started in 2021, so 5.5, but I have, like, I started also as business analyst, so I had experience of Tableau and Power BI, but that's not relevant to AI, so I'm just keeping it aside. So I started my career back in 2018, so total of, like…
Mayank: Well, I will cover it from 18 and 8 years of experience, doesn't matter. No one was anywhere doing AI before 21 as such, right?
Mayank: Rather, if you are doing deep learning, that is more than enough, so do… take it up as 8 years of experience only, not 5.5.
Mayank: And I will suggest that you connect, and just do a little bit of DSE and stuff, and get into the good product-based companies. That would be much better for your career with respect to the kind of work you want to do with money, and with future opportunities as well.
Mayank: Desai that, that would be much better as a career chance. Amazon, Google, and these Tier 1 companies. Work will be more, but yes, it will be enjoyable, hopefully, and Asa, I think money is also good.
Mayank: And if you want to earn a lot.
Mayank: and just not even go into depth of tech, then you can try out any finance-based company as well, like Goldman Sachs, DeShaw.
Mayank: Any of the bags, because they pair very good.
Mayank: They are technically also fine midway.
Mayank: But yeah, so that is the kind of companies which you can target.
occipitalnet: But man, the problem is that my coding skills, as I said, I mean, it's… it's just… I don't see myself coding and calling it a good code or something, so that's… that's where my main problem lies.
Mayank: So you can fix it in 6 months now.
Mayank: Let's fix it in 6 months, although let's not think, let's not have that tag Kayyar bad at pudding.
occipitalnet: students.
Mayank: 6 months. Much better.
occipitalnet: Okay, so after, like, completing this course, and I have to revise, like, deep learning as well, because, as I said, 3 years and no deep learning concepts, all RAG and.
Mayank: At this time, we'll just go through it properly. In the course, I will be coming about drag and other things properly, but otherwise, you have to revise it, yeah.
occipitalnet: Okay, so I have to work on my, coding skills. The second part, like, I'll be completing this course, and also I have enrolled in, falls class, so all these three things, and probably.
Mayank: I think, again, now it is getting a lot extra, so just try to see where you will be, because these are now lots of things to do.
Mayank: So… I normally suggest you properly focus on one thing.
Mayank: Multitasking is not doing multiple things, it's doing one thing.
occipitalnet: At a time.
Mayank: So if you're doing my course, Paul course, coding and everything, and your job as well, just try to see if you can manage the time. If yes, all good.
Mayank: Let's try to prioritize.
Mayank: If I would have been at your position, I would have mastered the AI concepts, then I would have also did the coding part and started giving interviews and
Mayank: November or December.
Mayank: I would have planned that by next financial year, March or April, I'm able to get out and get the real job in some product-based companies, even if it's a startup and everything.
Mayank: That would have been my approach, rather than mustering everything. The best way to do nothing is to do anything.
occipitalnet: Okay, but Mayank, so, I mean, what you are saying is this class is not in my, I mean, trajectory, this is what you are saying.
Mayank: Nini, I'm just saying he… what you are suggesting is a lot to do.
Mayank: So, just try to balance it out, just… that is my… what I'm suggesting. I'm not saying that do this class or do the other class. I'm just saying you try to balance it out properly if you're doing this much.
Mayank: Revise, code, properly, job.
Mayank: my course, Paul course. Just, I'm saying, just try to prioritize properly so that you actually know these things in depth, nothing else.
occipitalnet: Oh, that's something.
Mayank: what I'm seeing with you.
occipitalnet: Thank you, thank you, ma'am, thank you so much.
Mayank: Cool. Hardik, then we have Prasan, Dines, and Basavannah, I think these are all the people. Cool. Sorry for all the extreme heat, everyone, but I'm also happy.
Hardik Vora: pathetic.
Mayank: Hi.
Hardik Vora: I wanted to go out early, but okay, I got many learnings waiting.
Mayank: 30 seconds.
Hardik Vora: Yeah. So, appreciated, Mike, in detail, as usual.
Hardik Vora: Mike, a couple of quick things. I mean, I wanted to speak in middle. Somebody was,
Hardik Vora: I mean, you were discussing on that, Langchain part in the,
Hardik Vora: middleware, right? In the pre-built middleware, where we should call. So I was also thinking of that same logic. But a couple of things I wanted to add, just correct
Hardik Vora: Correct me if we can go in that direction, or
Hardik Vora: as what you had mentioned earlier, I heard everything, what you explained in detail. I mean, concept budget is very good. So, if you, I mean, recollect that conversation, right? In that MCP, I already have
Hardik Vora: So, basically, we have 10 tools, add tools, separate, okay? Normal add tools, normal methods, which are working for some other reason, okay? Now, I have, considered this recipe box as a generic MCP tool, which will be used across my company.
Mayank: Mhmh.
Hardik Vora: With the three methods which we have created.
Hardik Vora: Okay, I understood your example, that if somebody wants to change, a friend wants it, and it is good, I understood, that it is… we should keep it separate, which can be used globally, and, which nobody should change, and we will handle everything. I mean.
Mayank: Nope.
Hardik Vora: I ain.
Mayank: Oh, understood, yes.
Hardik Vora: Okay, so now, coming on to the actual question, Mike.
Hardik Vora: these tools, which I have created for an org level, I want to use it before… I mean, I want to initiate it.
Hardik Vora: Before the agent call. So there, we will be using add before loop, and then…
Mayank: you can.
Hardik Vora: I will mention that.
Mayank: Everything else.
Hardik Vora: Okay, so I will keep it bare minimum, because I know, as you mentioned, context and all, so I understand, what you were talking on, from optimization perspective. So, that is what we will use first, okay? Now, coming on to my second question, Mike, if you can just, open your…
Hardik Vora: codings, I mean, today's code, please.
Hardik Vora: Debra.
Mayank: The VSC for doing that.
Hardik Vora: Abhi escort me.
Mayank: Yep, should you visible.
Hardik Vora: Yes, can you please go… okay, one second. So, Mike, this recipe… no, no, that recipe is one. Scroll up, just scrolling up.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, I was a bit confused earlier, because I was asking, you know, the tags you have already written, why you're asking, so now I understood that in the recipe's dictionary, you have mentioned that tags, so that is different with respect to the tags which you have created below.
Mayank: They're valid tax.
Hardik Vora: No, no, so this… Okay, I'm talking from a front-end user experience. A user has written a…
Hardik Vora: I mean, request to Claude or to LLM.
Hardik Vora: In that perspective, I was thinking earlier, when I asked you the question. So, for example, a person mentions, in… suppose both the, tags, I mean.
Hardik Vora: list, as well as in the dictionary, I have vegan as a common example, or weekend Sunday, you can say. Sunday.
Mayank: Let me make it a little bit easier. I think you're an assisted in choosing it. This is what I have the recipes, okay?
Hardik Vora: Correct.
Mayank: Now, let's say you ask that, hey, can you give me some recipe for the holiday? I have a holiday, can you give me this? Will you send tags this holiday, will you get anything?
Hardik Vora: No.
Mayank: Alright.
Hardik Vora: Mmm.
Mayank: I think, ideally, your LLM should have known that, hey, I can send Sunday rather than holiday.
Hardik Vora: Correct group.
Mayank: Now, how will it get that information?
Mayank: is also supported.
Mayank: So that is where it is.
Hardik Vora: Tags may… No, no, I understood that. Resource car, I understood the concept. But I'm saying, at the top, you have mentioned tags separately, there you have mentioned…
Mayank: Saini
Hardik Vora: Acha, toho…
Hardik Vora: Okay, let me try to understand in this way. Ki LLM ko agar Sande dihya hai is meh in the.
Mayank: LLM is not getting this.
Hardik Vora: Understood, understood. LN not get this? Okay, I understood now.
Mayank: If it doesn't hit list recipe, LLM will not get these tags. LLM mehdiaka B.
Hardik Vora: Teja in detail. Nay.
Mayank: So DB? It's just a DB.
Hardik Vora: I mean, what I was thinking, Yuki, I'm logo na 15th row meh, we have looped it for recipient.item kausco MC 15th row, 15th call, 15th line number.
Mayank: Getting the title, huh?
Hardik Vora: Not that.
Mayank: Title be title. So…
Hardik Vora: The values of Khan.
Mayank: 4K, we… really, we are just sending the…
Hardik Vora: Aparna kan.
Mayank: Sabhinav, but what if we don't hit the list recipes? But tomorrow, if there are thousands of recipes.
Hardik Vora: what we said?
Mayank: All of them, right?
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: If you just say, get me, so it will search the recipe directly, right? Rather than distinctly.
Hardik Vora: Correct, correct, correct.
Hardik Vora: Why I was thinking, Kiki, I am talking from the earlier conversation which we had. Kayyaray before Loop Meh, if I'm trying to, call this.
Hardik Vora: this recipe, voila. So, it will, in which is go to the latest recipe section.
Hardik Vora: list call lekhilei.
Mayank: Meh is a neat. Wait.
Mayank: You can connect to your Gmail and say that, hey, send me an email, send an email, or search an email directly. Why would it go to the list directly? It will get the list of the function just, these three.
Mayank: Vitual.
Hardik Vora: Okay, let's have the function.
Mayank: Aparna can be thousands of regular, there can be.
Hardik Vora: closer to this.
Mayank: It's not just 43.
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay, clear, clear, clear. CG, concept is clear. Second question is Mayank, I was asking you, this MCP resource, and you mentioned to someone, right? We can provide documents or lists of documents. A basic example, can you show? So I was thinking…
Mayank: Vikme Find is a very good example.
Hardik Vora: Correct, Reddy Saha was only thinking. So, hum ko pad dina hai, yeah, because we will be storing it somewhere in the server, na?
Mayank: Mehihi, we can send the computers.
Mayank: beside it?
Mayank: So, there is resources. The resource exports data from files, API, database, or any other resource. Data schema, oya kuchibi ogia. Each resource has a unique URI example file, and there is its mic type.
Mayank: For mime type may aka, mime type is actually the… if it's a PDF text or anything.
Hardik Vora: Hmm, hmm.
Mayank: So, you can give a file as VIN, but Path 3, you can have the file and everything as well. So, rented data, travel documents, previous itineraries.
Mayank: So it is having this complete, ID, and then…
Hardik Vora: If you can just show… okay, I understood. If you can just show in that, resources in our code.
Hardik Vora: Get a little…
Mayank: chauhan.
Mayank: You don't resources?
Hardik Vora: Yeah.
Mayank: resource, we are just.
Hardik Vora: Naidu resources meh. So, where exactly will you share the path?
Mayank: As in, you know?
Mayank: Actually, yapkap kay ruh. Path, exactly. So I can return the path here, after I return the file as well, like…
Mayank: I couldn't.
Hardik Vora: And the medium full day.
Mayank: No, I can't have done that. It will be taken up as a file, not as a Md or anything.
Mayank: I can give an MP4 or anything as well.
Mayank: If you search for anybody ever for my type is Sari Zariya.
Hardik Vora: There are different types of formatting.
Mayank: web pages of the ZRA why they matter.
Mayank: Provide a list of types of audio and video formats.
Mayank: Common types, audio with this, the video business, the audio session.
Hardik Vora: Meh yeh sushi, ye sushi pe host Juve, right? I mean, Hamara server, tohi will host it somewhere.
Hardik Vora: slash Rake folder structure mein readme. Mdne Deserta nape meh. Yeah, hape. So that people can… people should read it. People, I mean, LLM should read it.
Hardik Vora: to better melt.
Mayank: affiliate download.
Hardik Vora: Correct, correct.
Mayank: But whether for 5 days, Indonesian are much better.
Hardik Vora: I'm just trying to understand.
Mayank: k resource.
Mayank: Do you Katare kept me happy?
Mayank: Jayaput aabuska mind diabetic Khare k karang ko.
Mayank: For content handling.
Mayank: kare basic.
Hardik Vora: Okay.
Mayank: Example me ak kumar sahoohmh.
Mayank: ChatGPT, well, it's pretty simple, let me just ask you.
Hardik Vora: Foods.
Mayank: Great. Now, can you please help me create a resource function which returns the file?
Mayank: Mind type.
Mayank: Which is a Reddy?
Mayank: From my server, so that whenever it gets hit, it is returning the file directly.
Mayank: The file is TXT.
Mayank: So this time it will… see, since your file is TXT, the mic type should be explained.
Mayank: At the right MCP resource, file, bind type text plane data, readV.path, read text, encoding.
Mayank: So…
Mayank: Whatever is the readme path, y aka text read us ku pes Deh. Isidarhik you can give the audio and other thing as well.
Mayank: Fort… If it's an audio… for audio file based on.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: This is basic coding sidewal.
Mayank: You know, it's an audio aka bytes, toh mime type iska bite Sujayka bytes a mind type audio MK MP3 hai, tok audio jayapap karogi resource mehsk Sida shiva Mohin chai, read bytes kare. Toh bytesk kumar peer legit.
Hardik Vora: The reason I was asking, ma'am, ki… we are trying to, I mean, globally or global Teja hai, our MCP server ka johi, list of tools here. Before the agent even starts thinking of it.
Hardik Vora: And yap architecture.mdi redemin.md hai, wo mujhe already Klaod ko bata ki raknai pai lesson, ya skills. Md, whatever, XYZ. Chho ki Mehra ye kud bolta ka.
Mayank: Again, you are trying to mix up concepts.
Mayank: Why are you planning it with MCPs, who normally provide kers that they're paying?
Mayank: Why are we mixing it up kini ni ni, I will only be providing it via MCP, though I will hit it up with MCP first. Rather than getting it.
Mayank: Why am I baking?
Hardik Vora: Okay, though, this is not the writer.
Mayank: So, Hitu kanat, you are saying ki mehi nini, I will…
Mayank: Give a most important information to chai MCP. Why not do it directly?
Mayank: And even if it is required, just have an MCP… have a middleware which calls the same and gets you the same.
Hardik Vora: Okay, that is a vegetable person. Okay, thank you, take it.
Mayank: There's a wrong approach.
Hardik Vora: Hmm, understood, understood. So I was thinking… We don't take it.
Mayank: Protein of protein.
Hardik Vora: Got it, got it, got it. And Mayank, can you just go to the code again, please?
Hardik Vora: So here, what I was asking you, okay, this prompt and resource which you have mentioned, Amalab, suppose this prompt is there, right? promptly kay. So, this, we have not defined it for a, I mean, this is globally generic for all the tools which we have created, right?
Mayank: Nikita is just present here. You, if you want, you can add some tabs or anything, I think you have prompts resign there.
Mayank: So, prompts kart tools, they are not connected to a tool, as Aniruch.
Mayank: You can, Mikk.
Hardik Vora: Sirate? Okay.
Mayank: If example, just as an example.
Hardik Vora: Mhmh.
Mayank: If you are searching recipes.
Hardik Vora: Hmm, okay.
Mayank: You just provide easy search recipe prompt.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: So it… LLM will be smarter, and it will be able to get it. But Asangy prompt is tied to a tool or something, I don't think that is the case.
Hardik Vora: So, that was what I was trying to ask. I have asked you earlier, ki LLM to call Nika, but humjab LLM ko bolengar kar request aega, Yuske, basically, when LLM will find… so he, he should be able to understand ki, ye prompt ye relevant.
Mayank: SB pada.
Mayank: MCP.
Hardik Vora: You understood what I was asking right now.
Mayank: I'm making, I'm making it deaf.
Mayank: Search for quick recipes.
Mayank: Good.
Mayank: Please.
Mayank: No skill.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: achau kan ye tool call karum.
Hardik Vora: you brought me.
Mayank: But if you think about this, Sari information malik as in LN, which you will anyway be getting.
Mayank: new Katare MCP, tools list. Toherap.
Hardik Vora: hmm.
Mayank: That is the case.
Hardik Vora: I was thinking for, malab, fast and efficient response, kleiag gursk link…
Mayank: this. Never link.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: MCP ni karta. Apo ki aka.
Hardik Vora: I mean, this way is the right approach.
Mayank: We recipe, research recipe.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Mayank: Let's Nikita.
Mayank: Sportune NSP, you know.
Mayank: Valid time.
Mayank: use.
Mayank: Wronged. Jayapilika peseh thakur
Mayank: As in Post News, okay?
Hardik Vora: Okay, okay.
Mayank: This is a… not hacky way, this is a suggestion, but Asa ni ki enforce Mujaykap code or something, won't.
Hardik Vora: Edinburne kite.
Mayank: Come on, where did it be?
Hardik Vora: where it will be.
Hardik Vora: Nay nih, I was thinking ki ham ganjik BANARE MCP.
Mayank: Mini, again…
Hardik Vora: Engage.
Mayank: Nin y aap unnecessarily complex kar rhise. Agar aap post karukhetap, ye normally bhata na ki tool ka se best use Panda, Map prompt ka kan kara.
Mayank: Give it in depth.
Hardik Vora: Mhmhm.
Mayank: unnecessarily Kaushika, let me make it complex. That's the worst approach in system designing.
Hardik Vora: Oh, okay.
Mayank: Huh.
Hardik Vora: Hmm.
Hardik Vora: Okay. And, Mike, one last thing. Yeah, system design, I was also looking into it, I mean, on the…
Hardik Vora: interview questions and all. So, I was also thinking to ask Yuki if there is a good.
Mayank: Yeah, I'm creating on it because of the friend which I was working, he just got something, at his side, so we both will be connecting, I think, now around second half of September.
Mayank: I have planned, so I will create it. But before your batch gets over, I will shortly make sure to give you that content.
Mayank: What's handing it?
Mayank: much in-depth, although that is very much in-depth.
Hardik Vora: correct the NHSU to create in detail, I saw that.
Mayank: For example, I have empty video recording, but I was not able to put it up, because I did not get time, I have to travel and everything.
Hardik Vora: Understood, completely understood.
Mayank: But I will do that, I will do that, don't worry.
Hardik Vora: No, no, no. And Mike Raghme, I think I've seen many things changing from past couple of months.
Mayank: Oh, movies.
Hardik Vora: 6A to complex, so, I mean, it would be appreciated ki MCP ka in detail, agar Ra.
Mayank: Ragh is a lot more in-depth. I will have to see that thing.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, I mean, you can take… yeah, yeah, I am okay, I mean, I think we all are okay for that.
Mayank: Biggie.
Hardik Vora: MCP chai dasavko, I think. I understand why people were asking in detail, but TK. And my.
Mayank: Let me take the call, don't know either.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah. It will be helpful, mah me.
Mayank: I will see that, what all things we have to cover, and then we take that call then.
Hardik Vora: hybrid, and I mean, there are many things.
Mayank: Final team.
Hardik Vora: Yay, recently, I hope…
Mayank: A little bit harder, because the people.
Hardik Vora: Yeah, yeah, just one last thing, right?
Hardik Vora: Jaykobne Sunay Yoga, right? The latest news.
Mayank: Hmm.
Hardik Vora: What is your perspective, manga? I just want to understand.
Mayank: Honestly, I did not get in depth of this, but Mukhe… human beings try to be greedy and AI speak capitalism, too much for the rich, too little for the poor. So, kahi na kahi toh, it will have some consequences. Hopefully, we will be able to stop it before it
Mayank: gets a lot more in-depth, but yes, I… what I felt is that
Mayank: key… Ai is moving, and right now, it is able to solve some of the most difficult computer science problems and everything else.
Mayank: So, on that case, It is very, very far beyond com…
Mayank: For us, all the simple bhavi, let's just try to upskill. But I don't have anything, okay? It is very…
Mayank: Skyfly kind of a thing.
Hardik Vora: But these people are going into AGI, ASI, quantum.
Mayank: ganhiji.
Hardik Vora: Zoom me got it.
Mayank: Should be fine.
Mayank: That filled it too.
Hardik Vora: technically, we will… we have to save money then, but I understand what you are saying.
Hardik Vora: long term.
Mayank: of now. That he was singing AI could kill us by all by the end of the decade. Honestly, that can happen, that should not be a problem at all.
Mayank: Which ganita Pedded the other day?
Hardik Vora: Yeah, I was just thinking on the roadmap, I mean, in the future.
Mayank: Ni roadmap uska ejobi karum.
Hardik Vora: What we should do.
Mayank: ak chauh kan diagte.
Hardik Vora: Correct, correct, because…
Mayank: area in a nuclear power hack kartek.
Hardik Vora: missiles and all, though. Nay, I know the.
Mayank: Hardik, let's do it afterwards. Sure, sure.
Hardik Vora: in the industry.
Mayank: Take care. Thank you.
Hardik Vora: Okay, thanks.
Mayank: prasan, dines and Prasada.
Mayank: President Nakumar?
Mayank: Biswinda?
Mayank: Olekar.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, can you hear me?
Mayank: Yes, yes, Basavan.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, first million dollar question is, like, are you married?
Basavanna Olekar: Or Sudhar.
Mayank: Yes, yes, yes.
Basavanna Olekar: No, I was wondering, like,
Basavanna Olekar: Is your spouse started breaking your laptop, or she's still tolerating all the time?
Mayank: She's also in the content space. She's a finance content creator with 400K subscribers. She helps companies.
Basavanna Olekar: Then it's a clear understanding.
Mayank: Yeah.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah.
Basavanna Olekar: No, that was just a joke, because…
Basavanna Olekar: I see here, staying in a Bay Area, like, all the time, supposed
Basavanna Olekar: threaten to break the laptop, some… really go ahead and do that.
Mayank: So I get that thing, but laptop is expensive as well.
Basavanna Olekar: you know, it's really nice of you, to having patience and, like, you know, trying to help us out. Yeah, there is no question as such, but I wanted to connect with these two, like, you know.
Basavanna Olekar: my batchments.
Basavanna Olekar: who are going through some particular stuff, where I feel I can help out. So, the request is, how should one student
Basavanna Olekar: Connect with other students.
Mayank: just put.
Basavanna Olekar: So that E…
Mayank: group that he can be connected to everything, so there we can connect.
Basavanna Olekar: Okay, okay.
Mayank: That's still the best way everyone is present, right? Or if else you can give me their email ID, and I can share it across with everyone else.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, that would be helpful. Yeah, the first one is, like, Yusuf, Jaqria. Like, he raised some concerns, and, like, he has some particular, like, you know, vision to do some stuff, and challenges and all. I am in his same
Basavanna Olekar: Like, you know, foot.
Basavanna Olekar: shoes, I can say, rather than foot. So, I can… Yeah, what I will suggest…
Mayank: Just put the message in the group, that would be much better, because I think they have already left the class.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, okay.
Mayank: Very much better.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, that name is there, I can try.
Basavanna Olekar: But, this occipital net… Works on vision.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah.
Mayank: She's a little.
Basavanna Olekar: I was wondering, like,
Mayank: put up the message in the group, in the Krishnak Academy group.
Basavanna Olekar: The same stuff.
Mayank: share it with me, yeah. Just ask them if they can reach out to you, Shrir Engine, etc.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, okay. And it was interesting, actually. It was interesting.
Mayank: Mhmh.
Basavanna Olekar: Last, especially to class.
Basavanna Olekar: tumors to digest, but.
Mayank: Hopefully tomorrow will be more interesting, because it will be a little bit more recording-based. So let's see how many people hold up to that.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, thanks, thanks a lot, Mike.
Mayank: Thank you.
Basavanna Olekar: Yeah, bye-bye.
Mayank: dines or Prasada?
dines: Hi, Meng, this is Dinesh.
Mayank: Pavan.
dines: So, first of all, thank you for providing me an opportunity to speak. I really like your sessions, and I admire your patience.
dines: So, my question is with respect to MCP testing mainly, right? As you know, the AI responses are not deterministic, and the MCP tool that we create mostly works on the doc string, right, where we provide the instructions.
dines: I have, let's say I have created an MCP, and I've deployed it, and it is being used by clients, so I have clients who are using Claude, and ChatGPTs, and Copilot, mainly.
dines: My concern is that I have tested my MCP with all the golden questions and ground truth, and it works fine with Claude. But with Copilot, it is not giving the right response, and I…
dines: really don't want to test, with all the golden growth, and ground… ground truths, right? Golden, golden questions.
dines: My question is very specific to testing MCP, right? How do I test the MCP so that, it can give you the nearly determinist… I mean, I'm sure it won't give you determinist as well, but at least 80-90%,
Mayank: You have to make sure that you are giving right information about your tool and everything.
dines: Correct.
Mayank: Of course, it will depend on the LLM as well, like, you can have all the things, but if the LLM is weak, then also it will not be the case, right?
Mayank: On that note, I think better you can define your tools and everything, description and everything, that would be much better, rather than
Mayank: focusing, because if you are defining everything right, but I'm using a… Voice in them.
Mayank: Then it will not be the case.
dines: Okay, so what is the best approach to do the automation testing for this MCP? That is the question which I wanted to ask. I don't want to do it manually, and I don't want to break anything which is already deployed in production, right?
Mayank: MCP, and again, it is just like any normal testing you do, like, it is, again, nothing but you are connecting with some extra system.
Mayank: So, via some APIs or anything? So, just return, see that, okay, how much time it is filling, have some use cases.
Mayank: And try to hit the… try to mimic the falls, rather than
Mayank: you telling your AI, then hitting it, then hitting it, hit it anyways.
Mayank: just see that, okay, how many calls it can take, because MCP in the backend can also have the same… same things which any API server has. It can have rate limiting, it can have authorization, and all these things. So, just simple as. Simple how you test the ring, nothing else.
dines: Yeah, like, probably I'm not able to put it correctly. The main question is, like, how do I make sure that the co-pilot will also explore my MCP tools correctly and versus the, flaws?
Mayank: So for that, you will have to make sure that, when the way you are defining your prompts, resources, and tools, okay, that. Plus, if you can give better input to your co-pilot, like, if you can tell them that, hey, make sure that you go through the tools and everything. Plus, normally, in a real sense, prompts are a real good way of doing that.
Mayank: If you can share the prompts, very nicely in your MCP server.
Mayank: That's a much better way of using that as well.
dines: Got it. So I should be able to create a tool which can, run those ground truth before I deploy it to production, right? With multiple LLMs.
Mayank: Hmm.
dines: Okay, fair enough, I think that's.
Mayank: And making sure that every tool is getting tested, and then tool testing is based on the normal API thing, that how many times it is getting called, is it failing?
Mayank: Am I getting the right, arguments? All those things at me.
dines: I was thinking in right that direction only, but I just wanted to confirm with you.
dines: Alright, thanks, Mike.
Mayank: Basindo?
Mayank: Doesn't know.
Mayank: Cool. Good everyone, I think that was all the questions, so let's meet in the tomorrow's class. Please make sure that you revise it, because tomorrow we'll be doing some testing and coding part properly. Okay, I will try to keep the code beforehand, but let's see how it holds out, okay? Thank you.
Mayank: Yes, Rajkash. So I actually closed the participant list, bye-bye, yeah.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Oh, yeah, yeah, sorry. So, Mayank, just I'm trying to understand, even though MCP has been quite popular, whatever APIs we are exposing, right, right, just we are wrapping in the tool, so it will
Rakesh_Kumar42: become MCP compliant or something like that. I'm thinking, why not with the traditional REST APIs, we already have a REST API ecosystem in the place, and it's being consumed by the back-end or front-end across.
Rakesh_Kumar42: So, what's the difference between calling all those REST APIs.
Mayank: I agree.
Rakesh_Kumar42: And this tool.
Mayank: We very much in it in the first class when I explained MCP, like, that was the why MCP has to exist class.
Mayank: So, that I've explained properly, why using APIs or tools is not the best way out there.
Mayank: So, properly, in depth, I've explained how you have to maintain it, then how you have to define every tool, everything.
Mayank: No, listen.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Creation and decoration, that's fine, but why these patterns, MCP protocols came in the picture?
Rakesh_Kumar42: Because, it's, again, it's a kind of document, or whatever you're telling, right? It has to respond to the document list, and all those. It's just getting one of the assets from one server to another machine, right?
Rakesh_Kumar42: So why does AMCP itself been introduced? If I should be able to call with, means I can wrap the API within the tool, and then I should be able to call, isn't it?
Mayank: But how will you maintain it like that? Don't you think that for a scale problem, that would be a menu problem?
Rakesh_Kumar42: Okay, your voice is low, actually.
Mayank: I'm saying that, don't you think that while we are trying to scale it, that would be a very big problem then?
Rakesh_Kumar42: So far, we were able to scale our API system, right?
Mayank: not API system, I'm saying access. It is not about API system, it is about giving the access.
Mayank: Just as an example, let me make a very simple example. Let's say Google is having 15 tools, Gmail.
Mayank: You will always define 15 tools and make sure that you are adding them into your AI, right?
Rakesh_Kumar42: A 15 tool, in the sense? It's adding features, right?
Mayank: No, no, if you're adding tools to your agent, let's say in Lang Jain.
Mayank: If MCP is not there, you will be defining those 15 tools, right?
Rakesh_Kumar42: Correct, correct.
Mayank: So now, think about that. If tomorrow Three of them changes.
Mayank: And you will be doing that change.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Change in the sense,
Mayank: Gmail… Gmail send tool requires that you don't send double C or BCC.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Perfect.
Mayank: It's okay, but earlier that was supported, so you will be doing that change now?
Rakesh_Kumar42: as parameters, right? Obviously, yeah? Yeah, yeah. And…
Rakesh_Kumar42: It should be in this MCP as well, isn't it? Because,
Mayank: No, nobody…
Rakesh_Kumar42: One parameters.
Mayank: You need MCP to handle it, na? MCP to, of course, handles it.
Mayank: But let's say that you have to do that. Then it would be a little bit problematic thing, right? Scaling it up for billions of users who are using Gmail.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Correct. I think version and all that is still there, right? Whenever any API is getting exposed, V1, V2, that's how we handle…
Mayank: You will have to change that, no? You will have to change that.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Right, if those customers would like to switch to those updated versions, they have to switch to that, right?
Mayank: But now, think about, from a live-in perspective, isn't MCP much better? Like, in Gmail, we have connectors which are MCP only.
Mayank: So, don't you think that is much better directly?
Rakesh_Kumar42: connectors are there. Connectors are nothing but that hooking it up, right? I'm more focusing on these protocols, right? Even connector in any data platform also, we are having connectors. We connect from one source to other sources. It's nothing but behind the scenes, it's REST APIs, calls are…
Mayank: Okay, but, so that is where, again, I will explain it. So, when we have connectors in other parts where you are saying, right?
Rakesh_Kumar42: Regularly.
Mayank: Let's say that you connect Gmail.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Blue boots.
Mayank: You cannot make a call saying that, hey, send an email. In that, when you connect.
Mayank: You have to tell KHAR this exactly is the system of vision which you want to focus on.
Mayank: MCP as a protocol makes that easier, where you can just easily connect it and make it key ASH connect to send an email, so it automatically figures out what to do, which API to call.
Mayank: Whereas connectors in other applications, There, they get clicked with a button or something, right? Directly.
Mayank: So that is the difference here. Okay, that is AI compatible. That is why MCP comes up, and that is why it is having the complete protocol and everything in there.
Rakesh_Kumar42: So, you're… focusing on the way the LLM regions it and, make a call, deciding which…
Mayank: are there to call MCMCPs are not used to make a normal API call or normal tool calling. It is always used with LLM.
Mayank: To use the LLM, we were not having any… HTTP was not the right…
Mayank: Protocol for that, right? That is why MCP has to come up.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Http was not… But again, all the agents itself calling LNMs through HTTP itself, isn't it?
Mayank: No, no, no, I don't care.
Rakesh_Kumar42: For instance…
Mayank: Who knows?
Rakesh_Kumar42: for inferencing, all the API keys and all those, all those are the REST APIs.
Mayank: Oh, no, you're not understanding. When I connect to Gmail and MCP,
Mayank: I just give my request as an NLPA, like, as a…
Rakesh_Kumar42: Yeah, that's where I'm getting in, yeah, yeah. That is making me more clear now, that it seems like reasoning and choosing which tool I have to call, that's where it fits in. It's not more towards the communication protocol between one end to another end.
Mayank: No, no, it is not like that. Then we have STDIO-based MCP servers as well, which cannot be done via API directly. So there is where MCP protocol comes into picture. Plus, now, though, we have seen the complete life cycle. That is not how HTTP or API works, right?
Mayank: So MCP test out every time that if there is any changes in the tool, it can communicate that back as well. I covered that, how HTTP can server make a call to the client in HTTP.
Rakesh_Kumar42: No.
Mayank: CPUs can.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Mix. NMC.
Mayank: You can.
Rakesh_Kumar42: I'll be your openness.
Mayank: So that is why it is helpful. That is why the new protocol was required.
Rakesh_Kumar42: We performed.
Mayank: For example, just as a very basic example, you ask an MCP to download a file.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Mhmhmh.
Mayank: Now, it is going to take 1 hour. So the server can tell the client that, hey, I'm 5x100 completed, I'm 20 by 100 completed. That is not possible in…
Mayank: Rac, sorry, HTTP.
Rakesh_Kumar42: So that is.
Mayank: by this new protocol. Just see the first class ZRA covered, it's very much in.
Rakesh_Kumar42: Okay, okay, okay, okay, yeah, we'll make sure that. Thank you very much, man.
Mayank: Alright.